<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" 
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
    >
  <channel>
    <title>True Happiness</title>
    <description>Learn the science and practice of how to truly be happy at True Happiness.</description>
    <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://true-happiness.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 03:36:09 +0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 03:36:09 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cause of Unhappiness Part Five: When Life Is At A Lost</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There will be times when life becomes too overwhelming. There will be times in our lives where we have no idea how to go on. There will be times where doubt, fear, confusion, and uncertainty will set in and cloud our minds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this age of information where we are constantly bombarded by the tales of what we should want in life. “You have to get a degree from college in order to be happy.” “You need a new phone in order to look good in front of your friends.” “You need that job/promotion.” “You have to have that big house to be ‘successful’.” “You need to get married by this age or else it will be impossible afterward.” On and on and on we are fed by stories of what “happiness” is suppose to be. But instead, these so called “happiness” often times left us with a sense inadequancy to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what should one do when life is at a lost? Here are four simple steps to getting your life back on track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;4 Steps to Get Your Life Back&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Stop and Take A Step Back&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;One evening I return to my hermitage from a walk in the hills, and I found that all the doors and windows of the hermitage had been blown open. When I left the house, I hadn&#39;t secured them, and a cold wind blew through the house, opened the windows, and scattered the papers from the desk all over the room. Immediately I closed the doors and the windows, lit a lamp, picked up the papers, and arranged them neatly on my desk. Then I started a fire in the fireplace, and soon the crackiling logs brought warmth back to the room.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Thich Nhat Hanh&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above is exactly what we do with our life when it is at a lost. Thich Nhat Hanh equates our senses as the doors and windows of our life. &lt;strong&gt;You can’t pick yourself up in the middle of the storm.&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes it is wise to just stop and take a step back from it all. Of course, the purpose of this is not to give up. Its purpose is to give ourselves the chance to recover and prepare to face life again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To stop and take a step back from life could be anything from spending time with yourself, turning off all your electronics, a solo vacation, meditate, to participating in a meditation retreat. I do not recommend losing yourself to something else or putting the problem off by blurring the reality of the situation like making ourselves busy on purpose or do something just to forget the problem. The point is not to run away. The point is to allow you to step a out of your situation to look inward and review your life with more clarity so that you can begin anew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;capitalized&quot;&gt;2. Understand that it’s ok to be lost.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;It&#39;s ok to not be ok.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life never goes according to what one wants. This is the fact of life. So it&#39;s inevitable for everyone to, at some point, not be ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the worst and best thing that one can do at this point?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The worst thing anyone could do&lt;/strong&gt; when facing such a situation is to hate the situation one is in. Imagine you are lost in a desert with someone and that person just kept brooding, crying out loud, throwing tantrum, and complaining about the situation. How does that help make the situation any better if not worse? To hate the situation you are in is, therefore, like digging you own grave. It only makes everything worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its worse form, it creates an infinite down spiral. When one dislikes the situation one is in one tends to become dishearten and give up the whole thing which makes the situation even worse. And when the situation is worse, it makes one wants to give up even more. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best thing that one could do&lt;/strong&gt; when lost is simply to focus on the problem in front of us in order to put our lives back again. Don&#39;t victimized yourself. See how others might even be in worse situation. Don&#39;t complain. Learn to be opened to the problems of life is a skill. Be nice to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;capitalized&quot;&gt;3. Regaining your sense of direction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have given yourself an opportunity to stop and take a step out of your situation and you are calm and collected enough to face the challenges of life then it is time to find your sense of direction in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding one’s sense of direction required alot of inner and outer exploration. The questions which one should aim to answer are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What matters to me most?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What is the purpose of living?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What am I passionate about?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What is my core value?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What is my inner drive?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What cause do I believe in that is higher than myself?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s ok to not be able to answer these questions. Many never found their true sense of direction in life until late in their life. It is not something you can’t rush it because it has its own time. However, to help you find what drives you. Here are some advises:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&#39;t Overthink. Just Explore.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;The benefit of being lost is that it forces you to explore. It forces you to find your inner drive. So take this chance and learn more about yourself and find what it is that you truly believe in. Learn something new. Meet new and inspiring people. Live life differently from what you used to. Perhaps the reason why you are lost is because you haven&#39;t try that thing which you always wanted to try. Very much like when you are lost in real life in a middle of a jungle. You probably first need to know and assess what you&#39;ve got, where you want to head toward, and see what is in your surrounding that could be of use. So get exploring both inside and outside. And try your best to not to do it out of fear, but out of joy.
	&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplify&lt;/strong&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;The reason why we are sometimes confused with life is because we have too many wants--some which are even conflicting with one another. Having too much wants makes our lives become too difficult to manage. As a rule of thumb, a simple life always lead to happiness. So find whatever that matters to you most and let go of others which are not. In this way, you have a clearer sense of the direction which you want to head toward.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revisit Your Inner Drive&lt;/strong&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;If you are feeling lost then you must have known what it was like to not be lost. Revisit your past when you feel sure of life or when you felt you have a sense of purpose could be helpful to getting you back on track.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Keep Going, Do Not Give Up.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Players with fight never lose a game, they just run out of time&quot; - John Wooden&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are never lost until you give up. So never give up. Keep going. Eventually you will find your way. Perhaps it is not the path you were expecting. But you will find it. It’s only a matter of patient, perseverance, and time. You have my full support! If you would like to share you story for others to help and support you or become an inspiration to others. You can do so at &lt;a href=&quot;/forum/&quot;&gt;True Happiness’s Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/06/09/why-am-i-unhappy-5/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/06/09/why-am-i-unhappy-5/</guid>
        
        <category>why-am-i-unhappy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Know Oneself?</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;We Meditate.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meditation is simply to know. “Know” in this sense is not knowing in our thoughts or knowing from reading, listening, or thinking but knowing as in &lt;em&gt;to experience, be aware of, or be mindful of.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do we know in meditation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objects that we must know in meditation are ourselves. The self can be divided into two main parts: &lt;strong&gt;the mind and the body&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it could further be separated it into five parts which are..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Body&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Consciousness&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Thoughts&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Feeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the objects of meditations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do we do once we are mindful of our body, consciousness, knowledge, thoughts, and feeling?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing. Simply by being mindful of ourselves is enough. This might sounds very strange in this age where one has to always do more or always take a more active stance in achieving something. But this is not the case for meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the correct way to know in meditation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Know objectively as is. Without any need to change or to desire how our body, consciousness, knowledge, thoughts, and feeling should or should not be. If you are upset, know that you are upset. If we have a stomach ache, know that we have the stomach ache. This is how we develop our mindfulness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why should I develop my mindfulness? What is the purpose of meditation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of meditation is to allow the mind to see its own reality. Our life is full of ups and downs, positive emotions and negative emotions, good thoughts and bad thoughts, birth and death, and of knowledge of what is “good” and “evil”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we live and navigate in the world which is full of these dualities of life is the real question that one must know the answer to live a  happy life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When life is not going the way we want we can always say to ourselves that, “life is uncertain” or that “it will soon pass.” But do our hearts really accept this fact? Even with the knowledge that life is uncertain, we still suffer. For this reason, knowing by knowledge is not enough. What we need is to know life by heart. This is why meditation is needed as the tool for our hearts to come to know truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By allowing our hearts to see the dualities of life, we can see that life with its ups and downs has three characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything is impermanent.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Nothing lasted.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Reality has nothing to do with what we want, but it has everything to do with the natural law of cause and effect. &lt;a href=&quot;/2016/01/07/no-room-for-desire-in-life/&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;(For a more detailed explanation, click here.)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meditation is how one comes to understand reality. It is how our hearts learn about how everything comes and goes, how all must inevitably progress from birth to death, and how the world is not about what we want but about the absolute law of cause and effect. These are the truth that our hearts will come to see for itself just by being mindful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the hearts could come to understand the truth of life. Life becomes easier to live and harder for it to suffer. Like learning how to ride a horse, if you do not know how, riding becomes a nightmare. And often times than not, the horse rides you more than you ride the horse. Life is very much the same. This is why one must learn life to live it. And meditation is how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Types of Meditation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Meditation in Daily Life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important type of meditation is not one in which most people believe. Many have the idea of meditation as sitting down, closing our eyes, and watch our breathing. But for meditation to be effective it must be practical in our daily life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there are two ways one could develop mindfulness in our daily life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Being mindful of our mind&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Our mind consists of our consciousness, knowledge, thoughts, and feelings. Consciousness&#39;s only task is to know. Knowledge is what we know. Thoughts are our cognitive thinking. And feeling is... feeling! (However, it could be further generalized into three types of feelings: positive, negative, and neutral.)&lt;/p&gt;

		&lt;p&gt;We develop our mindfulness by noticing our thoughts and feelings. When a thought takes our mind from places to places we know our mind is wandering. When we are happy, we know that we are happy. When we are sad we know that we are sad. This is all it takes to develop mindfulness. (Really?) Really!&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Being mindful of our body&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;In our daily life, we can develop our mindfulness by knowing our bodies in the present moment like when we are breathing, walking, eating, sitting, and etc. Simple right? Just know our bodily movement through out the day and we are all set!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, meditation in daily life is to know our body, consciousness, knowledge, thoughts, and feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;How much daily meditation is enough?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;All day is enough. True practictioners of mindfulness begin their practice starting from the moment they wake up until the moment they go to bed. They are mindful of when they get out of bed, brush their teeth, eat, walk, go to work, come home, and go to bed. They are mindful of all their positive or negative thoughts and emotions through out the day. The practice of mindfulness is easy; but to practice it consistently through out the day is not. Slowly build your mindfulness in daily life until it becomes a second-nature.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Sitting and Walking Meditation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sitting Meditation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Sitting meditation is ultimately to be mindful of our in breath and out breath. Let&#39;s first begin with the steps:&lt;/p&gt;

		&lt;ol&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Find a suitable spot for sitting meditation. Preferably any place that is quiet and give you a sense of peace and tranquility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sit in a comfortable position. It is not required for you to sit on the floor. Sitting on a chair would do. But I would recommend that the chair should not be too comfortable because it would make you fall asleep!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can begin noticing your out breath and in breath with your eyes open or closed. If you easily get sleepy while doing your sitting meditation then it would be good to start with your eyes open and just notice the in and out breath before closing your eyes once you feel more concentrated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuosly be mindful of the breath. If you mind wanders, simply bring it back to the breath and continue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ol&gt;

		&lt;p&gt;These are the steps to sitting meditation which can seem pretty simple but once you are into the practice and actuality of doing it, it is not. So here are some tips.&lt;/p&gt;

		&lt;u&gt;Quick Tips on Sitting Meditation&lt;/u&gt;
		
		&lt;p&gt;Meditation is not about control nor is it about letting the mind runs loose. The trick is to find the perfect balance between controlling and not. To know the breath by being not too tight and not too loose. Sitting meditation is like holding a chick. If you hold it too loosely it runs away. If you hold it too tightly, the chick suffocates. If you find yourself feeling tight, stiff, having a headache, or finding it difficult to just breathe during or after meditation then it is a clear sign that you are exerting too much control. If you are sleepy, find your mind wandering from places to places without being able to come back to the breath, then it might be possible that you are too loose. Learning sitting meditaiton is like learning how to ride a bike. It will take time and experience to adjust and know your own balance. And practice is key to finding it.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walking Meditation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Since my practice in walking meditation has been trained from the Theravada Buddhist tradition. I want to offer what I know from my own experience. So follow the links below to learn about how as well as why we do walking meditation. (Make sure you turn on the subtitle.) This knowledge will also aid you in your sitting meditation since it pretty much has the same concept.
&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LPqhDiHmQWw&quot;&gt;Video on &quot;How to practice walking meditation?&quot; #1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zJRBu5uYrjI&quot;&gt;Video on &quot;How to practice walking meditation?&quot; #2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;How much sitting/walking meditation is enough?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Twice a day. I would suggest to make this into a habit by chaining it with some daily routine you have been doing. For example, right after you shower or before you go to bed. It does not need to be a hour long session. In fact one minute would do. But the important thing is to not lose the routine. Once you keep the routine for around 3 weeks, the habit of meditating will stick with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;I can only show you the door. But you are the only who has to walk through it.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, I could talk all day about how you should meditate; but in the end you have to do it. Only through meditation will you find out for yourself what meditation actually is. You can’t learn how to ride a horse or swim from just reading a textbook. You must do it to learn it. Life is where we can learn about life’s truth. This is why &lt;strong&gt;meditation is defined as the process of knowing oneself&lt;/strong&gt;. Enough talking and start doing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;short&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recommended readings about “Meditation”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Why Meditation?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2016/03/22/why-meditate/&quot;&gt;Learn goals behind the art of meditation, click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Why Meditation Matters to The World?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/08/24/why_true_happiness/&quot;&gt;If you are curious about why meditation is important to this world, click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;What I Have Received from Meditation as a Long-Time Practitioner?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2016/04/02/my-experience-with-meditation/&quot;&gt;Click here to learn more about my experience with meditation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/05/21/how-to-know-oneself/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/05/21/how-to-know-oneself/</guid>
        
        <category>practice-of-true-happiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When You Love, You Become Love</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;And in the end, the love you take is equal to the love you make.&quot; ― The Beatles&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything is and can be the object of our love. When we exercise our capacity to love on anything at all–ourselves, love ones, stranger, work, pets or even an insect–we become love itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site is about finding True Happiness. And love is definitely one of the ways in which one could come to understand and experience True Happiness. But unlike the convention kind of romantic love, the kind of love we are talking about is an act of compassion and selflessness, to look beyond ourselves for the well-being of others without expecting anything in return. It is an act done entirely for the benefits of others. There is no exchange in this kind of love. It is not a give and take. We get nothing for it. It is a &lt;strong&gt;gift&lt;/strong&gt; in its truest sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many believe it is never worth it to do anything if it does not pay. Just like this website, many have told me it is a waste of time to write these articles on True Happiness. Their logic is that if it does not generate income then it is, in their exact words, “useless”, “a waste of time”, “never going to work.” But this website is not intented to be an exchange for me to gain something. &lt;em&gt;It’s a gift.&lt;/em&gt; It is to love others even though there is nothing in return. It is an investment in a relationship that may or may not work at all. I am pouring my heart and soul into this blind shot in the dark all in the hope that it will help someone in their life to find love, peace, truth, purpose, and happiness. I am betting everything to get nothing and it is fine by me because I am happy to love first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Love is Happiness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love is probably one of the strongest emotion. It dominates and dissipates all doubts, hates, politics, and the dramas of human’s life. You will be surprised how quickly can love turn your day around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We always think that we would be happy if others love us. But what we do not realise is that we would be just as happy if we were to love others. So stop wanting to be loved, and start looking for ways to love. Look no further to find True Happiness because &lt;strong&gt;True Happiness is in the very act of love.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dalai Lama once said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;If you want others to be happy, practice compassion. If you want to be happy, practice compassion.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all have the capacity for love. So exercise it. And exercise it often epecially on those who you dislike. Exercise it on yourself and everything that come into your life until it becomes your nature to love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you look at someone, always ask the question of “How can I love?” or “How can I love this person?” Just in that very thought, you are already setting up yourself to be happy. Regardless of who he is she is or what he or she has done to you, this is our &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; duty. It’s perhaps the only attitude we all should have toward life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Let no one ever come to you without leaving better and happier. Be the living expression of God&#39;s kindness: kindness in your face, kindness in your eyes, kindness in your smile.&quot; - Mother Teresa&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This task is not limited to others but it can be applied to anything at anytime. So you can also ask question like “How can I love myself?” or “What is the best thing to do for myself right now?” Even ill thoughts and negative feelings that enter our mind, they are also the objects of our love. I have been waking up with the question of “How can I love today?” It’s a great question to start the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- We always want to be loved by others, but rarely do we want to love others. So let&#39;s change that.
 --&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to leave you with these beautiful and memorable quotes below which I believe better summarise my point about love and True Happiness. (I think it would also be a good ideas to put these quotes up on our desks and in our bedrooms.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;“Seize the moments of happiness, love and be loved! That is the only reality in the world, all else is folly. It is the one thing we are interested in here.” 
― Leo Tolstoy&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;short&quot; /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;“For every minute you are angry you lose sixty seconds of happiness.” 
― Ralph Waldo Emerson&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;short&quot; /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;“The Paradoxical Commandments&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

People are illogical, unreasonable, and self-centered.
Love them anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

If you do good, people will accuse you of selfish ulterior motives.
Do good anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

If you are successful, you will win false friends and true enemies.
Succeed anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

The good you do today will be forgotten tomorrow.
Do good anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Honesty and frankness make you vulnerable.
Be honest and frank anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

The biggest men and women with the biggest ideas can be shot down by the smallest men and women with the smallest minds.
Think big anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

People favor underdogs but follow only top dogs.
Fight for a few underdogs anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

What you spend years building may be destroyed overnight.
Build anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

People really need help but may attack you if you do help them.
Help people anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Give the world the best you have and you&#39;ll get kicked in the teeth.
Give the world the best you have anyway.” 
― Kent M. Keith, The Silent Revolution: Dynamic Leadership in the Student Council&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;short&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related resources about “love and compassion”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Ted Talk by Ex-Googler Chade-Meng Tan on &quot;Everyday Compassion at Google&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/chade_meng_tan_everyday_compassion_at_google.html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/04/10/becoming-love/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/04/10/becoming-love/</guid>
        
        <category>love</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Experience With Meditation</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It is not wrong to be curious about meditation and where it would take us. So as a long-time practitioner of mindfulness, here is a short list of what I have received in these last 10 years of meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Happiness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Make a man happy and he will be happy for a day. Teach a man how to be happy and he will be happy for a life time.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People today are finding life more difficult to be happy and easier to be discontent. The reason is because our happiness has become both fleeting and is always in front of us. We often think, “I’ll be happy if…”, “I’ll be happy when…” Thus, our happiness is always in the future. Never is our happiness with us in this very moment. We have become so busy running and jumping from one kind of happiness to the next hoping it would finally fulfil our lives. But the chase never ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;If you can&#39;t be happy now. You will never be happy.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meditation is a method which allows us to be in touch with our inner balance. It is not about chasing, but about coming home. When we are in touch with our inner balance, we become more conscious of our inner imbalances. And that is how mindfulness builds and becomes awareness. What I mean by “imbalance” is our unhappiness; namely anger, worry, jealousy, greed, frustration, despair, disappointment and etc. (For more information about what unhappiness is, click &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/06/01/what_is_happiness/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether or not we will be happy or unhappy all depends on how much we can be awared of our own imbalances. When we are unawared of the unhappiness in our lives, the unhappiness spreads in our mind like wildfire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are angry at someone and you do not forgive him or her, what you eventually find is yourself saying bad things about him or her in your head. You will start convincing yourself how he or she is a bad person and how you will never talk to them again. So by allowing our inner fire to go wild, we unknowingly fueled our fire of hatred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noticing these imbalances quickly and objectively is enough for the fire to stop. When you practice long enough, you will notice, in split second, even the slightest imbalance in our hearts. When we could quickly see what is causing our unhappiness, we couldn’t help but ask ourselves, “Why hold on to the hot iron?” This is precisely the reason why meditation or mindfulness is imperative to our happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mindfulness protects our happiness.&lt;/strong&gt; It allows us to see the true cause of our unhappiness. It helps us to not be consumed by our own feelings and instead see it for what it is. Through mindfulness, we become the observer of our unhappiness and not the unhappiness itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;blockquote&gt;Hatred can&#39;t be stop by hatred. It only stops by compassion. &lt;br&gt;-Buddha&lt;/blockquote&gt;
 --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t tell you how many times a day these imbalances pop up in my daily life. And every single day for the last 10 years, mindfulness has countlessly saved my happiness. This is why I started True Happiness. This is why I know for sure that it will save your happiness too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Self-Transformation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to think I am already “good”. Even when others gave me honest constructive criticisms or useful feedbacks, I would see them as “attacks” or attempts to delegitimize my identity of being “good”. I prefered to hold on to my image of being “good” rather than be good. And for that, I can’t grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This attitude of being too good for improvement is perhaps the worst attitude anyone could have toward self-growth. According to the Buddha, he considered these people to already be “dead.” For they no longer have anything more to offer because their attempts to hold on to their “goodness” has hinder them of bettering themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meditation has turn this attitude of mine 360 degrees. What meditation allows me to see is myself for who I really am. Before I was biased toward myself. I thought I was already “good”. And there is nothing more I need to improve. But once I started seeing myself more and more, I start to see that I was not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have found many contradictions within myself which I only apply to others but never to myself. I realised my prejudices and double-standards which many times have causes me many troubles without me seeing itse negative effects. I have come to see my many flaws and shortcomings which I had always overlook and sometimes even blamed others for. I have overcame many unwholesome desires which I thought was my “happiness” but turns out just to be the attempts to fill the unfillable void in my heart. The list goes on and on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mind is like a garden. If you do not tend it, only weed grows. It is impossible to improve what we do not know because you don’t even know what the thing to be improved is in the first place. Seeing ourselves is precisely what meditation allows us to do. And if meditation could completely change who I am for the better then it will change yours too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Love&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not the romantic kind of “love” we know. But this is the love that is found and given out of self-understanding and selflessness. It is the love which comes as the fruits of meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one is perfect; and I am of no exception. Many times in my life I wanted to yell and insult others who have angered me. Many times in my life I feel jealous of others who are doing better than me. Many times in my life I wanted to hurt others who have hurt me. Many times in my life I wanted to lie and cheat to quickly get whatever I want in life. But I never did any of those things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? Because I kept my practice and was mindful of these unwholesome desires. I can’t command what kind of thought would pop up in my mind. I can’t tell my feelings to never feel bad. I can’t tell my stomach ache to stop being painful. These are my realities. However, what I can do is how I response to it. And I simply choose to be mindful of it instead of giving in to it. This is meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I become mindful of my own reality. I start seeing myself as something which comes and goes. I learn to not take my negative thought and feeling seriously. I start seeing myself as something which has death as its final destination, I learn to let go of my unhappiness knowing life is too short to be unhappy. I start seeing myself as part of the absolute law of cause and effect, I know that everything happens because there are conditions for it to happen. Thus, I can easily come to terms with reality whether it is good or bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The practice of mindfulness is an upward spiral which helps one to be better than oneself. Each time I come to understand and let go of one unwholesome desire, I became better and better at handling the next. This is self-mastery. If you truly love yourself this is what you do. If you seek happiness and truth, meditation is what you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I can overcome my unwholesome desire, I am in the process stop myself from harming others. This for me is love–one which is good for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Purpose in Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every individual lives to seek happiness in one form or another. However, the pursue of one’s happiness does not necessarily mean that it is always beneficial for all. Often time than not, our pursues of happiness only benefit ourselves. And worse, in some cases, they come at the cost of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the best way of living life–one that is beneficial for both oneself and the world? What is the best way to solve world problem and social problem of today? What is the best step to take toward creating the condition for world peace? &lt;strong&gt;What is the best thing life can offer?&lt;/strong&gt; These are the questions I have since 18.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my journey to answer these questions, I began studying Philosophy. I traveled, backpacked, and lived in India, France, Japan and many others countries around the world. I even ordained as a Theravada Buddhist monk for one year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After years of ceaselessly searching for the answer, the answer I have found is happiness. Happiness is what create our world, for good or for evil. It dictates people’s lives and decides how our world will be. Wealth will not save this world from itself. Even if it rains in gold today, people’s greed will not end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;World peace can not be achieved by changing what is outside of us, it is achieved by developing how each and everyone of us seek and define happiness inside of ourselves.&lt;/strong&gt; And meditation is the tool for developing our happiness. Through the practice of mindfulness, not only will we find both Truth and True Happiness, but in the process benefits the world as well. It is the best thing that one can do for oneself as well as the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Truth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Knowing yourself is the beginning of all wisdom.&quot; - Aristotle&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What originally led me to meditation is not my desire to be happy, but my desire to know Truth. It is rather odd how the two coincide. But from my experience, they do and they must. There is no True Happiness without Truth. One would not be wrong to say that finding Truth is also finding True Happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my time in college, I studied Philosophy. My journey in Philosophy has led me to know Truth. I know that Truth is outside of language. I know that it is the Unspeakable. I know that it transcends all dualities of life. But what I am saying to you right now is like describing to you how a dish would taste. I could tell you all about it but in the end it is you who have to taste it to know what it actually taste like. Similarly, Truth can be learned. But it must be experienced through meditation in order to truly know what it actually is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, learning the truth of life is enjoyable in and of itself. Think of it as learning how to ride a horse. When you don’t know how, it is difficult and stressful to try to steer it. But once you come to learn about the nature of the horse and how to ride it, it is much easier and much more enjoyable. Life is very much the same. The more I became aware of the Truth of life the easier and happier life becomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You either live life or the life will live you, one way or the other.&lt;/strong&gt; And the only difference is how much can  we come to know life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What meditation has given me is unrequitable and invaluable. There is too much that meditation has given me to all be written in words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have spoken to you about what I have received through meditation. But just as a final note, &lt;strong&gt;meditation is not something anyone should expect to gain anything out of.&lt;/strong&gt; The expectation and desire of meditation will make it impossible to succeed in any attempt to meditate. Even though meditation leads you to True Happiness, but you can’t even expect or demand it to make you happy. Meditation is just to be mindful of ourselves. Just that is enough to get us to True Happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I am not here to prove to you why you should meditate. &lt;strong&gt;Meditation does not need convincing as much as it needs to be proven.&lt;/strong&gt; Thus, the only way to find out if what I have told you is true or if meditation can really give you True Happiness is to give it a try. Let meditation speaks its own truth to you so that you can see for yourself what meditation is and what it is for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;I can only point you toward the door. But you have to walk through it yourself.&quot; - Buddha&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;short&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For other suggested/related readings...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/08/24/why_true_happiness/&quot;&gt;How Meditation Will Save The World?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2016/03/22/why-meditate/&quot;&gt;Why Meditate?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/04/02/my-experience-with-meditation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/04/02/my-experience-with-meditation/</guid>
        
        <category>practice-oftrue-happiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Know Oneself?</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are 3 goals in knowing oneself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		To see the true nature of ourselves and the world
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		To experience peace and happiness
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		To become skillful at handling our own desires
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This practice is known since ancient times as &quot;&lt;strong&gt;meditation&lt;/strong&gt;&quot;. Meditation allows us to experience a state of stillness. When the mind is not looking for something it wants and is not concern about its dislike, our mind comes together to produce an experience of True Happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be careful though that the practice of mindfulness is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; about not thinking or ignoring or denying the reality of our undesirable thoughts and feelings. Mindfulness is simply to be mindful. All thoughts, feeling and everything that comes to our senses are &lt;em&gt;allowed.&lt;/em&gt; The practice of mindfulness is not a judgment on ourselves. It is not a self-management exercise in which we must assert control over ourselves. It is a practice of knowing and being mindful of life as it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more we come to know the nature of ourselves the more we will realize the three noble Truths of our lives which are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything-ourselves, our feelings, our attitude, our body, or the world-is impermanent.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Nothing lasted.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Reality has nothing to do with what we want. (&lt;a href=&quot;/2016/01/07/no-room-for-desire-in-life/&quot;&gt;For a more detailed explanation, click here.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How could the heart be unhappy if it knows everything is impermanent? How could the heart be unhappy if it knows everything will not last forever? How could our heart be unhappy if it knows that reality is not about what we want but about the absolute law of cause and effect that determined reality? It can&#39;t be unhappy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the Truth that our hearts will come to know through meditation. It is not about knowing it intellectually. We can know that everything is impermanent in our thought but does our hearts truly accept and understand that Truth? When someone we love passes away, regardless of how many books we read about impermanent, it is only the heart that decides our happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this reason, &lt;strong&gt;we need to meditate in order to let our heart see the Truth for itself.&lt;/strong&gt; It&#39;s not an intellectual discovery to be found in books or in logic. It&#39;s a spiritual discovery which comes from and by the heart that see the Truth of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;short&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recommended readings about “Why we know oneself?”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Why Knowing Oneself Matters to The World?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/08/24/why_true_happiness/&quot;&gt;If you are curious about why meditation is important to this world, click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;capitalized&quot;&gt;What I Have Received from my self-study as a Long-Time Practitioner?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2016/04/02/my-experience-with-meditation/&quot;&gt;Click here to learn more about my experience with meditation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/03/22/why-know-oneself/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/03/22/why-know-oneself/</guid>
        
        <category>practice-of-true-happiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cause of Unhappiness Part Four: Mistake in Life</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;You can&#39;t change or erase what happened in the past, all you can change is your attitude toward it.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mistake in life is not to be taken lightly. For some, one small mistake could define who they are and enslave our lives in an unending quest to redeem or fix the mistake that he or she has done in the past. So let’s first begin by understanding what mistake is and how it affects our happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Understanding the Nature of Life Mistake&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Mistake is like a ghost.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we do not reconcile or do not know how to reconcile with our mistake, the mistake becomes an open loop which endlessly haunts our lives. The more we wish to not think about our mistake, the more our minds irresistibly wander back to the mistake to relive it. Even though that particular mistake might have happened many years ago, or you might be at work or in the middle of a party, our mistake will not rest or give us a break. It will continue to enter into our conscious mind to remind us of its presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The mistake itself is not what makes us unhappy. It’s our attitude towards it that makes us unhappy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mistake is fueled by our biases toward it. The more we resist, avoid, hide, deny, blame, bend, or twist the reality of our mistake the more powerful it becomes in our lives. It draws power from our desire to not accept or come to term with it. The feeling of guilt, depression, anger, frustration, self-hating, and embarrassment. All of which originate from our desire that the past should or should not have been otherwise. It’s the void in our want from reality which we desperately want to change but can’t. The only way for a mistake to lose its power is for us to allow our mistake to be, without disliking it or denying its reality. Accept the mistake as it is without any filters. This is how a mistake loses its power and slowly fade away from our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Mistake is by default inevitable.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody wants to make mistake. Yet, why do we make mistake? Nobody would make a mistake if they know ahead of time what would be the consequence of that action. &lt;em&gt;But the point here is we don’t.&lt;/em&gt; That is why we must make mistake. There is no avoiding it. So when we look back at our mistake in life especially ones that our minds often replay in our heads, it is important to understand that there was nothing we can do to change the past. It is something that must happen the way it did and not any other way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changing Our Attitude with Our Mistakes in Life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how does one deal with one’s mistake? Here are 4 definitive steps to overcoming your mistake in life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Take Full Responsibility For Your Mistake And All Its Ramification&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;If we are unwilling to accept its consequences, then we are not ready to fully come to terms with our mistake. Have the courage to face your mistake. Be responsible for it. Don&#39;t run away from it. Mistake is by definition undesirable. But when we made a mistake, we must be strong and mature enough to take full responsibility for it whether or not it was intentionally or unintentionally, whether it effects just you or many other people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Think About What Is Best At This Very Moment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Is there a benefit in going over our mistake? If there is then please do. But if brooding over our mistake only rubs the salt in the wound, then perhaps there is no point in letting our mistake take over our lives. The best question to ask in this situation is, &quot;What can we control at this moment?&quot; Can we change the past? No. Can we change what is in the now? Yes. So let&#39;s focus on what we can change instead of what we can&#39;t. Let&#39;s ask relevant questions like, &quot;How can I do my best now so that I can avoid more mistake in the future?&quot; or &quot;What is the best thing to do right now?&quot; So without the burden of the past, &lt;strong&gt;move on by letting go of the past which you no longer have control and focus on what you can control in the present moment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Learn to Forgive Ourselves&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;It&#39;s impossible to move on if we do not forgive ourselves from our mistake. The characteristic of mistake in life is that they inevitable. Thus, it must happen the way it did. Looking back, you would never have done it. But because you did not know. That&#39;s why you made that mistake. So don&#39;t take it personally. Anyone who was in your shoes would have made the same mistake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Accepting Our Mistake as It Is. Do not Avoid, Hide, Deny, Blame Others, Bend, or Twist the Reality of Our Mistake.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;If you can&#39;t openly tell others your mistake, then this is perhaps a good indicator that there is something you still cannot accept about it. Of course, I am &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; suggesting for us to go out and tell everybody of our mistake either. My point is simply to come to understand ourselves to see if we still have our biases toward our mistake. If we still do then it is time to reconcile ourselves with these mistakes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Learning to Be with Your Mistake&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to reconcile with any mistakes in life is to accept it. Accepting is different from justifying our wrong doing. Accepting our mistake is to understand that there is no way of going back to fix the past of what we have done. Accepting our mistake is to be courageous and mature enough to accept whatever outcome and ramification that resulted as the direct or indirect outcome of our mistake. Accepting is to see no value in brooding or regretting our mistake, but instead see the value in what is in front of us. It is to be in the now by taking in the mistake as is, not as what you hope or do not hope it would be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a basic practice, when the mind wanders back to your mistake in life, &lt;strong&gt;do not fight it.&lt;/strong&gt; Do not find excuses for yourself about why you were not wrong. Do not look for a scapegoat. Observe the feelings associated with our mistakes, but let it be as it is without hoping the mistake would happen otherwise. Simply, know it and be mindful of it. Take it as it is. And understand that it must happen the way it did. Remind yourself of what is the best thing to do right now by knowing what you can and what you can’t control. And let go of our feelings by seeing how the bad feelings that comes with your mistake does not help you or anyone to be better. Eventually, your mistake will begin to lose its power as you slowly come to understand its nature. &lt;strong&gt;Don’t let your mistake of the past clouds what is in front you today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Worse, we even welcome it in our lives by letting the mistake take over us. This is similar to when you are sad and want to listen to a sad song just to make life sadder. We feel it is not enough for us to feel the pain of the mistake, so we begin rubbing the salt in the wound just so the pain can seep a little deeper.
 --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/03/09/why-am-i-unhappy-4/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/03/09/why-am-i-unhappy-4/</guid>
        
        <category>why-am-i-unhappy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cause of Unhappiness Part Three: Fear of Being Meaningless</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the worst fear of our lives is that we become meaningless. Whether this would be meaningless to oneself, meaningless to others, or meaningless to the world. Meaninglessness comes in various forms. The feeling of being useless, most evident in today society where everything is about productivity, to a feeling of inadequacy. At True Happiness, this is an important concept to understand as often times, we, humans, equate our self-worth with our meaning. So let’s dig a little deeper on this subject of meaninglessness to see where we could find True Happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; src=&quot;http://true-happiness.github.io/img/stick.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most renowned Theravada Buddhist Monk in Thailand, “Ajahn Chah,” once asked his disciples if a wooden stick–just like the one in the picture above–is long or short. Some answered, “It is long.” Some answered, “It is short.” But Ajahn Chah’s answer was not what one would unexpected. His answer is that the stick is neither long nor short. It is only long if we want it to be short. And it is short only if you want it to be long. Thus, the wooden stick is neither short or long. It is what it is. Only our want make it short or long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, our life is the same as that wooden stick. &lt;strong&gt;We are as meaningless as how much meaningful we want to be.&lt;/strong&gt; A rich person who want to be richer always feels he or she is not meaningful enough. So in a sense, he is “poor.” A poor person who feels that he or she has all that he or she could ever want is in way “rich.” It all depends on your want. If you want to be richer then immediately you are “poor.” If you feel you already have more than you want then at that very moment you are “rich.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We are as meaningless as how much meaningful we want to be.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moment you want to be more meaningful is the moment that you have become meaningless. Those who feels they are already meaningful has no need to search for more meaning in their life. They are already happy and satisfied with life. They have finished looking for more meaning to fill the void of their meaninglessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, &lt;strong&gt;to find true happiness is not to look for more meaning, but to stop looking for one&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;What To Take Away&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are as meaningless as how much meaningful we want to be. Thus, to find true happiness is not to look for meaning, but to stop looking for one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- 
&lt;p&gt;
	Meaning emernate from the function of difference. What I mean by that is meaning is only possible by comparing two things. The meaning of something is emernate from what it is not. How
&lt;/p&gt; --&gt;

&lt;!-- 
&lt;p&gt;Life, in essense, is incomparable to one another. Life is just is. You can compare all you want but at the end of the day how could you ever compare something so different to one another? So live and let live.&lt;/p&gt;

We are as meaningless as we want to be. 


&lt;p&gt;meaning = self-worth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have studied Philosophy espeically on the topic of epistemology or the study of how we know what we know then you will know that meaning emernate from a function of difference. What I mean by that is &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what I am going to tell you. First, it&#39;s ok to be meaningless.(decontructivist) Second, you are not meaningless.(constructivist)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are looking for a meaningful life, but to truly live is not to look for one.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If you want to be meaningful, then you need to have what it takes to be meaningless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;http://seattleinsight.org/Talks/BrowseTalks/DharmaTalk/tabid/90/TalkID/375/Default.aspx&quot;&gt;recommended talks&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;p&gt; 
	Let&#39;s face it. I believe we are all born with the fear of being meaningless. We are so fearful that we will not have any meaning that we live our lives trying to add meaning to ourselves. We buy things we do not need to help boost our ego. We want to get that degrees so that we look better than our friends. We want to get that job so that we feel better about ourselves. Why? because we feel we still do not have enough.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;It takes so little, so infinitely little, for someone to find himself on the other side of the border, where everything - love, convictions, faith, history - no longer has meaning. The whole mystery of human life resides on the fact that it is spent in the immediate proximity of, and even in direct contact with, that border, that it is separated from it not by kilometers but by barely a millimeter.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- Milan Kundera, The Book of Laughter and Forgetting&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This fear of being meaningless has been with us since we were born and it is at the core of our existence.

	We can&#39;t even rest anymore since it is tied to a sense of meaninglessness. We can&#39;t even not have a salary. How much salary we make become how meaningful we are.

	But is being meaningful or useful in life
&lt;/p&gt;


So why do we not want to be meaningless? What&#39;s wrong with being meaningless? I believe that the answer to this question is the fact that we were born with nothing to begin with.

So why do we fear meaninglessness?
How does meaningless cause us unhappiness?


&lt;p&gt;
	But we are born with nothing, and we will die with nothing. So actually whatever a little we have right now is already a plus. It is a gift just to be alive. It is a gift to be born healthy. Thus, it is not correct to assume that we are meaningless.

	It&#39;s ok to be meaningless. We were all born from being zero. 

	There are probably millions of infant motality  We have nothing to begin with. Why are we crying over something which is even already even better than when we are born. Many infants today die even before they get a chance to live. Why are we crying over our the bad luck despite being so lucky to live up until now?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Meaning is, therefore, relative. Let&#39;s say you feel you are not rich enough. And you are unhappy about it. 

	Meaning is created by comparing one thing with another. It simply the difference between one thing and another. Meaning does not emernate from the thing itself. 
&lt;/p&gt;
 --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/02/20/why-am-i-unhappy-3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/02/20/why-am-i-unhappy-3/</guid>
        
        <category>why-am-i-unhappy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Science of Happiness</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If I know water would boil at a 100 degrees Celsius. Do I need to hope it would boil at 100 degree Celsius? Or even if I do not want the water to be boiled, could I desire the water not to be boiled even if I heat it up to 100 degrees Celsius? I can hope, dance, or pray—or do all three at once—for it to rain tomorrow. However, if the causes are not right, it will not rain. Or maybe I do not want it to rain tomorrow. But again, if the conditions are right for it to rain, it will rain regardless of what I want or do not want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simple yet elegant wisdom that I am attempting to reiterate here is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reality has nothing to do with what one wants. Instead, reality has everything to do with the law of cause and effect.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the causes are right for an effect to occur, it will occur regardless of what one wants or do not want. Scientifically speaking, there is no room for desires in reality. There is only cause and effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The common way, we, humans, achieve happiness in life is to put what we desire in front of the causes we must perform to achieve the result. We start a project by wanting it to be finished. We run a business by hoping to gain and never to lose. We often live by being afraid of dying even though we are perfectly fine. Even when we are deeply in love with someone, we can’t help ourselves feeling a little insecure about how long the good time will last. Humans always put our desire in front of what the reality is. For this reason, our pursue of happiness has led us to constantly become fearful, worried, impatient, and frustrated by what we demand from reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But is this really necessary? or is there a better way of pursuing happiness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Two Approaches Toward True Happiness: One Is Scientific And Other Is Not.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ways of achieving anything in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Desire-Oriented Approach to Happiness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This human’s most typical approach toward happiness. By putting our desire in front of what the reality is, our happiness is externalized and is dependent what we hope from the reality than what the reality is. And thus, he or she can never be happy until his desire is fulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Reality-Oriented Approach to Happiness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second way is to work toward your goal without the need to get ahead of ourselves. In other words, to work with and according to what the reality is, not work from the stance of what we expect reality to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man whose desire is with reality is always satisfied with what is. Since his desire is in tune with reality, he is not anxious or worry. This, in turn, allows him to become more composed, relaxed, and ultimately more productive while working toward his goal with a peace of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I am explaining here is also captured by Epictetus as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Do not seek to have events happen as you want them to, but instead want them to happen as they do happen, and your life will go well.
-Epictetus&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Our Duty To Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone—like me—is applying for graduate school I might, right away, desires to be accepted. But who am I to want or not want things from reality without ever creating the right causes for it to happen? In reality, whether or not anyone would or would not be accepted has many different factors—many beyond one’s control. So just by applying or having a great supporting resume doesn’t mean I have the right to demand or hope from reality my admission. So why hope? Why put my desire ahead of the reality? Why worry? And why not channel this energy, instead, at creating the right causes which are writing the best application?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can attain anything in life &lt;em&gt;with or without&lt;/em&gt; the need to desire for it. But since reality runs by the absolute law of cause and effect, it does not obey one’s desire no matter how large or small the desire. The only that matters is whether or not there is enough causes for the effect to occur. Thus, there is no need to desire because…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;One simply can&#39;t. &lt;strong&gt;There is no room for desire in reality.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;It is unscientific. How can I hope the tree to grow instantly if I just put the seed into the soil? Every effect must has it rightful causes.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Putting our demands of the reality before the reality is the root of all unhappiness of life. Why suffer?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One does not need to desire to achieve whatever he or she set out to accomplish. Our duty to life is not to desire, but to create the right causes to produce the right effect. And depending on how well one could live in accordance with this natural law and not according to what he or she demands of reality, the happier he or she becomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.7;&quot;&gt;All in all, the message here is simple: life is happier, better, and more satisfactory if one lives in accordance with reality and its law rather than living in accordance with what one wants from reality. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.7;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reality does not revolves around what one wants from it; it revolves around the absolute law of cause and effect.&lt;/strong&gt; Thus, life is never like what one wants it to be. The only way for anyone to feel the unsatisfactoriness of life is to be unmindful of the law of conditionality and desire life or reality to be the way one wants. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&#39;What&#39;s worse, the falling rain, or your resistance to getting wet?&#39;
- Jeff Foster&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.7;&quot;&gt;So let’s keep our feet on the ground; and stay with reality and its law. Forget about all your fantasies about how reality should be. Instead, focus on, be satisfied, and accept what is. Begin living in the now! Keep on working with reality by making the right causes to achieve the right effect. And always remember that the way to live happily, correctly, and more efficiently, is not to put our desires in front of our reality, but the other way around.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/01/07/no-room-for-desire-in-life/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/01/07/no-room-for-desire-in-life/</guid>
        
        <category>cause-of-true-happiness</category>
        
        <category>true-happiness-essential</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Six Greatest Gifts You Can Give Your Loved Ones</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;So if we love someone, we should train in being able to listen. By listening with calm and understanding, we can ease the suffering of another person.&amp;#8221; &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8211; Thich Nhat Hanh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s Christmastime and it&amp;#8217;s the season of giving &amp;#8230; what are you giving your loved ones this year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The holidays often mean giving a lot of gifts, sometimes expensive, but often we lose sight of what&amp;#8217;s most important.&lt;span id=&quot;more-2072&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What gifts do your loved ones really want, whether they&amp;#8217;re your children, your significant other, your parents, your friends, or other family members? Is it an expensive electronic item, or some other material or tangible item? Perhaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the gifts I list below are more important. Sure, they might not be as fun to open on Christmas morning (or whatever other holiday you might celebrate), but in the long run, they&amp;#8217;ll value these gifts more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Your Presence&lt;/strong&gt;. This means making it a priority to spend time with them &amp;#8212; if they are truly important, you can make the time. You might have to change things in your life to make the time, but it&amp;#8217;s worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond just making the time, though, you have to actually be present when you spend time with loved ones. That means learning to stay in the moment, rather than having your mind on other things, checking your iPhone or Blackberry every two minutes, or trying to take care of other tasks and chores while spending time with them. Instead, drop everything else and focus on being there with your loved ones &amp;#8212; really listen, really have fun, really be present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Your Love&lt;/strong&gt;. This is perhaps an obvious one on the list, but it&amp;#8217;s too important to gloss over. It&amp;#8217;s imperative that you tell your loved ones that &amp;#8230; well, that you love them. Regularly. But just as important is that you actually show them you love them, in your actions every day, throughout the day. Hugs, intimacy, smiles, doing kind things for them, considering their needs and feelings &amp;#8230; just little things that mean a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Your Compassion&lt;/strong&gt;. How is this different than giving the gift of your love? Well, it&amp;#8217;s possible to love someone and not show compassion. For example, we parents often discipline our children and love them at the same time &amp;#8230; but often compassion is even more important than discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compassion is finding empathy with your loved one &amp;#8230; trying to see things from their eyes, trying to understand what they&amp;#8217;re going through &amp;#8230; and then doing your best to be kind and to end their suffering and to make them happier. &lt;a href=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/2007/06/a-guide-to-cultivating-compassion-in-your-life-with-7-practices/&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. A Voice&lt;/strong&gt;. We can give so much just by paying attention to a loved one, and really listening, and showing that we&amp;#8217;re interested in what they have to say, and showing that what they say is important and respected. Too often our children or spouse might talk to us but are only met with a disinterested nod or other small acknowledgment, or we&amp;#8217;ll make light or fun of what they say, as if it&amp;#8217;s not important. But giving a person a voice, and showing that their words matter, will have a long-lasting different in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. A Healthy Lifestyle&lt;/strong&gt;. When you spend time with your loved one, try to do so while enjoying a healthy and fun activity, such as going on a hike, playing a sport, tossing around a Frisbee, going for a walk or jog, doing some yardwork, and so on. When you get together to eat, try to eat healthy foods. Make the habits of good health a part of your lifestyle, and encourage your loved ones to do the same &amp;#8212; it could save their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Your Belief in Them&lt;/strong&gt;. Simply believing in another person, and showing that in your words and in your deeds, can make a huge difference. Studies of people who grew up in dysfunctional homes but who grew up to be happy and successful show that the one thing they had in common was a significant adult who believed in them. Do this for your child, and for the adult loved ones in your life as well. Support their dreams and passions and hobbies. Participate with them. Be nothing but encouraging. Be their greatest cheerleader. Whether they actually accomplish these dreams or not, your belief is of unlimited importance to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Love and compassion are necessities, not luxuries. Without them, humanity cannot survive.&amp;#8221; &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8211; the Dalai Lama&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/12/24/six-greatest-gifts-you-can-give-your-loved-ones/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/12/24/six-greatest-gifts-you-can-give-your-loved-ones/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cause of Unhappiness Part Two: Comparing Yourself to Others</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Human’s innate ability to compare ourselves to others is perhaps the root of all sins in this world. Knowing that I am better create a sense of pride or even arrogant, while knowing that I am less create a sense of envy and jealousy toward the other. There can be no ends to our comparison unless we stop to put any value into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The fuels behind our comparisons are our likes and dislikes.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say for example that we would like to be promoted. However, someone was promoted instead. We can’t help but feel disappointed or even a sense of hate or jealousy. Why? Because we believe a promotion has value and is desirable. But if we did not want to be promoted in the first place then we simply would not care who got promoted or didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to be someone who enjoyed being better than others. My identity was dependent upon others being less than who I am. Every conservation I start every word I speak leak a sense of pride and the desperate need to show off myself. When I met someone who is worse of than I am then I became overjoyed because I felt I was “better”. But when I met someone who was better suddenly I felt scared and inferior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My happiness was contextual. I thought my happiness was to look better than others, but what I couldn’t see is how tiresome it was for me as well as those around me to put up with my own inferiority complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness is not to be taken likely. If one does not take care of it and see it objectively. It is most likely that this kind of pursue of “happiness” will never stop. And for me or for anyone, they would forever carry around this “happiness” complex without noticing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mindfulness saves my life.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was lucky. I somehow found my way to the practice of mindfulness. Through the practice mindfulness, I began to reflect upon this inferiority complex I called “happiness”. And the more I reflect the more I see its negative effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it is rather obnoxious for others who have to put up with my own insecurity. No one likes someone who fill up the conversation only to boast about himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, it was tiresome to try to talk about how great you are in every context. I simply can’t be happy by myself. I needed someone to be better than at all time else I couldn’t be happy. When I felt like I am better than a person, I became happy. When that person or someone else become better than me then I became unsatisfied. My happiness was fleeting. It’s the kind of happiness which is dependent upon whether or not the context allow me to feel as if I am “better” than others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I eventually realise is that it was too hard for me to find happiness. My happiness to look better didn’t do anyone, including myself, any good except fulfilling the unfulfillable desire to look “better”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comparing myself to others did not bring me any joy, only pain and bitterness. Thus, I quit.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to Stop Comparing Yourself to Others&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Reflect. As long as you are biased toward yourself and your ways of attaining happiness, you will never find True Happiness. You will say, &quot;This is my happiness. Why would I change?&quot; Thus, it is necessary to have the desire to improve one&#39;s happiness by reflecting often. Question yourself. Why I am still unhappy even though I am trying to be happy? And if possible, learn to be mindful of your actions to see whether they are driven by your unwholesome desire or the desire to prove yourself. Know thyself and change yourself before it&#39;s too late!&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Knowing that there is no ends to comparing yourself to others. You will never be satisfied because your satisfaction is relative to how others are.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Better could mean worse and less is sometimes more. It all depends on which standard or perspective are you putting yourself against. No one is better or worse. Everyone has different background and up-bring and naturally each is incomparably different from one another.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Seeing the negative effects it has on oneself and everyone around you.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Compare yourself today with yourself yesterday&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Learn the art of mindfulness! &lt;a href=&quot;http://true-happiness.github.io/tags/practice-of-true-happiness/&quot;&gt;Click here to learn!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;p&gt;
Knowing this, I am reminded of story of Adam and Even in the Holy Bible where God warned Adam and Eve not eat the forbidden fruit of knowledge of good and evil. But they did and now it has began our original sin.

With our knowledge of what is good and bad, we are driven for that which is good and 
&lt;/p&gt;
 --&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;p&gt;There is no good or evil in reality. Atoms or molecules are neither good or bad. They are just the way they are. Only human made them &quot;good&quot; or &quot;bad&quot;. Thus, there is no static good or bad.&lt;/p&gt; --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/12/19/why-am-I-unhappy-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/12/19/why-am-I-unhappy-2/</guid>
        
        <category>why-am-i-unhappy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cause of Unhappiness Part One: Externalizing Our Happiness</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;Happiness is like a string which ties us to that which we believe is our happiness.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We, humans, have many things which our happiness is dependent upon whether it would be our wealth, health, or our love ones. Let’s say for example that if you tie your happiness with being rich and accepted, then as long as you are not rich and accepted you can not be happy. Similarly, if you rest your happiness on your promotion then the promotion becomes the happiness which you have put outside of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, the society &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; encourages us to put our happiness outside of ourselves. The media is telling us that for one to be happy one needs to have a new iPhone, a big house, a good job, and a beautiful spouse, a degree from Harvard and on and on. Imagine ourselves being tied to millions of these strings which we come to know as “happiness”. What we soon realise is that “happiness” starts to become a spider webs in which we are the preys. Each “happiness” is pulling us left and right to the point that it becomes impossible to obtain any happiness or freedom in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading capitalized&quot;&gt;So What Do We Do?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we keep our happiness with us? Here are some interesting concepts to contemplate and chew on which will help you find True Happiness in this chaotic world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;1. Don&#39;t Let Anything Defines Your Self-Worth.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The worst thing you can do for yourself is to let money defines your self-worth. And the worst thing you can do to others is to define others&#39; self-worth through money.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing can define your self-worth unless you let it. However, one way we, humans, externalize our happiness is to let something else defines our self-worth. This is very common in our materialistic society where often times we let material–like cars, money, cloth, or house–tells us our self-worth. If we let material defines our self-worth then material becomes our happiness. The more material or wealth we have the happier we becomes and inversely the less material or wealth we have the more unhappy we become. So by letting money defines ourselves our happiness becomes dependent to money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The happiest man on earth does not rest his “happiness” on anything. And for that reason, he cannot not be happy. He does not need to be “rich” to be happy. He does not need to be “smart” to be happy. He does not need other’s compliment or affection to be happy. He is already happiness as is. There is no happiness which he has externalized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, material or outer wealth has nothing to do with ourselves self-worth from the very start. When we were young materialism does not affect our world much. We wear whatever we want. We be whoever we want to be without feeling superior or inferior to anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whatever we come to value we also judge.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we let money defines our self-worth, we, in the same way, judge others through money. When how much money one has can define a person, there is naturally someone who is worse, or the same as the others. When such valuation of our humanity is as such. This valuation becomes the root of discrimination, prejudice, jealousy, pride and arrogant. Hence, one should be very careful about what one values and how far one takes it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading capitalized&quot;&gt;2. Good Or Bad Is A Matter Of Human&#39;s Perspective&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Good or bad, rich or poor, beautiful or ugly, these dualities are man-made. In God&#39;s eyes there is no such thing as good or bad. For Him, everything is just is.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether or not we have externalized our happiness, the value we perceive about ourselves–whether we believe we are rich or poor, beautiful or ugly, successful or unsuccessful, young or old, worthy or worthless–is only a matter of how and what we compare ourselves to. If you compare yourself to someone who are less fortunate than you might be “rich.” But if you compare yourself to a billionaire then we are, in a way, “poor”. So we are both “rich” and “poor” and at the same time we are neither. Positivity or negativity is a matter of perspective. In the realm of the ultimate reality, there is no one who is better or worse. We are just who we are–incomparably different from one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;3. Question Your Happiness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;A happy life must always be simple no matter how complicate our lives have become.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people rarely question their own happiness. But in order to maintain a happy life, it is necessary to regularly check up on what we called “happiness.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a practice, I suggest you to regularly review your life. I personally have a habit of writing a journal every night before going to bed to see what is bothering my mind. List them all out, question this list of what you called “happiness” then sort only ones that matter most to you while eliminating others which are not. You will easily find many things which you desire yet they are unnecessary towards life and are, in some ways, even weighting you down from achieving what really matters. Is it all that important to be “successful” in eyes of the others? Is being rich the answer to life? Is it worth it to trade your inner happiness for an outer one? Is my family comes first before my work? Slowly find out what matters to you most. Cut out any unnecessary wants. Eventually your life will feel lighter as you let go of those extraneous ties of “happiness.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing where your happiness truly belongs is a skill one which can be improved by learning to quickly identify where you have misplaced your happiness. This is what mindfulness is for. (Click &lt;a href=&quot;http://true-happiness.github.io/tags/true-happiness-essential/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about the practice of True Happiness.) And once you can see that these ties of “happiness” have been causing you more pain than happiness then perhaps it is time to let go. As a rule of thumb, the less ties of “happiness” we have the easier for us to find happiness in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;What To Take Away&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happiness is a delicate science. It is intriguing how sometimes even the things in which we believe will bring us “happiness” can end up causing us more unhappiness than happiness. Who would have thought that the way to be happy is less about pursuing it than questioning it? Happiness should never be ahead of us. It should be with us even though we are pursuing something ahead of us. Happiness is like a fire. And it is advisable that one be very careful with what you believe to be “happiness”. Question it. Simplify it. Deconstruction it. And what you will find is that there is nothing you need more to make you happy since our heart is by nature already happy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/12/12/why-am-I-unhappy-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/12/12/why-am-I-unhappy-1/</guid>
        
        <category>why-am-i-unhappy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Empty Handed Full Hearted</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We often load ourselves up when we travel, because we want to be prepared for various situations. This burden of being prepared leaves us with our arms full, unable to receive whatever is there when we arrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It leaves us tired from carrying, so that we are not happy when we meet someone new on our travels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if we traveled with empty hands, ready to embrace new experiences, receive new foods, touch new people?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We might feel less prepared when we leave, but the preparedness is an illusion. Stuff doesn&amp;#8217;t make us prepared. Having empty hands but a heart that is full of love leaves us prepared for anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn&amp;#8217;t just apply to taking a trip, but to living each day. Each day is a journey, and we load ourselves up with material possessions, with tasks and projects, with things to read and write, with meetings and calls and texts. Our hands are full, not ready for anything new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drop everything, be &lt;a href=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/embrace-chaos/&quot;&gt;open to everything&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter each day empty-handed, and full-hearted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/11/21/empty-handed-full-hearted/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/11/21/empty-handed-full-hearted/</guid>
        
        <category></category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Simplify</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8216;In proportion as he simplifies his life, the laws of the universe will appear less complex, and solitude will not be solitude, nor poverty poverty, nor weakness weakness.&amp;#8217; &lt;strong&gt;~Henry David Thoreau&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tendency of life in our society is to become more complicated: Internet, television, shopping, work, family commitments, possessions, eating, debt &amp;#8230; these things pile on top of each other endlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a rather bad formula, as our days have a limited capacity, and so do we as humans. We can only do so much, only handle so many tasks and possessions and social commitments, and filling ourselves to those limits means we stress our breaking points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It takes a bit of conscious effort to simplify, but it&amp;#8217;s one of the greatest things I&amp;#8217;ve ever learned to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simplify everything. That might sound hard, but with practice it&amp;#8217;s actually fairly easy, and leads to a quiet, content, lovely life full of space, with only the things in it that matter to me: my family, my writing, with some reading and workouts thrown in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do you simplify? As simply as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Block off some disconnected time&lt;/strong&gt;. The Internet is amazing, but always being connected means you&amp;#8217;re always pulled in a thousand directions at once. It&amp;#8217;s hard to focus, hard to connect with others, hard to get out into nature and be active. So schedule some time every day for disconnection: maybe a block in the morning where you get your best work done, and a block in the afternoon when you get out and active, or connect with friends or family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start eliminating commitments&lt;/strong&gt;. List your commitments, and pick one to eliminate today. It&amp;#8217;s a simple matter of making a call or sending an email explaining that you can&amp;#8217;t do the commitment. Trust me, they&amp;#8217;ll find a way to live without you. You&amp;#8217;ll start to free up time for what&amp;#8217;s more important to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start purging possessions&lt;/strong&gt;. Every day, find 5 things to donate or give to friends. Or clear an entire shelf or countertop, leaving only the things you actually use, getting rid of the rest. Slowly your possessions will be simplified to just the essentials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ban shopping for 30 days&lt;/strong&gt;. You can do this. Don&amp;#8217;t buy anything except the essentials (food, toiletries, basic supplies). If you think you really need it, put it on a list to be evaluated after the 30 days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wash your bowl&lt;/strong&gt;. When you&amp;#8217;re done eating, mindfully wash your bowl. When you&amp;#8217;re done with anything, get in the habit of pausing before moving onto the next thing, and cleaning up after yourself. Put your food away. Put your clothes where they belong. Put your keys in one spot. Clean the sink before you leave it. This simple habit will keep you mindful while saving you lots of cleanup later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schedule time for what&amp;#8217;s important&lt;/strong&gt;. What&amp;#8217;s most important to you? Your spouse or kids? Creating? Reading novels? Cooking, gardening, crafts, carpentry? Make the time for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get outdoors once a day&lt;/strong&gt;. Too often we are stuck at a desk or on the couch. Get outside, take a walk, enjoy the fresh air and sunshine. Go for a hike or a run with a friend. Play some sports. Run around and play tag with your kids. These simple activities will change your life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eat some plants&lt;/strong&gt;. Learn some simple recipes that incorporate super healthy foods you might not be eating: kale, spinach, broccoli, quinoa, berries, flaxseeds, lentils, avocados, black beans, squash, raw almonds and walnuts, garlic, turmeric, cayenne, cinnamon. These simple plants will make you strong like oxen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drink tea&lt;/strong&gt;. Green tea brewed from relatively fresh whole tea leaves is calming, healthy, and wonderful. A daily tea ritual keeps you grounded and mindful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/yoyo/2015/09/17/simplify/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/yoyo/2015/09/17/simplify/</guid>
        
        <category></category>
        
        
        <category>yoyo</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why True Happiness Matters</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;!-- &lt;h2 class=&#39;text-center&#39;&gt;Saving the World Through Mindfulness One Breath At a Time&lt;/h2&gt;
 --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would making everyone in the world richer give us world peace? If wealth can save the world, why are we nowhere near world peace despite the fact that our GDP has increased by the thousand folds compare to what it was hundreds years ago? Even if it rains in gold today, what we will have is not world peace. But more likely wars in which people would fight one another to be richer even though they might already be rich.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would giving humans more power give us world peace? Since the beginning of our civilization, humanity has poured unimaginable amount of resources into bettering our education system. But does giving humans more power and skills without teaching how to excercise that power lead us toward world peace? Theodore Roosevelt once stated:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;A man who has never gone to school may steal from a freight car; but if he has a university education, he may steal the whole railroad.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Power is a double-edged sword. One which must not be taken lightly. Imagine a simple scenario in which you are a swordmaster. And you are now deciding which of your pupils to teach. Would you give someone the ability to take life to someone who finds happiness in taking from others or would you give it to someone who finds happiness in giving to others? The obvious answer is the latter. Thus..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;capitalized&quot;&gt;Happiness can and must be developed.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness matters. It is what create our world, for good or for evil. It dictates people lives and decides how our world will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By developing our happiness, not only will humanity finds both Truth and True Happiness, but it will also along the way create the right condition for world peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;capitalized&quot;&gt;World Peace is not possible without True Happiness.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More wealth will not stop people from their greed. And more power will not stop people from abusing it. World peace cannot be achieved by changing what is outside of us, it is achieved by developing how each and every one of us seeks and defines happiness inside of ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than sharing the way to True Happiness, this is also another the noble goal which this website aims to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;float-center text-center&quot;&gt;World Peace Begins Here In Our Journey Toward True Happiness.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/08/24/why_true_happiness/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/08/24/why_true_happiness/</guid>
        
        <category>true-happiness-essential</category>
        
        <category>why-true-happiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Attain Happiness?</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#39;What&#39;s worse, the falling rain, or your resistance to getting wet?&#39;&lt;br /&gt;- Jeff Foster&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quote above is what I believe best summarizes how happiness is a matter of what&#39;s going on inside of us more than a matter of what&#39;s going on outside. We can&#39;t be mad at reality. Reality is just is. But our attitude toward reality, that&#39;s up to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness is not about getting what we want. It is about knowing how to want what we get. And for that very reason, one must learn how to want which requires us to change ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actual process of changing oneself is not hard. What is hard is the fact that &lt;strong&gt;we do not, cannot, and do not want to alter ourselves.&lt;/strong&gt; This is why &lt;strong&gt;the problem here is not so much that we cannot change as much as we do not want to change ourselves.&lt;/strong&gt;  I never hear anyone defines happiness as  “how to want what we get.” It’s always the other way around. Worse we say, &quot;It’s what I want, why would I question my own want?”, &quot;It’s what I hate, why I would alter myself to not hate?” The only time we ever decide to change our want is when our wants have become unbearable. It is the only after the damage that our wants have caused that we are willing to change. This is the common attitude which makes it so difficult to change ourselves which, in turn, makes it so difficult for us to be happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you are ready to be happy, below are the steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Four Core Habits to True Happiness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know Thyself&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;I am not going to lie to you: Happiness requires work and expertise. You can&#39;t master what you do not know well. And you definitely can&#39;t know anything well if you do not even know it in the first place! Thus, to master ourselves, the first step toward True Happiness is to know ourselves. Knowing ourselves is by far the most important steps in changing ourselves. It will be where we work. It is our laboratory where we do our experiment in happiness. The goal is to learn the truth and nature of both ourselves and reality in order to achieve harmony between the two. (For more information, &lt;a href=&quot;/2016/03/22/why-meditate/&quot;&gt;Click Here&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- 	&lt;p&gt;I won&#39;t go into details about the how here. These are the links to some articles at True Happiness that will guide you in detail about the how.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
			
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
			
		&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt; --&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be an Expert: Truly Understand the Nature of Happiness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Once you have your practice of knowing yourself or mindfulness rock solid, you are now ready to walk toward True Happiness. Being able to walk is different from knowing where to walk to. Thus, the next step is to learn as much as you can from those who have walked before us so that we will have a road map of where we are taking ourselves toward. Happiness is delicate science which could even take more than a life-time to learn. But it is definitely the most meaningful, fulfilling, and beautiful journey you will ever take.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;capitalized&quot;&gt;Learn to see life for what it is and not for what you want or don&#39;t want it to be.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Once you understand what you are doing and learn some basic about how to practice, it is time to applied it into your own life. And the result of understanding life is the ability to see it objectively.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find a Role Model and a Learning Communities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;There will be times when it is difficult for us to continue on our journey. There will be struggles. There will be confusions about how to go about one&#39;s inner path. Thus, what you need is others to go with you especially those who have already walked the path. Don&#39;t expect this to be a solo journey. It&#39;s nearly impossible alone. Thus, finding your supportive community of practitioners and people who have mastered this art of happiness is a must.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True Happiness is impossible if we are unwilling to change ourselves. And the only steps toward True Happiness is just to know ourselves. It is as simple as that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next article will we will look at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/08/24/why_true_happiness/&quot;&gt;why happiness matters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to the world and how developing our happiness is the key for making the world a better place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/07/23/how_of_happiness/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/07/23/how_of_happiness/</guid>
        
        <category>practice-of-true-happiness</category>
        
        <category>true-happiness-essential</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Causes and Conditions of Happiness</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;By looking at the &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/06/01/what_is_happiness/&quot;&gt;definition of happiness&lt;/a&gt; alone, one could come to the conclusion that there are two ways of approaching happiness in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To learn how to change reality to fits our want.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To learn how to change our wants to fit the reality.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mix and match between the two approach is also possible. Either way both are ways of achieving happiness by synchronizing our wants and reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why Our Common Approach of Happiness Makes Us Unhappy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first approach is the common approach that we, humans, use to find happiness which is to do our best to change reality to fits our want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;strong&gt;two major fallacies&lt;/strong&gt; in this approach to happiness:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Our want, if untrained, is ever-expanding in its demand of the reality.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we are rich we want to be richer. When we see someone who is happy, we too want to be like them. When we see our friends succeed sometimes we can’t help but feel a sense of jealousy or inferiority. There is no end to our want. Imagine if there is a million of things that we want but have not achieved, then we have a million things that are unsatisfactory in our lives. That does not sounds like a good, happy, and fulfilling life. When we infinitely want things from the reality then we infinitely must suffer from our unending chase of happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could we demand the dead to come back to life? The obvious answer is no. Could we expect everyone to like us without being disliked? The answer is very unlikely. Even though we all know these facts but still our mind will not easily accept it. When someone talked behind our back, we become agitated and wish that person to stop. When someone we love passed away, we wish that person would still be alive with us. An untrained mind does not play by the rules or law of the universe. It does not live with reality. It takes in, hold on and grab whatever that it likes and push away or destroy all that it does not like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. By trying to satisfy our want only by changing what is outside of us we overlook the other half of happiness which is inside of us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we only work to change what is the outside of ourselves. We left our wants static, unchanging and unquestioned across time and space. But the fact of life is that &lt;strong&gt;we can’t always get what we want.&lt;/strong&gt; Life does not always goes according to what we want. Often times than not, there are too many things in which we can not change the reality to be like how we want. These could be something as obvious as death, sickness, and old-age. It could be our inability to control others’ thought, speech, and action. It even could be something as trivial as a stomach-ache in which we can’t command it to stop being painful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reality is never satisfactory with our expanding minds wanting the impossible. With our untrained minds, we are stuck in the situation where we have unchanging want in an ever-changing reality, unrealistic want in a realistic reality, and an infinite want in a finite reality. And naturally, we end up being the ones who suffer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, the cause of our happiness depends on how much we can harmonize our wants with our reality. We all know how to change what is outside of us but not many people know how to change what is inside. The less you know about yourself and its nature, the less control you have over it. And inversely, the more unhappiness you will have in your life. I believe this is why Horace, a famous greek philosopher, said this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;“Rule your mind or it will rule you.”&lt;br /&gt;- Horace&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next article, “&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/07/23/how_of_happiness/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Attain Happiness?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;”, will introduce to you to the other missing half of achieving True Happiness. It will introduce you to the basics of changing and improving oneself and how it is imperative to our happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/06/29/cause_of_happiness/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/06/29/cause_of_happiness/</guid>
        
        <category>true-happiness-essential</category>
        
        <category>cause-of-true-happiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is Happiness?</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Happiness, in its most typical definition, is to get what we want. We would be happy if we always get what we want. We would be happy if everything goes exactly like how we want life to be. Once we get all that we want, we become content and satisfied with life. This sense of contentment, fulfilment, and satisfaction is ultimately what happiness is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three basic components of happiness:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;One’s desire&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The reality or the world&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;And their interaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness is when what you want from reality is in harmony with what reality is; or to put it in an even simpler term, happiness is when life is exactly like how you want it to be. There is nothing that you want more or less. Life is just perfect as it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;It&#39;s impossible to know what happiness is unless you also know what unhappiness is.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unhappiness, on the other hand, is when the reality is not like what you want it to be. Anything which you want but couldn’t have, anything that you do not want yet it enters into your life, anything that you used to have but now it’s gone. These are the unhappinesses of life which we come to know as worry, frustration, disappointment, depression, confusion, and etc. As an example, disappointment is when the reality is not what you hope it would be. And worry is when you want the reality to be a certain way, yet you are afraid it might not be like what you hope. In essence, all of these array of negative emotions, or unhappinesses, stem from the disharmony between what we want from reality and what the reality is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, understanding happiness is the easy part. The hard part is how to attain one. Why are we &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; always happy despite our knowledge of happiness? If happiness is simply to match reality and our want then where did we go wrong in this simple process to produce happiness? Why does our pursuit of happiness still lead us toward discontent and sometimes even a sense of meaninglessness in life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer these questions, the next article, “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/06/29/cause_of_happiness/&quot;&gt;The Cause and Condition of Happiness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;”, will introduce you into the nature of happiness, so that we will understand how to attain one. Click on the button below!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/06/01/what_is_happiness/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/06/01/what_is_happiness/</guid>
        
        <category>true-happiness-essential</category>
        
        <category>what-is-true-happiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Secret Habit to Success</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In Og Mandino&amp;#8217;s self-help classic, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/055327757X?ie=UTF8&amp;#038;tag=zenhab-20&amp;#038;linkCode=as2&amp;#038;camp=1789&amp;#038;creative=9325&amp;#038;creativeASIN=055327757X&quot;&gt;The Greatest Salesman in the World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=zenhab-20&amp;#038;l=as2&amp;#038;o=1&amp;#038;a=055327757X&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;, one of his more powerful concepts is how to form good habits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will form good habits and become their slave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will read each scroll for thirty days in this prescribed manner, before I proceed to the next scroll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I will read the words in silence when I arise. Then, I will read the words in silence after I have partaken of my midday meal. Last, I will read the words again just before I retire at day&amp;#8217;s end, and most important, on this occasion I will read the words aloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the next day I will repeat this procedure, and I will continue in like manner for thirty days. Then, I will turn to the next scroll and repeat this procedure for another thirty days. I will continue in this manner until I have lived with each scroll for thirty days and my reading has become habit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So basically, the habit is to read from the 10 Scrolls for 30 days each, morning, noon and night &amp;#8212; but the challenging part is holding back so you only do one scroll per month. &lt;strong&gt;And the first month, you focus on the process of forming those good habits.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you draw from that powerful concept, and start by first teaching yourself how to form a habit, and then focus on one habit for each of the following months, you will be more successful with each habit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So here&amp;#8217;s the secret: for the first month&amp;#8217;s habit, you need to develop the discipline of reading a mantra morning, noon and night &amp;#8211; the First Habit.&lt;/strong&gt; It can be a mantra you write yourself, or one that I suggest below. If you can stick to that habit for a month, you can build on that success and start with a second habit &amp;#8212; staying with another small one is best. Each month, you can work on a new habit, focusing on only one per month. But the key is to have the patience to work on only that First Habit for the first month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of us have a bunch of habits we&amp;#8217;d like to instill in our daily routine &amp;#8212; from eating healthy, to exercise, reading, writing, waking early, organization, frugality and more &amp;#8212; and it&amp;#8217;s hard not to try to conquer them all at once. But if you can do this, and hold off on those habits until you&amp;#8217;ve accomplished this one, &lt;strong&gt;you&amp;#8217;ll have a much, much greater chance of success at all of them&lt;/strong&gt;. Having the patience to do this won&amp;#8217;t be easy, but remember: you have your entire life ahead of you. If you follow this program, and you&amp;#8217;re successful, you&amp;#8217;ll have eight more habits developed by the end of this year (starting with your next habit in May), and 12 more the next year, and so on. It&amp;#8217;s worth the wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do you implement this First Habit? Here&amp;#8217;s the plan:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commit Thyself.&lt;/strong&gt; Commit to doing this First Habit for the rest of this month (or if you&amp;#8217;re starting late, do it for 30 days).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morning Habit.&lt;/strong&gt; Every morning, when you wake up, silently read this mantra (borrowed in part from reader &lt;a href=&quot;http://gitmo2007.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Ann M.&lt;/a&gt;, and in part from Og Mandino): &amp;#8220;Today, I start a new life. Today, I create a new, positive habit. The only difference between those who have failed and those who have succeeded lies in the difference of their habits. Good habits are the key to all success. Thus, the first law I will obey is: I will form good habits and become their slave. Today, I take control of my actions and behaviors. With these, I create my life and destiny.&amp;#8221;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Midday Habit.&lt;/strong&gt; Every day after you eat lunch, silently read the above mantra.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evening Habit.&lt;/strong&gt; Every evening, just before you go to bed, read the above mantra out loud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tracking Habit.&lt;/strong&gt; Create a chart or log, and each day give yourself a checkmark, gold star, or other such mark so that you can see that you&amp;#8217;ve done the habit every single day. Don&amp;#8217;t miss a day, no matter what &amp;#8212; if you can do it every day, without fail, you will have create a 3x-a-day habit that you can use to build upon for your next habit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Future Habits.&lt;/strong&gt; Make a list of what habits you&amp;#8217;d like to work on each month, once you&amp;#8217;ve successfully completed the First Habit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivation Hacks.&lt;/strong&gt; If possible, use as many of the Top 20 Motivation hacks to help you stick to your habit for the rest of the month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Celebration Time!&lt;/strong&gt; Celebrate your successes along the way, and celebrate when you&amp;#8217;re done!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resolve yourself to this First Habit, and you&amp;#8217;ll be inspired by your own success. From Og Mandino:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And I make a solemn oath to myself that nothing will retard my new life&amp;#8217;s growth. I will lose not a day from these readings for that day cannot be retrieved nor can I substitute another for it. I must not , I will not, break this habit of daily reading from these scrolls and, in truth, the few moments spent each day on this new habit are but a small price to pay for the happiness and success that will be mine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So here&amp;#8217;s your challenge: Commit to doing this First Habit, morning noon and night, for a month.&lt;/strong&gt; That simple. Then you can move on to other habits, once this one is established.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/05/30/the-secret-habit-to-success-an-april-challenge/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/05/30/the-secret-habit-to-success-an-april-challenge/</guid>
        
        <category>self-improvement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Half Step That Will Change Your Life</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;d be surprised to know how many emails I get where people are stuck in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&amp;#8217;re broke, or unmotivated, or in a job they hate, or they can&amp;#8217;t find their passion, or they can&amp;#8217;t get motivated to get healthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they don&amp;#8217;t know where to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It hurts to read these emails. It brings back to life the pain I lived through not too many years ago, when I too was stuck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know the feeling of despair when you are unhappy with your life and don&amp;#8217;t know how to change. When you&amp;#8217;ve tried lots of changes, but couldn&amp;#8217;t find the discipline to make them stick. When you feel crappy about yourself because you know you should get off your butt and start improving your life, but you&amp;#8217;d rather put it off for another day.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;more-8744&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Problems go away when you ignore them, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also know that there is really only one way out of this mire of despair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s to take an action, no matter how tiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#8217;t need to fix everything in your life right now. You don&amp;#8217;t even need to fix one thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You just need to do one little, miniscule, almost nothing thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make a list. Go outside and take a walk. Get rid of some of your junk food. Clear off your kitchen table. Cancel something tomorrow so you can make time to create something, no matter how small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t do all of these. Do one. Or half of one, or one thousandth. It doesn&amp;#8217;t matter how small &amp;#8212; the smaller, the better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take that first step. Celebrate that first step. Love the step, not the destination. That step, even the motion of taking the first foot off the ground and moving it forward &amp;#8212; that&amp;#8217;s everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s the truth, and you&amp;#8217;ll not read it in many self-help books: put every microparticle of your existence into that half step, and be nothing but that half step, and love it with all you have &amp;#8230; and your life has changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this half step, everything is different. You haven&amp;#8217;t achieved any goals &amp;#8230; but you&amp;#8217;ve moved. You haven&amp;#8217;t created something amazing &amp;#8230; and yet, more than ever before, you have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ve created beauty and joy and movement where none existed before, where previously only constriction and paralysis and confusion lived. You have changed the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The First Habit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose one little habit to add joy to your life. Just one, and tiny is miraculous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be writing or painting or making music for 2 minutes a day. It can be a ridiculously easy walk or jog or enjoying a bowl of fruit. It can be 2 minutes of meditation or reflecting in a journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy the hell out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create this one habit, and you have a success. This is a foundation, a first step, to build on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you can do a second, and a third, but you can&amp;#8217;t do those without a first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t change your entire life. Just change this one little thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;d be amazed how much that matters. I was.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/02/12/half/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/02/12/half/</guid>
        
        <category>self-improvement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The No. 1 Habit of Highly Creative People</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;In order to be open to creativity, one must have the capacity for contructive use of solitude. One must overcome the fear of being alone.&amp;#8221;&lt;strong&gt; ~&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rollo_May&quot;&gt;Rollo May&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creativity is a nebulous, murky topic that fascinates me endlessly &amp;#8212; how does it work? What habits to creative people do that makes them so successful at creativity?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve reflected on my own creative habits, but decided I&amp;#8217;d look at the habits that others consider important to their creativity. I picked a handful of creatives, almost at random &amp;#8212; there are so many that picking the best would be impossible, so I just picked some that I admire, who came to mind when I thought of the word &amp;#8220;creative&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was going to be a list of their creative habits &amp;#8230; but in reviewing their lists, and my own habits, I found one that stood out. And it stands out if you review the habits and quotes from great creative people in history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s the Most Important Habit when it comes to creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you read the No. 1 habit, please scroll down and read the No. 2 habit &amp;#8212; they might seem contradictory but in my experience, you can&amp;#8217;t really hit your creative stride until you find a way to balance both habits.&lt;span id=&quot;more-4649&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The No. 1 Creativity Habit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a word: solitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creativity flourishes in solitude. With quiet, you can hear your thoughts, you can reach deep within yourself, you can focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are lots of ways to find this solitude. Let&amp;#8217;s listen to a few of the creative people I talked to or researched:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/feliciaday.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feliciaday.com/blog&quot;&gt;Felicia Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8211; wonderful actress perhaps best known for her awesome awesome work on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.drhorrible.com/&quot;&gt;Dr. Horrible&amp;#8217;s Sing-along Blog&lt;/a&gt;, Buffy the Vampire Slayer, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.watchtheguild.com/&quot;&gt;The Guild&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was thrilled when she replied to my email asking about her creative habits. One of the things she said: she makes &amp;#8220;sure to be creative first thing in the morning, before doing anything for the outside world, really sets the day up for me. It makes it feel that CREATING is my job, not answering emails.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/aliedwards.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aliedwards.com/&quot;&gt;Ali Edwards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8211; an author, designer, and leading authority on scrapbooking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was honored with a response from Ali as well. One of her top habits wasn&amp;#8217;t exactly solitude, but is related: &amp;#8220;&lt;strong&gt;Do nothing&lt;/strong&gt;. I have a habit of welcoming time away from my creative work. For me this is serious life-recharging time where my only responsibility is to just be Mom &amp;amp; Wife &amp;amp; Me. Doing nothing has a way of synthesizing what is really important in my life and in my work and inspires me beyond measure. When I come back to work I am better equipped to weed out the non-essential stuff and focus on the things I most want to express creatively.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/chasejarvis.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.chasejarvis.com/blog/&quot;&gt;Chase Jarvis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8211; an award-winning photographer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chase also kindly responded with several of his key creativity habits &amp;#8212; see more great ones at the bottom of this post. But here&amp;#8217;s one that I loved: &amp;#8220;Find Quiet.  Creativity sometimes washes over me during times of intense focus and craziness of work, but more often I get whacked by the creative stick when I&amp;#8217;ve got time in my schedule.  And since my schedule is a crazy one and almost always fills up if I&amp;#8217;m just &amp;#8220;living&amp;#8221;, I tend to carve out little retreats for myself.  I get some good thinking and re-charge time during vacations, or on airplanes, but the retreats are more focused on thinking about creative problems that I&amp;#8217;m wanting to solve.  That&amp;#8217;s why I intentionally carve time out.  I make room for creativity.  Intentionally.  The best example of what I mean by a retreat is a weekend at my family&amp;#8217;s cabin.  It&amp;#8217;s a 90 minute drive from my house on the coast.  There are few distractions.  Just a rocky beach and a cabin from the 60&amp;#8217;s with wood paneling and shag carpet.  I go for walks, hikes, naps. I read.  I did get an internet signal put in there to stay connected if I need it.  But the gist is QUIET.  Let there be space for creativity to fill your brain.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/maciej.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.idlewords.com/&quot;&gt;Maciej Cegłowski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8211; painter, programmer, excellent writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maciej is one of my favorite bloggers, and responded to my email with a classically short answer that to me, embodies a beautiful way to find solitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What habit helps his creativity?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maciej replied: &amp;#8220;Running up hills!&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leo Babauta&lt;/strong&gt;: OK, I wasn&amp;#8217;t going to talk about myself in this post, but I thought I should share some of my previous thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best art is created in solitude, for good reason: it&amp;#8217;s only when we are alone that we can reach into ourselves and find truth, beauty, soul. Some of the most famous philosophers took daily walks, and it was on these walks that they found their deepest thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My best writing, and in fact the best of anything I&amp;#8217;ve done, was created in solitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a few of the benefits I&amp;#8217;ve found from solitude:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time for thought&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in being alone, we get to know ourselves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we face our demons, and deal with them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;space to create&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;space to unwind, and find peace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time to reflect on what we&amp;#8217;ve done, and learn from it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;isolation from the influences of other helps us to find our own voice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;quiet helps us to appreciate the smaller things that get lost in the roar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/solitude/&quot;&gt;the lost art of solitude&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Greats on Solitude&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, many other creative people have believed in the habit of solitude. I&amp;#8217;ve collected a small but influential sample here. There are many more examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/mozart.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wolfgang_Amadeus_Mozart&quot;&gt;Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; prolific and influential composer of the Classical era. He composed over 600 works, many acknowledged as pinnacles of symphonic, concertante, chamber, piano, operatic, and choral music. He is among the most enduringly popular of classical composers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mozart: &amp;#8220;When I am, as it were, completely myself, entirely alone, and of good cheer&amp;#8211;say, traveling in a carriage or walking after a good meal or during the night when I cannot sleep&amp;#8211;it is on such occasions that my ideas flow best and most abundantly.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/einstein.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein&quot;&gt;Albert Einstein&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211;  theoretical physicist, philosopher and author who is widely regarded as one of the most influential and best known scientists and intellectuals of all time. He is often regarded as the father of modern physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Einstein: &amp;#8220;On the other hand, although I have a regular work schedule, I take time to go for long walks on the beach so that I can listen to what is going on inside my head. If my work isn&amp;#8217;t going well, I lie down in the middle of a workday and gaze at the ceiling while I listen and visualize what goes on in my imagination.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/kafka.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Franz_Kafka&quot;&gt;Franz Kafka&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; one of the most influential writers of the 20th century. Novelist and writer of short stories whose works came to be regarded as one of the major achievements of 20th century literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kafka: &amp;#8220;You need not leave your room. Remain sitting at your table and listen. You need not even listen, simply wait, just learn to become quiet, and still, and solitary. The world will freely offer itself to you to be unmasked. It has no choice; it will roll in ecstasy at your feet.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/tesla.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nikola_Tesla&quot;&gt;Nikola Tesla&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; inventor, one of the most important contributors to the birth of commercial electricity, best known for his many revolutionary developments in the field of electromagnetism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesla: &amp;#8220;The mind is sharper and keener in seclusion and uninterrupted solitude. Originality thrives in seclusion free of outside influences beating upon us to cripple the creative mind. Be alone—that is the secret of invention: be alone, that is when ideas are born.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/haydn.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joseph_Haydn&quot;&gt;Joseph Haydn&lt;/a&gt;: A life-long resident of Austria, Haydn spent much of his career as a court musician for the wealthy Hungarian aristocratic Esterházy family on their remote estate. Isolated from other composers and trends in music until the later part of his long life, he was, as he put it, &amp;#8220;forced to become original&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/goethe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Johann_Wolfgang_von_Goethe&quot;&gt;Johann Wolfgang von Goethe&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; German writer and polymath. Goethe&amp;#8217;s works span the fields of poetry, drama, literature, theology, philosophy, and science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His magnum opus, lauded as one of the peaks of world literature, is the two-part drama Faust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goethe: &amp;#8220;One can be instructed in society, one is inspired only in solitude.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/picasso.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pablo_Picasso&quot;&gt;Pablo Picasso&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Spanish painter best known for co-founding the Cubist movement and for the wide variety of styles embodied in his work. His revolutionary artistic accomplishments brought him universal renown and immense fortunes throughout his life, making him one of the best-known figures in twentieth century art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picasso: &amp;#8220;Without great solitude no serious work is possible.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/sandburg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_Sandburg&quot;&gt;Carl Sandburg&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211;  American writer and editor, best known for his poetry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He won three Pulitzer Prizes, two for his poetry and another for a biography of Abraham Lincoln. H. L. Mencken called Carl Sandburg &amp;#8220;indubitably an American in every pulse-beat.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sandburg: &amp;#8220;One of the greatest necessities in America is to discover creative solitude.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/mann.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thomas_Mann&quot;&gt;Thomas Mann&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; German novelist, short story writer, social critic, philanthropist, essayist, and 1929 Nobel Prize laureate, known for his series of highly symbolic and ironic epic novels and novellas, noted for their insight into the psychology of the artist and the intellectual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mann: &amp;#8220;Solitude gives birth to the original in us, to beauty unfamiliar and perilous — to poetry.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The No. 2 Creative Habit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it might seem contradictory, the No. 2 habit when it comes to nurturing creativity: participation. This can come in many forms, but it requires connecting with others, being inspired by others, reading others, collaborating with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how can you have both solitude and participation? They obviously have to come at different times. Finding the balance is key, of course, but it takes a conscious effort: this time is for solitude, and this time is for participation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are they both important? We need inspiration from without, but we need creation from within.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of the people I interviewed had habits that relate to this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.chasejarvis.com/blog/&quot;&gt;Chase Jarvis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;#8220;&lt;strong&gt;Devour Popular Culture&lt;/strong&gt;. Consuming the works of others inspires me.  And it&amp;#8217;s not just museums and the &amp;#8220;establishment&amp;#8221;. I devour magazines, books, street art, performances, music, etc. All things that make me think critically (and whimsically) about the world. You get the picture. Inspiration can come from anywhere.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://awww.aliedwards.com/&quot;&gt;Ali Edwards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;#8220;&lt;strong&gt;Participate&lt;/strong&gt;. My creative spirit is interested in documenting the wonderful everyday details of our lives. To really get to the heart of the matter I need to be fully participating in my life, in the interactions with my kids and husband and family and friends. If I am just going through the motions or wishing away the present moment for &amp;#8220;the next thing&amp;#8221; I am missing the blessing of right now. My creativity requires the habit of active participation and daily attention to detail.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other Creative Habits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other habits than those top two, of course, that can nourish creativity. Some other good ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feliciaday.com/blog&quot;&gt;Felicia Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;#8220;When I am most productive I am the most ruthless with my schedule. I will literally make a daily checklist with, &amp;#8220;one hour gym&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;30 minutes of internet research,&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;drink 3 glasses of water&amp;#8221; on it. For some reason being that disciplined creates a sense of control that I wouldn&amp;#8217;t have otherwise, as a self-employed person, and I get the most out of the scheduled hours that I have for writing.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aliedwards.com/&quot;&gt;Ali Edwards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;#8220;Take notes. I am a really good note-taker. It&amp;#8217;s essential for me to write down my ideas when they come to mind&amp;#8230;otherwise, poof, they disappear way too quickly as I move on to the next task (diaper changes, wiping noses, tending to the stuff of life). I use my phone, my computer, and a moleskine notebook to jot down thoughts and ideas and then I move them into Things every week or so.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.chasejarvis.com/blog/&quot;&gt;Chase Jarvis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; had a few more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Live a creative life everyday&lt;/strong&gt;.  I very much believe in doing creative stuff everyday. For one, I take photos and videos almost everyday.  Doesn&amp;#8217;t matter the camera.  I use my iPhone everyday. Just taking photos keeps me in a creative headspace.  Hell, I play with my food and draw and doodle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moderate Expectations&lt;/strong&gt;. Make it a habit not to judge yourself on your creative output.  Sometimes your creativity is on fire.  Great news.  Other times, it&amp;#8217;s not.  It&amp;#8217;s hard sometimes when you make art in a professional commercial capacity because you&amp;#8217;re paid to be &amp;#8216;ON&amp;#8217;, but you&amp;#8217;ll save yourself a lot of greif if you make it a habit to be cool to your psyche when your creative mojo isn&amp;#8217;t firing on all pistons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shake Your Tree&lt;/strong&gt;.  When I&amp;#8217;m starting to feel stale, I make a habit of getting into adventures.  Break molds. Drive home from work a different way. Stir up my routine.  I get active and &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.chasejarvis.com/blog/2009/05/shake-your-tree-today.html&quot;&gt;shake my tree&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find fun&lt;/strong&gt;.  Doing what you love inspires you to be more creative.  Make time and space for having fun.  All work and no play makes Jane a dull girl.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lastly, being creative means &lt;strong&gt;living a creative life&lt;/strong&gt;.  Expect yourself to have one.  Believe you are creative. Know that you are. Make that the most important habit of all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more on creativity, read my &lt;a href=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/the-little-but-really-useful-guide-to-creativity/&quot;&gt;Little But Useful Guide to Creativity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Creativity is essentially a lonely art. An even lonelier struggle. To some a blessing. To others a curse. It is in reality the ability to reach inside yourself and drag forth from your very soul an idea.&amp;#8221; &lt;strong&gt;~Lou Dorfsman &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/01/20/number-one-habit/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/01/20/number-one-habit/</guid>
        
        <category>self-improvement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Short but Powerful Guide to Finding Your Passion</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;The supreme accomplishment is to blur the line between work and play.&amp;#8221; &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8211; Arnold Toynbee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following your passion can be a tough thing. But figuring out what that passion is can be even more elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m lucky &amp;#8212; I&amp;#8217;ve found my passion, and I&amp;#8217;m living it. I can testify that it&amp;#8217;s the most wonderful thing, to be able to make a living doing what you love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, in this little guide, I&amp;#8217;d like to help you get started figuring out what you&amp;#8217;d love doing. This turns out to be one of the most common problems of many True Happiness readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be the thing that will get you motivated to get out of bed in the morning, to cry out, &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m alive! I&amp;#8217;m feeling this, baby!&amp;#8221;. And to scare your family members or anyone who happens to be in yelling distance as you do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide won&amp;#8217;t be comprehensive, and it won&amp;#8217;t find your passion for you. But it will help you in your journey to find it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. What are you good at?&lt;/strong&gt; Unless you&amp;#8217;re just starting out in life, you have some skills or talent, shown some kind of aptitude. Even if you are just starting out, you might have shown some talent when you were young, even as young as elementary school. Have you always been a good writer, speaker, drawer, organizer, builder, teacher, friend? Have you been good at ideas, connecting people, gardening, selling? Give this some thought. Take at least 30 minutes, going over this question &amp;#8212; often we forget about things we&amp;#8217;ve done well. Think back, as far as you can, to jobs, projects, hobbies. This could be your passion. Or you may have several things. Start a list of potential candidates.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;more-4993&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2. What excites you?&lt;/strong&gt; It may be something at work &amp;#8212; a little part of your job that gets you excited. It could be something you do outside of work &amp;#8212; a hobby, a side job, something you do as a volunteer or a parent or a spouse or a friend. It could be something you haven&amp;#8217;t done in awhile. Again, think about this for 30 minutes, or 15 at the least. If you don&amp;#8217;t, you&amp;#8217;re probably shortchanging yourself. Add any answers to your list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. What do you read about?&lt;/strong&gt; What have you spent hours reading about online? What magazines do you look forward to reading? What blogs do you follow? What section of the bookstore do you usually peruse? There may be many topics here &amp;#8212; add them to the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. What have you secretly dreamed of?&lt;/strong&gt; You might have some ridiculous dream job you&amp;#8217;ve always wanted to do &amp;#8212; to be a novelist, an artist, a designer, an architect, a doctor, an entrepreneur, a programmer. But some fear, some self-doubt, has held you back, has led you to dismiss this idea. Maybe there are several. Add them to the list &amp;#8212; no matter how unrealistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Learn, ask, take notes&lt;/strong&gt;. OK, you have a list. Pick one thing from the list that excites you most. This is your first candidate. Now read up on it, talk to people who&amp;#8217;ve been successful in the field (through their blogs, if they have them, or email). Make a list of notes of things you need to learn, need to improve on, skills you want to master, people to talk to. Study up on it, but don&amp;#8217;t make yourself wait too long before diving into the next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Experiment, try&lt;/strong&gt;. Here&amp;#8217;s where the learning really takes place. If you haven&amp;#8217;t been already, start to do the thing you&amp;#8217;ve chosen. Maybe you already are, in which case you might be able to skip to the next step or choose a second candidate to try out. But if you haven&amp;#8217;t been, start now &amp;#8212; just do it. It can be in the privacy of your own home, but as quickly as possible, make it public however you can. This motivates you to improve, it gets you feedback, and your reputation will improve as you do. Pay attention to how you feel doing it &amp;#8212; is it something you look forward to, that gets you excited, that you love to share?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Narrow things down&lt;/strong&gt;. I recommend that you pick 3-5 things from your list, if it&amp;#8217;s longer than that, and do steps 5 &amp;amp; 6 with them. This could take month, or perhaps you&amp;#8217;ve already learned about and tried them all out. So now here&amp;#8217;s what you need to ask yourself: which gets you the most excited? Which of these can produce something that people will pay for or get excited about? Which can you see yourself doing for years (even if it&amp;#8217;s not a traditional career path)? Pick one, or two at the most, and focus on that. You&amp;#8217;re going to do the next three steps with it: banish your fears, find the time, and make it into a career if possible. If it doesn&amp;#8217;t work out, you can try the next thing on your list &amp;#8212; there&amp;#8217;s no shame in giving something a shot and failing, because it&amp;#8217;ll teach you valuable lessons that will help you to be successful in the next attempt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Banish your fears&lt;/strong&gt;. This is the biggest obstacle for most people &amp;#8211; self-doubt and fear of failure. You&amp;#8217;re going to face it and banish it. First, acknowledge it rather than ignoring or denying it. Second, write it down, to externalize it. Third, feel it, and be OK with having it. Fourth, ask yourself, &amp;#8220;What&amp;#8217;s the worst that can happen?&amp;#8221; Usually it&amp;#8217;s not catastrophic. Fifth, prepare yourself for doing it anyway, and then do it. Take small steps, as tiny as possible, and forget about what might happen &amp;#8212; focus on what actually is happening, right now. And then celebrate your success, no matter how small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Find the time&lt;/strong&gt;. Don&amp;#8217;t have the time to pursue this passion? Make the time, dammit! If this is a priority, you&amp;#8217;ll make the time &amp;#8212; rearrange your life until you have the time. This might mean waking earlier, or doing it after work or during lunch, or on weekends. It will probably mean canceling some commitments, simplifying your work routing or doing a lot of work in advance (like you&amp;#8217;re going on a vacation). Do what it takes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. How to make a living doing it&lt;/strong&gt;. This doesn&amp;#8217;t happen overnight. You need to do something, get good at it, be passionate about it. This could take months or years, but if you&amp;#8217;re having fun, that&amp;#8217;s what&amp;#8217;s most important. When you get to the point where someone would pay you for it, then you&amp;#8217;re golden &amp;#8212; there are many ways to make a living at that point, including doing freelance or consulting work, making information products such as ebooks, writing a blog and selling advertising. In fact, I recommend you do a blog if you&amp;#8217;re not already &amp;#8212; it&amp;#8217;ll help solidify your thinking, build a reputation, find people who are interested in what you do, demonstrate your knowledge and passion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I told you this wouldn&amp;#8217;t be easy. It&amp;#8217;ll require a lot of reflection and soul-searching, at first, then a lot of courage and learning and experimentation, and finally a lot of commitment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;#8217;s all worth it &amp;#8212; every second, every ounce of courage and effort. Because in the end, you&amp;#8217;ll have something that will transform your life in so many ways, will give you that reason to jump out of bed, will make you happy no matter how much you make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you follow this guide and find success, because I wish on you nothing less than finding your true passion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Choose a job you love, and you will never have to work a day in your life.&amp;#8221; &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8211; Confucius&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2014/12/15/the-short-but-powerful-guide-to-finding-your-passion/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2014/12/15/the-short-but-powerful-guide-to-finding-your-passion/</guid>
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why I don’t care about success</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8216;Try not to become a man of success, but rather try to become a man of value.&amp;#8217; &lt;strong&gt;~Albert Einstein&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people in my field write about how to be successful, but I try to avoid it. It&amp;#8217;s just not something I believe is important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, that might seem weird: what kind of loser doesn&amp;#8217;t want to be successful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me. I&amp;#8217;m that loser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, the first problem with success is how you define success &amp;#8230; is it becoming famous, rich, creating a world-changing business, coming up with an idea that changes people&amp;#8217;s lives, helping others, being happy? So many people with values similar to mine would reject the traditional definitions of success: being rich or famous or having a best-selling book or creating a huge business is not all there is to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And those people are right, in my book. If all you&amp;#8217;re striving for is money, you&amp;#8217;ll do horrible things to get it. If all you want is a successful business, you&amp;#8217;ll screw people over to get it. If all you want is fame, you&amp;#8217;ll give up your dignity to achieve it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could probably get a book on the New York Times best-seller list if I really tried, but it&amp;#8217;s not something I care enough about, and I know I&amp;#8217;d have to do things I wouldn&amp;#8217;t be happy doing in order to get there. I&amp;#8217;d have to make promises I couldn&amp;#8217;t deliver on, sell something to people who are looking for answers I don&amp;#8217;t have, trick them into buying the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could make a lot more money than I make now, if I capitalized on all the readers I have and pressured them into buying more things. But I don&amp;#8217;t think buying a lot of things is a good thing, so I&amp;#8217;d feel crappy doing that. It&amp;#8217;s not worth it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;more-7023&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Snake oil&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So those who teach you to be successful &amp;#8230; they&amp;#8217;ll share methods that are a bit shady sometimes. If not, often they sell you platitudes that sound good but are too vague to really mean anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve read many, many things on how to be successful (I can&amp;#8217;t avoid finding them &amp;#8212; they&amp;#8217;re everywhere), and rarely will any of them really show you how to get where you want to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when you don&amp;#8217;t get there, you blame not the success system, but your own inadequacies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The deeper problem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other problems, though. Whatever your definition of success, it&amp;#8217;s something you&amp;#8217;re looking for &amp;#8230; something that exists in the future. It&amp;#8217;s based on your desire to achieve something, your feelings that you&amp;#8217;re not where you want to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s why the snake oil salesmen are so &amp;#8220;successful&amp;#8221; &amp;#8230; they capitalize on the feelings of inadequacies that other people have. I think that&amp;#8217;s horrible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But beyond that, the trap of striving for this future &amp;#8220;success&amp;#8221; &amp;#8230; it&amp;#8217;s never-ending. You strive for more, and then when you get it, you strive for more again. You&amp;#8217;re never satisfied. People who have a billion dollars, for example &amp;#8230; they&amp;#8217;re successful, right? Why don&amp;#8217;t they stop trying to make money, then? Why would they possibly need more than a billion dollars? How can you possibly spend that much? They strive to make more because there will never be enough. They&amp;#8217;ll never be successful enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s true not just of the rich, but of anyone who strives for success. Striving is a condition that doesn&amp;#8217;t have an end, unless you give it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The real success&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might have a lot of readers now on True Happiness, but I don&amp;#8217;t feel that&amp;#8217;s what makes me a success. I&amp;#8217;ve been a success since Day 1, because even when I had zero readers, I was doing what I loved. Even when no one else would have called me a success (I really was a nobody then), I absolutely loved writing my posts, and though I don&amp;#8217;t agree now with a lot of what I wrote back then (in 2007), I was happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Success isn&amp;#8217;t about achieving something in the future, but about doing something right now that you love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So doesn&amp;#8217;t that mean I care about success? Well, sure, if you define success as whatever it is you care about, then of course you&amp;#8217;re going to care about success. But then &amp;#8220;success&amp;#8221; really doesn&amp;#8217;t have a meaning, does it? If it can mean anything, then it means nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So forget about &amp;#8220;success&amp;#8221;, and just find joy, passion, love, awesome-ness right now, in this moment. *That* is a success you can achieve, without any self-help course, without any method. Just go out and do it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2014/10/22/why-i-dont-care-about-success/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2014/10/22/why-i-dont-care-about-success/</guid>
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Live Well</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not a rich man, nor do I fly around the world and drink champagne with famous people in exotic locales, nor do I own a sports car or SUV or a yacht.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, I&amp;#8217;m very happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much happier than seven years ago when I ate fried foods and sweets all time time and felt unhealthy and overweight, when I watched television and was out of shape, when I shopped a lot and was in debt, when I worked a job that paid fairly well and had no time for myself or my loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How have I accomplished this? With small tricks. The truth is, you don&amp;#8217;t need a lot to live well &amp;#8212; you just need the right mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s what I&amp;#8217;ve learned about living well on little:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You need very little to be happy&lt;/strong&gt;. Some simple plant food, modest shelter, a couple changes of clothes, a good book, a notebook, some meaningful work, and some loved ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want little, and you are not poor&lt;/strong&gt;. You can have a lot of money and possessions, but if you always want more, you are poorer than the guy who has little and wants nothing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on the present&lt;/strong&gt;. Stop worrying about the future and holding onto the past. How much of your day is spent thinking about things other than where you are and what you&amp;#8217;re doing, physically, at this moment? How often are we living as opposed to stuck thinking about other things? Live now and you live fully.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be happy with what you have and where you are&lt;/strong&gt;. Too often we want to be somewhere else, doing something else, with other people than whoever we&amp;#8217;re with right now, getting things other than what we already have. But where we are is great! Who we&amp;#8217;re with (including just ourselves) is already perfect. What we have is enough. What we&amp;#8217;re doing already is amazing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be grateful for the small pleasures in life&lt;/strong&gt;. Berries, a square of dark chocolate, tea &amp;#8212; simple pleasures that are so much better than rich desserts, sugary drinks, fried foods if you learn to enjoy them fully. A good book borrowed from the library, a walk with a loved one in the park, the fine exertion of a short hard workout, the crazy things your child says, the smile of a stranger, walking barefoot on grass, a moment of quiet as the morning wakens and the world still rests. These little pleasures are living well, without needing much.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be driven by joy and not fear&lt;/strong&gt;. People are driven by the fear of missing out, or the fear of change, or the fear of losing something. These are not good reasons to do things. Instead, do things because they give you or others joy. Let your work be driven not because you need to support a lifestyle and are afraid of changing it, but by the joy of doing something creative, meaningful, valuable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practice compassion&lt;/strong&gt;. Compassion for others creates loving, rewarding relationships. Compassion for yourself means forgiving yourself for past mistakes, treating yourself well (including eating well and exercising), loving yourself as you are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forget about productivity and numbers&lt;/strong&gt;. They matter not at all. If you are driven to do things to reach certain numbers (goals), you have probably lost sight of what&amp;#8217;s important. If you are striving to be productive, you are filling your days with things just to be productive, which is a waste of a day. This day is a gift, and shouldn&amp;#8217;t be crammed with every possible thing &amp;#8212; spend time enjoying it and what you&amp;#8217;re doing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2014/09/24/how-to-live-well/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2014/09/24/how-to-live-well/</guid>
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>self-improvement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Master the Art of Living</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine you had a gorgeous blueberry sitting on the otherwise empty plate in front of you. You pick it up gently, place it on your tongue, and begin to taste it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You already know how a blueberry tastes, and so when this one is a bit riper than you&amp;#8217;d like, you make a face, feel the disappointment, swallow it with displeasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps it tastes exactly as you&amp;#8217;d expected: no big deal. You swallow, and move on with your day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first case, the blueberry was disappointing because it didn&amp;#8217;t meet expectations. In the second, it was boring because it met expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now try this: have no expectations of how the blueberry will taste. You don&amp;#8217;t know because you haven&amp;#8217;t tried it yet. You&amp;#8217;re curious, open to a variety of tastes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You taste it, and really pay attention. You notice the tanginess, the firmness of the skin, the sweet mushiness of the center, the complex flavors that emerge as you eat it. You didn&amp;#8217;t know how it would taste, but this is brilliant! It&amp;#8217;s new, because you&amp;#8217;ve never tasted anything quite like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is sometimes called the Beginner&amp;#8217;s Mind, but I think of it as a mind free of expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blueberry, of course, can be anything in life: any experience, any person you meet, any cup of tea, any task before you, any interaction with a loved one, any thought that enters your head, any moment of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you approach any of these with expectations, they will often disappoint or frustrate you &amp;#8230; or be bland, blah, &lt;em&gt;usual&lt;/em&gt;. And you move on to the next disappointing or frustration or usual experience, and so on, so that life is nothing but a series of things you barely like and barely notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you approach each moment, each task, each person, without expectations &amp;#8230; and just see that moment or person &lt;em&gt;as they are&lt;/em&gt; &amp;#8230; then you will really see that moment. Really appreciate it. Experience it like you&amp;#8217;ve never experienced anything before, because you haven&amp;#8217;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the Art of Living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Worlds That Open Up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you learn to approach each person and moment and task without expectations, it transforms everything. New worlds open up to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A handful of examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Procrastination&lt;/strong&gt;: Let&amp;#8217;s say you have been putting off a big task at work because you&amp;#8217;re dreading doing it. Maybe it&amp;#8217;s a big project, and you have this feeling of overwhelm. It&amp;#8217;s a lot of work! You are &lt;em&gt;expecting&lt;/em&gt; to have to do hard work you&amp;#8217;re perhaps not good at, expecting failure or difficulty. But letting go of the expectations means you don&amp;#8217;t know how this task will go &amp;#8230; you go into it with an open mind. You try it and see how it goes. You learn from the experience no matter how it goes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habits&lt;/strong&gt;: You enter a new habit with the expectation that it will be amazing, change your life, and you&amp;#8217;ll do great. And when it is inevitably harder than you thought it would be, and you&amp;#8217;re less successful at it, you&amp;#8217;re disappointed, discouraged, frustrated. So you lose motivation, and give up. If instead, you let go of the fantasy of how this habit will go, and just be open to what emerges &amp;#8230; you can just do the habit. Just be in the moment with it. Then, no matter how it turns out, you&amp;#8217;ll learn something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frustrating person&lt;/strong&gt;: This guy at work is frustrating you because he&amp;#8217;s not doing the work the way he should, or maybe he&amp;#8217;s being inconsiderate somehow. Your frustration stems from an &lt;em&gt;expectation&lt;/em&gt; of how this person should act. They don&amp;#8217;t act according to this ideal, and so you suffer. Instead, you can put aside this expectation that people will live up to your ideals &amp;#8230; and just be open to them. They will behave imperfectly, just as you will. Accepting the person as they are doesn&amp;#8217;t mean you do nothing &amp;#8230; you can let go of the frustration, and see how they&amp;#8217;re having difficulty, and it as a teaching opportunity or an opportunity to help them &amp;#8230; with no expectation that they&amp;#8217;ll love your lesson or follow it, but just with the intention of helping someone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kids don&amp;#8217;t behave&lt;/strong&gt;: When your kids behave badly, it&amp;#8217;s the same problem &amp;#8212; they aren&amp;#8217;t acting according to your ideal. But of course they&amp;#8217;re not! No kid behaves ideally, just as no adult behaves ideally. Do you behave ideally? I certainly don&amp;#8217;t. I&amp;#8217;m rude when I&amp;#8217;m in a bad mood or tired. I&amp;#8217;m not proud of that, but I struggle to be considerate or cheerful sometimes. Everyone does. Your kids are struggling, and you can be compassionate and help them. Kindly. That is, if you can let go of your expectations that they&amp;#8217;ll behave perfectly, and accept them as struggling, beautiful people who just want to be happy, just like you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your body&lt;/strong&gt;: You aren&amp;#8217;t happy with your body, because it&amp;#8217;s not perfect. It doesn&amp;#8217;t meet your ideal, your expectation, and so you dislike it. That&amp;#8217;s not good, because this self-discontent means that you&amp;#8217;re less likely to do healthy things. Often we think that dissatisfaction with ourselves motivates us to change, but in my experience this discontent means that you don&amp;#8217;t really trust yourself to stick to changes and so you make excuses when things get hard, and quit. I&amp;#8217;ve done that a lot. When I am content with myself, I trust myself more, and I stick to things more. So let go of expectations that your body will be perfect, and just see your body as it is, for the beautiful thing it is, independent of society&amp;#8217;s ideals of perfection. You&amp;#8217;re great!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Each moment&lt;/strong&gt;: As we enter each new moment, we expect things from it. We want it to be fun, amazing, productive, according to plan. And of course each moment has its own plan, and will be its own thing. So we are not happy with it. Instead, we can drop the expectations and just see the moment as it is. Just experience it, noticing, appreciating, being grateful. This is mastery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just the start. We can learn that plans, goals, ideals &amp;#8230; these are all fantasies of what we&amp;#8217;d like life to be like, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fantasies/&quot;&gt;they&amp;#8217;re not real&lt;/a&gt;. We can learn to let go of the fantasies that inevitably occur, and just experience life as it is, as it happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the Art of Living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How to Master the Art&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mastering the Art of Living is not as easy as you&amp;#8217;d expect, as you&amp;#8217;d fantasize. It takes practice. It means learning to be mindful of when you have these ideals, expectations, fantasies. It means learning to see the frustrations, anger, sadness, loneliness, irritations as signals of the expectations you have and didn&amp;#8217;t notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It means practicing that, and then practicing letting them go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means a lot of practice, and a lot of remembering to practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that&amp;#8217;s the fun of it. You drop the expectation that you&amp;#8217;ll be perfect at this practice, and just try it. You learn from the trying. You get better. You learn some more. And each moment, along the way, is a miracle to be appreciated and enjoyed, so the process of mastery is a succession of miracle moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s a beautiful thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2014/07/08/how-to-master-the-art-of-living/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2014/07/08/how-to-master-the-art-of-living/</guid>
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>20 Things I Wish I Had Known When Starting Out in Life</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Everything has been figured out, except how to live.&amp;#8221; &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8211; Jean-Paul Sartre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m nearly 25 years old, and I&amp;#8217;ve made my share of mistakes in my life. I&amp;#8217;m not a big believer in regrets &amp;#8230; and I have learned tremendously from every single mistake &amp;#8230; and my life is pretty great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there are a few things I wish I had known when I was graduating from high school and starting out as an adult in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would I change things? I&amp;#8217;m not so sure. I might never have gotten into a mountain of debt, but then I wouldn&amp;#8217;t have learned the amazing satisfaction of getting out of it. I might have made better career choices, but then I wouldn&amp;#8217;t have all the work experience that makes me the blogger and writer that I am today.&lt;span id=&quot;more-651&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might not have gotten married that first time, so that I would never have gotten divorced &amp;#8230; but then I wouldn&amp;#8217;t have my first two beautiful wonderful incredible children from that first marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t think I would change any of that. However, looking back, there are some lessons I&amp;#8217;ve learned that I would probably tell my 18-year-old self. Do I share them now to share my regrets? No, I share them in hopes that younger men and women, just starting out in life, can benefit from my mistakes and my lessons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What follows isn&amp;#8217;t an exhaustive list, but it&amp;#8217;s one that I hope proves useful to at least a few people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;I hope life isn&amp;#8217;t a big joke, because I don&amp;#8217;t get it.&amp;#8221; &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8211; Jack Handey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to control impulse spending.&lt;/strong&gt; If there&amp;#8217;s anything that got me in trouble financially, it&amp;#8217;s impulse spending. Buying clothes when I don&amp;#8217;t need them. Buying gadgets because I gotta have them. Ordering stuff online because it&amp;#8217;s so easy. Buying that new shiny SUV because &amp;#8230; well, because it was going to help me with women. I&amp;#8217;m not proud of any of that. I&amp;#8217;ve learned to control my impulses, at least a little better. Now, I give myself some time to breathe. I think over my purchases, see if I&amp;#8217;ve got the money, think about whether it&amp;#8217;s a need or a want. That would have been a useful tool 15 years ago.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You gotta stay active. &lt;/strong&gt;I was in track, cross country and basketball in high school, but once I started college, the running and basketball began to slowly fade away. Not right away &amp;#8212; I played pick-up basketball for years after high school. But even that went away, until I became sedentary. Playing with my kids outdoors winded me. And I began to get fat. I&amp;#8217;ve reversed that trend, and am very active now, but I&amp;#8217;m still trying to burn the fat I gained in those inactive years.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to plan finances. &lt;/strong&gt;I always knew that I was supposed to budget and track my spending, when I became an adult. I just was too lazy to do it. And I didn&amp;#8217;t have a good idea of how to actually do it. Now, I&amp;#8217;ve learned how to plan, and how to stick to that plan. Sure, I deviate from my plan, but I&amp;#8217;ve learned how to handle that too. Maybe that&amp;#8217;s not a skill you can learn from book reading. You just gotta practice. Well, I hope to teach it to my children before they go out on their own.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Junk food will come back to bite you in the butt. &lt;/strong&gt;Yeah, it wasn&amp;#8217;t just the sedentary lifestyle that got me fat. It was all the damn junk food too. I would eat pizza and burgers and Twinkies and sugar cereal and desserts and donuts and &amp;#8230; well, you get the picture. As someone used to being able to eat whatever I wanted, it never seemed like it would be a problem. Bad health was something to worry about when you got old. Well, my jeans began to get way too tight, and to my horror, I climbed several pants sizes and developed a gut that only now is going away. I wish someone had shown me an &amp;#8220;after&amp;#8221; picture when I was young and downing the Big Gulp sodas.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smoking is just dumb.&lt;/strong&gt; I didn&amp;#8217;t start smoking until I was well into my adult years. I won&amp;#8217;t go into why I started, but it didn&amp;#8217;t seem like a problem, because I knew I could quit anytime I wanted. Or I thought I could, at least, until several years later I gave it a go and couldn&amp;#8217;t do it. Five failed quits later and I realized with horror that my addiction was stronger than I was. Sure, I eventually beat the habit (quit date: Nov. 18, 2005) but it took a piece of my soul to do it.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fund your retirement, son.  And don&amp;#8217;t withdraw it. &lt;/strong&gt;This piece of wisdom, and probably all the ones above, might seem blisteringly obvious. And they are. Don&amp;#8217;t think I didn&amp;#8217;t know this when I was 18. I did. I just didn&amp;#8217;t pay it serious attention. Retirement was something I could worry about when I was in my 30s. Well, I&amp;#8217;m in my 30s now and I wish I could slap that little 18-year-old Leo around a bit. What money I could have invested by now!  I had a retirement plan, but on the 3 occasions when I changed jobs, I withdrew that and spent it frivolously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All the stuff you&amp;#8217;re doing that seems hard &amp;#8212; it will be of use. &lt;/strong&gt;This is the first one that might not be as obvious. There were times in my life when work was hard, and I did it anyway, but hated it. I did it because I had to, but boy did it stress me out and leave me exhausted. Hard work isn&amp;#8217;t as easy as I wanted it to be. But you know what? Every bit of hard work I did without knowing why I was doing it &amp;#8230; it&amp;#8217;s paid off for me in the long run. Maybe not right away, but I&amp;#8217;m using skills and habits I learned during those times of high stress and long hours and tedious work &amp;#8212; I use them all the time, and they&amp;#8217;ve made me into the person I am today. Thank you, younger Leo!&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t buy that used van without checking it out closely. &lt;/strong&gt;I thought I was being smart by buying used, but I didn&amp;#8217;t check it out carefully enough. That dang van had loads of engine problems, a door that nearly fell off when I was driving, a door handle that snapped off, a side mirror that fell off, no spare tire despite three tires that were ready to blow (and did), windows that didn&amp;#8217;t roll up, rattling noises, an eventual blown radiator &amp;#8230; I could go on and on, but let&amp;#8217;s just say that it wasn&amp;#8217;t my best purchase. I still think buying used is smart, but check things out closely first.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That guy you&amp;#8217;re going to sell your car to? On a gentleman&amp;#8217;s agreement? He&amp;#8217;s not gonna pay you.&lt;/strong&gt; I sold another car to a friend of a friend, who I was sure would pay me even if I had nothing in writing. That was smart. I still see the guy once in awhile on the road, but I don&amp;#8217;t have the energy to do a U-turn and chase after him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make time to pursue your passion, no matter how busy you are.&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;#8217;ve always wanted to be a writer, and get a book published. I just never had time to write. With a family and school and a full-time job, there just weren&amp;#8217;t enough hours in the day. Well, I&amp;#8217;ve learned that you have to make those hours. Set aside a block of time to do what you love, cut out other stuff from your life that take up your time, and don&amp;#8217;t let anything interfere with that work. If I had done that 15 years ago, I could have 15 books written by now. Not all would be great, but still.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All that stuff that&amp;#8217;s stressing you out &amp;#8212; it won&amp;#8217;t matter in 5 years, let alone 15. &lt;/strong&gt;When things are happening to you right now, they mean all the world. I had deadlines and projects and people breathing down my neck, and my stress levels went through the roof. I don&amp;#8217;t regret the hard work (see above) but I think I would have been less stressed if I could have just realized that it wouldn&amp;#8217;t matter a single bit just a few years down the road. Perspective is a good thing to learn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The people you make friends with are so much more important than your job or the things you buy. &lt;/strong&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve had a few jobs, I&amp;#8217;ve bought a lot of things, and I&amp;#8217;ve made a few friends over these last 15 years. Of those, the only thing that still matter to me are the friends. And I wish I could have spent more time with friends (and family) than on the other things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All that time you spend watching TV is a huge, huge waste of time. &lt;/strong&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t know how much TV I&amp;#8217;ve watched over the years, but it&amp;#8217;s a crapload. Hours and days and weeks I&amp;#8217;ll never have back. Who cares what happens on reality TV, when reality is slipping by outside? Time is something you&amp;#8217;ll never get back &amp;#8212; don&amp;#8217;t waste it on TV.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your kids are going to grow up way faster than you think. Don&amp;#8217;t waste a minute&lt;/strong&gt;. I just had an Oh My God moment recently. My oldest daughter, Chloe, is 14 going on 15 next month. I have 3 years left with her before she leaves my house and becomes an adult. Three years! I am floored by that single fact, because it really doesn&amp;#8217;t seem anywhere near enough time. I want to go back to my younger self and whack that younger Leo on the head and say Stop working so hard! Stop watching TV! Spend more time with your kids! These last 15 years with Chloe (and my other wonderful kids) have gone by much, much too fast.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forget the drama. Focus on being happy&lt;/strong&gt;. There have been many things that have happened to me, professionally and personally, that seem like the end of the world. And while these things were bad, they get blown up in our heads so that they become major drama. They caused me to be depressed from time to time. What a waste of time. If I realized that it was all in my head, and that I could be happy instead if I focused on the positive, on what I did have, and what I could be doing &amp;#8230; I could have skipped all the moping about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--ad--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pay more attention to blogs when you first hear about them. They&amp;#8217;re more than just journals&lt;/strong&gt;. I first read about blogs 7-8 years ago, but when I took a look at them they didn&amp;#8217;t seem like anything of interest. Just some people&amp;#8217;s journals about stuff they read on the web. Why would I want to read those? I have my own thoughts about the web, but I don&amp;#8217;t need to share them with the world. I spent a lot of time on the Internet, on various sites and forums, but every time I happened upon a blog I would brush past it without interest. It wasn&amp;#8217;t until a couple years ago that I discovered what wonderful things they could be (I mentioned some of my early favorites in &lt;a href=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/2008/02/the-10-biggest-influences-on-zen-habits/&quot;&gt;my list of influences&lt;/a&gt;). If I had gotten into blogging years ago &amp;#8230; well, I wouldn&amp;#8217;t have been wasting all that time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaking of which, keep a journal. Seriously. Your memory is extremely faulty&lt;/strong&gt;. I forget things really easily. Not short-term stuff, but long-term. I don&amp;#8217;t remember things about my kids&amp;#8217; early years, because I didn&amp;#8217;t record any of it. I don&amp;#8217;t remember things about my life. It&amp;#8217;s like a lot of foggy memories that I&amp;#8217;ll never have access to. I wish I had kept a journal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tequila is seriously evil&lt;/strong&gt;. I won&amp;#8217;t go into details, but it should suffice to say that I had some bad experiences, and I&amp;#8217;m not sure I learned very much from them or benefited in any way except to learn that tequila is the drink of the Devil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes, you can do a marathon. Don&amp;#8217;t put this goal off &amp;#8212; it&amp;#8217;s extremely rewarding&lt;/strong&gt;. Running a marathon had always been a dream of mine, since high school &amp;#8230; something I wanted to do but thought was out of reach. Or if I ever did it, it would be years and years later. Well, I learned that it&amp;#8217;s not only achievable, it&amp;#8217;s incredibly rewarding. I wish I had started training when I was young and light and fit &amp;#8230; I could have had some good finishing times!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All these mistakes you&amp;#8217;re going to make, despite this advice? They&amp;#8217;re worth it&lt;/strong&gt;. My 18-year-old self would probably have read this post and said, &amp;#8220;Good advice!&amp;#8221; And then he would have proceeded to make the same mistakes, despite good intentions. I was a good kid, but I wasn&amp;#8217;t good at following advice. I had to make my own mistakes, and live my own life. And that&amp;#8217;s what I did, and I don&amp;#8217;t regret a minute of it. Every experience I&amp;#8217;ve had (even the tequila ones) have led me down the path of life to where I am today. I love where I am today, and wouldn&amp;#8217;t trade it for another life for all the world. The pain, the stress, the drama, the hard work, the mistakes, the depression, the hangovers, the debt, the fat &amp;#8230; it was all worth it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Let us so live that when we come to die even the undertaker will be sorry.&amp;#8221; &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8211; Mark Twain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2014/05/30/things-i-wish-i-had-known-when-starting-out-in-life/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2014/05/30/things-i-wish-i-had-known-when-starting-out-in-life/</guid>
        
        <category></category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
