<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" 
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
    >
  <channel>
    <title>True Happiness</title>
    <description>Learn the science and practice of how to truly be happy.</description>
    <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://true-happiness.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 09:47:20 +0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 09:47:20 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Experience as a Buddhist Monk</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The best time I ever have in my life was when I was a Theravada Buddhist monk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day starts off at 4:00 AM. At this ungodly hour, I woke up every day to chant for hours the Pali Cannon, a holy Buddhist text, in an ancient language I do not understand. Afterward, it is time for alms. I walked into the village with two thoughts in mind: the uncertainty of having enough food to eat and the certainty of having to withstand the pain of walking barefooted into the streets full of sharp pebbles, and sometimes even glass shards. Once I am back at the monastery, whatever I get, I must eat. In the alms bowl, it is not uncommon to have your curry mixed with your dessert, and your soup with chocolate. What was once seem “delicious” quickly dissipated. Worse, this “food” is the only meal I eat per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was living in a tiny wooden hut built ten years before I was born. The toilet was, to say the least, dirty. Occasionally, snakes, vipers, scorpions, spiders, and centipedes would show up uninvited in my room. As part of the training, I couldn’t even kill even a bug although there were bugs everywhere. Thus, I would have to live in the constant fear and annoyance of these guests. I could not listen to music. I could not dance. I couldn’t even run. I had no money of my own. The only thing I got going for me was an alms bowl and a pair of monk robes. That’s all. It would not be far fetch to describe such experience as “putting yourself in prison.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What good then would this kind of experience ever bring to a man? Why not just go to a beach and enjoy the sun? Or stay at a five stars hotel? How is it possible that I would even consider it as the best time I ever have in my life? Let’s me explain how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do we normally do when a mosquito bites us? We swat it, right? What do we do when there are bugs and animals visiting your home? Well, you build a better home, one which could wall ourselves against unwanted bugs and animals. What do we do when we dislike a job? We quit and get a better one—one which suits us better. The point here is that we, humans, often solve our problems in life by changing the reality to fits our wants. But what I learn by being a monk where my environment was, more or less, static is that it forces me to learn more than just trying to change what is outside but, more importantly, what is inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waking up at 4:00 AM everyday wasn’t easy; but at the same time, it taught me the virtue of being punctual, dutiful, and disciplined—traits which are imperative for one to be successful in life. Eating one meal a day taught me humility, patient, moderation, and perseverance. The mixed bowl of food was not there to torture me. It was there to teach me that if I could be happy with so little, how can I not be happy in the real world where I could eat anything I want as much as I want. True, chanting was meaningless. However, it taught me an essential lesson that there will be times in life where you have to do meaningless tasks and work with illogical people although you disagree, dislike, and get nothing out of it. The chance of encountering annoying bugs is actually less than the chance of meeting annoying people. So if I couldn’t even learn how to be with bugs then forget about learning to be with people.  My job as a Buddhist monk was to find happiness regardless of the condition. So was it the bugs’ fault that made me unhappy? Or was it my inability to accept the bugs that was there in the first place doing its job as it was designed to do while I was not doing mine? Was it the dirty toilet’s fault that I was unhappy with it or was it my resistance to the reality of the toilet that causes me to be unhappy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, happiness can be achieved by changing the world to be like how we want. But is that always viable when death, sickness, and old age is a certainty? or that we can’t always ask life to only gives us the “good” and never the “bad”? Clearly, such approach to happiness is not enough to make one happy. There will always be times when it is impossible to change the reality according to what we want. Happiness is as much about changing the world to fits our want as it is about changing ourselves to the world. &lt;strong&gt;For one to be happy, therefore, one must learn how to change/master oneself.&lt;/strong&gt; This is where real strength originates. There isn’t much to overcome by changing what is outside of ourselves. This is where humans truly flourish. This is where one can learn how to better oneself as a human being and benefit not only for oneself but for the world. This is where true happiness is found—a happiness which stands like a rock above the river of positivity and negativity called “life.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2017/04/05/my-experience-as-a-buddhist-monk/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2017/04/05/my-experience-as-a-buddhist-monk/</guid>
        
        <category>understanding-of-true-happiness</category>
        
        <category>practice-of-true-happiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Much Mindfulness is Enough?</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disciple:&lt;/strong&gt; &quot;How many hours should I spent doing mindfulness, master?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Master:&lt;/strong&gt; &quot;The moment you wake up til the moment you go to bed.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People often associate meditation with sitting meditation. But what many do not know is that, in fact, meditation in daily life is actually just as important. Walking to class, going to work, sitting at your desk, talking to your love ones, brushing your teeth, or washing dishing. Every moment is the opportunity to grow by practicing mindfulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walking to Class Needs Meditation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes when I walked to class, my mind got ahead of myself. It demanded, “I want to be at the class right now!” Once I had unmindfully put my happiness a head of where I am. I became unhappy. Each step I took, all I could think about is ”Why am I not there yet? Why am I not there yet? Why am I not there yet?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I do not realize is that I am being anxious and frustrated not because I haven’t reach my destination but because I’ve unskillfully placed my mind not in &lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.7;&quot;&gt;the reality but ahead of the reality. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the tool to help me to bring myself back to the reality/present moment? Of course, it is mindfulness. Once I remember to walk mindfully instead of letting my mind ran away with my happiness. I bring my happiness back simply by coming back to the present moment and be mindful of each step. This is meditation in daily life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking to class might seems like a trivial matter. But I would argue that walking to class is, in fact, no different from walking toward your goal in life. So if you can learn to be happy on your way to class, you can also learn to be happy on your way toward your goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I have talked about meditation as a way to bring us happiness by bring us back to reality. But another important theme that should be emphasized is that meditation makes people grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meditation makes people grow&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I walk to class everyday without being mindful of my obsessive passion to get to class, I am building my mental habits and my tendency to be unhappy the next time I walk to class. By being unmindful, therefore, I am learning to be unhappy. But each time that I can be mindful to class, I intentionally choose to unlearned my mental habits and transform myself from being unsatisfied to being happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meditation is transformative when put to use in daily life. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are waiting inline and someone in front of you is being slow, you might get impatient and irritated. But when you are mindful of your anger, you can learn to overcome it. In that way, not only will you learn how to save yourself your happiness but at the same time you are learning to build your character from someone who is impatient to someone who is patient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are talking to others, sometimes you might become defensive. But once you become mindful that you are being defensive, you can change. You can slowly choose to transform yourself from someone who is defensive and sentivie to someone who is open and composed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When sitting at your desk, you might often be distracted and sidetrack by going on social media or watching youtube videos. But by being mindful we can train ourselves to stay focus and productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly, meditation is not just something you do for a period of time. It is what one can do all day in every activity. So how much mindfulness is enough? That depends on how much you want to better yourself and how much you care about your happiness. The more you do it the more change you can be for yourself and the happier you become!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, mindfulness is your inner school. No one is in class when you are unmindful. So be present. (Literally and figuratively!)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/11/01/how-much-mindfulness-is-enough/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/11/01/how-much-mindfulness-is-enough/</guid>
        
        <category>true-happiness-essential</category>
        
        <category>understanding-of-true-happiness</category>
        
        <category>practice-of-true-happiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happiness is not Self-indulgence. It is Self-mastery.</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The happiness of a man in this life does not consist in the absence but in the mastery of his passions. - Alfred Lord Tennyson&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is a hundred dollar bill dropped in front of us while no one is watching, would snatching the opportunity considered “smart?” If there is an opportunity for us evade taxes and take advantages of the system’s loop hole, would profitting from such tactic “smart?” If we can cut corners and manipulate others to do the work we don’t want to do, would that be a “smart” thing to do? Here, Aristotle would not only said that it is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; “smart.” But worse, &lt;strong&gt;giving in to our own greed and desire is what Aristotle would describe as a weakness of character.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Aristotle, a moderate man becomes moderate because his ability to abstain from his greed. A courageous man becomes courageous because in spite of his fear he is able to act in ways which opposes it. The ability to rise above one’s impulses is the essense of human being.  It is what make human “human.” It is what make us “excellence.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a group of monkeys are hungry, they do not rationalize whether the act of stealing food is moral or immoral, they do whatever their impulses demand of them. When a dog is in shock or in a state of panic, it will attack even its owner if its instinct calls for such action. A moth does not rationalize whether flying toward a bon fire is “good” or “bad.” Its impulse demands it to do so, and thus it must fly toward its own demise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans have similar impulses that animals have. We sometimes desire things that are detrimental to ourselves like drugs, junk foods and alcohol. When a hundred-dollar bill is dropped in front of us while no one is watching, we can be tempted to take it. When we have to listen to someone in a discussion but he or she is off topic or is making completely no sense, we might be tempted to be frustrated and shut him or her out. But despite these impulses, we do not always lash out, became trapped as the slave to our own temptations, or give in to our desire of stealing. Instead, we learn how to be a good citizen by returning the money although we could have taken the money, we learn to quit bad habits to live a better life instead of a pleasurable one, and we let go of our frustration because see that giving others the proper respect is more important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Humans only become stronger, or “excellence,” by overcoming ourselves.&lt;/strong&gt; We are endowed with the capacity to be excellent. Character building is the development of one’s human capacity to be excellence. There is nothing to overcome by giving in to our desire and selflshness. In fact, how would humans then be so different from animals if we becomes the slave of our own desire? Being the master of our own desire is something only human can do. This development of one’s excellence is what Aristotle would have described as the greatest and truest path toward True Happiness. So be kind when there is no reason to be, abstain from anger even when other is at a fault, and love even though we get nothing for it because these are what humans are made of. Without them our society would be no different from that of a jungle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/10/08/character-building/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/10/08/character-building/</guid>
        
        <category>true-happiness-essential</category>
        
        <category>understanding-of-true-happiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>True Happiness Is Found, Not Chased</title>
        <dc:creator>V</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;blockquote class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&quot;The happiness ahead does not exist. It&#39;s now or never.&quot;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness only blooms within your heart when certain conditions are met. Like a seed that needs the right combination of soil, water, sunlight, and ecosystem to develop into a full-grown tree, the state of true happiness is achieved once their requirements are fulfilled too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am certain that everyone has experienced happiness in various occasions. The tumultuous, stressful lives that most of us lead motivate us to seek ways to escape and unwind. Most would choose vacations, leisure activities with friends and so forth. It simply is an emergency exit from your everyday troubles. You get temporary relief, and before you know it, you are thrown right back into the battlefield. While you do experience happiness, it is short-lived, and often comes at a high cost if you spend the rest of your life in this cycle. Most importantly, &lt;strong&gt;the chase is never-ending.&lt;/strong&gt; Imagine trying to do this in your 50’s and 60’s onwards! Why does happiness always seem to be ahead, and out of reach?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;capitalized&quot;&gt;So How Do We Start?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are starters to prime your mindset to get you on track to experiencing True Happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Think about the important events in your life where you felt saddest, angriest, and happiest.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make a list of those events, and mentally relive those moments. Notice different feelings that arise with each event.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you see the one thing in common that stands true among those feelings? Saddest, angriest, or happiest – none of them are everlasting. That happiness on your list does not last.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter how hard we try, this infamous happiness we all are seeking for slips out of our hands as soon as we taste it. We spend our lives searching for fuel to refill an infinitely leaking tank. We are seeking for happiness that does not truly exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;True Happiness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness is found, not chased. At True Happiness, what we are here to achieve is to help you find that happiness in every moment. This type of happiness is more economical and independent of external entities. It is attained from a set of factors fulfilled, it is generated from within us, and it &lt;strong&gt;results from understanding and accepting the reality.&lt;/strong&gt; It is reliable, stable, and does not result from being with your lover, your children, having a high net worth, or owning a beautiful mansion. It is free from conditions, no strings attached, and accessible to everyone. It does not require your chasing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin your journey toward True Happiness, &lt;a href=&quot;/start_here&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/07/28/happiness-is-found-not-chased/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/07/28/happiness-is-found-not-chased/</guid>
        
        <category>understanding-of-true-happiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Find Happiness in Challenging Times</title>
        <dc:creator>V</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We all face different kinds of challenging situations in our lives. I have personally struggled throughout life with my loved ones’ poor judgments and decision-making, leaving me stuck with the unpleasant fruit of their actions. As I go on living, I realize that there are numerous times in which I have no choice or control over my environment. I encounter selfish, greedy, and uncooperative coworkers in my workplace, yet I had to put up with it and get my tasks done as best as I could. I return to my home at the end of each day, to find more stress rather than relaxation. With the build up of stress everywhere I turn, I needed a quick and practical relief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;h2&gt;No matter how difficult the situation you face, there are ways to unlock the inner getaway to break yourself free, to safeguard your emotional health, and sanity.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right then and there. The result? Lighter, clearer mind, more relaxed mood, and a compassionate heart towards yourself, the situation, and the people in it. There are countless tactics to accomplish this. Here are the common tactics I have used which had worked for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.	Think of death.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of yourself. Of the ones you love. Of the ones you hate. Of you and all these people altogether. Of the very people you are trapped with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider this very real, and inescapable fact of life. No matter how everlasting the torture or pain you are experiencing, it does not go beyond death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.	Find a quiet room/corner/space.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turn your face to the wall, gently close your eyes, sit comfortably and breathe slowly. Just simply relax. This is your space. This is your moment. Feel the air traveling in and out of your whole body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2016/05/21/how-to-know-oneself#sitting_meditation&quot;&gt;(If you want to learn more about how to do sitting meditation, click here.)
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.	A go-to, comforting thought(s).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of your loved one, a sacred place, anything. If thinking of Dalai Lama often brings you a sense of relaxation and calm, use it. Practice it often so when you are deep in that hole of despair, the calm that arise with those thoughts can ease your pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although these are quick and temporary fixes, we all need a remedy every now and then to get ourselves back up on our feet and keep living. You can play around with the thoughts and methods that work for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please share with us if you found your remedies in the comments below!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/06/27/how-to-find-happiness-in-challenging-times/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/06/27/how-to-find-happiness-in-challenging-times/</guid>
        
        <category>dealing-with-unhappiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cause of Unhappiness Part Five: When Life Is At A Lost</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There will be times when life becomes too overwhelming. There will be times in our lives where we have no idea how to go on. There will be times where doubt, fear, confusion, and uncertainty will set in and cloud our minds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this age of information where we are constantly bombarded by the tales of what we should want in life. “You have to get a degree from college in order to be happy.” “You need a new phone in order to look good in front of your friends.” “You need that job/promotion.” “You have to have that big house to be ‘successful’.” “You need to get married by this age or else it will be impossible afterward.” On and on and on we are fed by stories of what “happiness” is suppose to be. But instead, these so called “happiness” often times left us with a sense inadequancy to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what should one do when life is at a lost? Here are four simple steps to getting your life back on track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;4 Steps to Get Your Life Back&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Stop and Take A Step Back&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;One evening I return to my hermitage from a walk in the hills, and I found that all the doors and windows of the hermitage had been blown open. When I left the house, I hadn&#39;t secured them, and a cold wind blew through the house, opened the windows, and scattered the papers from the desk all over the room. Immediately I closed the doors and the windows, lit a lamp, picked up the papers, and arranged them neatly on my desk. Then I started a fire in the fireplace, and soon the crackiling logs brought warmth back to the room.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-Thich Nhat Hanh&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above is exactly what we do with our life when it is at a lost. Thich Nhat Hanh equates our senses as the doors and windows of our life. &lt;strong&gt;You can’t pick yourself up in the middle of the storm.&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes it is wise to just stop and take a step back from it all. Of course, the purpose of this is not to give up. Its purpose is to give ourselves the chance to recover and prepare to face life again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To stop and take a step back from life could be anything from spending time with yourself, turning off all your electronics, a solo vacation, meditate, to participating in a meditation retreat. I do not recommend losing yourself to something else or putting the problem off by blurring the reality of the situation like making ourselves busy on purpose or do something just to forget the problem. The point is not to run away. The point is to allow you to step a out of your situation to look inward and review your life with more clarity so that you can begin anew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;capitalized&quot;&gt;2. Understand that it’s ok to be lost.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;It&#39;s ok to not be ok.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life never goes according to what one wants. This is the fact of life. So it&#39;s inevitable for everyone to, at some point, not be ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the worst and best thing that one can do at this point?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The worst thing anyone could do&lt;/strong&gt; when facing such a situation is to hate the situation one is in. Imagine you are lost in a desert with someone and that person just kept brooding, crying out loud, throwing tantrum, and complaining about the situation. How does that help make the situation any better if not worse? To hate the situation you are in is, therefore, like digging you own grave. It only makes everything worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its worse form, it creates an infinite down spiral. When one dislikes the situation one is in one tends to become dishearten and give up the whole thing which makes the situation even worse. And when the situation is worse, it makes one wants to give up even more. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The best thing that one could do&lt;/strong&gt; when lost is simply to focus on the problem in front of us in order to put our lives back again. Don&#39;t victimized yourself. See how others might even be in worse situation. Don&#39;t complain. Learn to be opened to the problems of life is a skill. Be nice to yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;capitalized&quot;&gt;3. Regaining your sense of direction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have given yourself an opportunity to stop and take a step out of your situation and you are calm and collected enough to face the challenges of life then it is time to find your sense of direction in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding one’s sense of direction required alot of inner and outer exploration. The questions which one should aim to answer are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What matters to me most?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What is the purpose of living?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What am I passionate about?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What is my core value?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What is my inner drive?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What cause do I believe in that is higher than myself?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s ok to not be able to answer these questions. Many never found their true sense of direction in life until late in their life. It is not something you can’t rush it because it has its own time. However, to help you find what drives you. Here are some advises:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&#39;t Overthink. Just Explore.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;The benefit of being lost is that it forces you to explore. It forces you to find your inner drive. So take this chance and learn more about yourself and find what it is that you truly believe in. Learn something new. Meet new and inspiring people. Live life differently from what you used to. Perhaps the reason why you are lost is because you haven&#39;t try that thing which you always wanted to try. Very much like when you are lost in real life in a middle of a jungle. You probably first need to know and assess what you&#39;ve got, where you want to head toward, and see what is in your surrounding that could be of use. So get exploring both inside and outside. And try your best not to do it out of fear, but out of joy.
	&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplify&lt;/strong&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;The reason why we are sometimes confused with life is because we have too many wants--some which are even conflicting with one another. Having too much wants makes our lives become too difficult to manage. As a rule of thumb, a simple life always lead to happiness. So find whatever that matters to you most and let go of others which are not. In this way, it is easier to find your sense of the direction which you want to head toward.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revisit Your Inner Drive&lt;/strong&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;If you are feeling lost then you must have known what it was like to not be lost. Revisit your past when you feel sure of life or when you felt you have a sense of purpose could be helpful to getting you back on track.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Keep Going, Do Not Give Up.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Players with fight never lose a game, they just run out of time&quot; - John Wooden&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are never lost until you give up. So never give up. Keep going. Eventually you will find your way. Perhaps it is not the path you were expecting. But you will find it. It’s only a matter of patient, perseverance, and time. You have my full support! If you would like to share you story for others to help and support you or become an inspiration to others. You can do so at &lt;a href=&quot;/forum/&quot;&gt;True Happiness’s Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/06/09/why-am-i-unhappy-5/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/06/09/why-am-i-unhappy-5/</guid>
        
        <category>dealing-with-unhappiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Know Oneself?</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;We Meditate.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meditation is simply to know. “Know” in this sense is not knowing in our thoughts or knowing from reading, listening, or thinking but knowing as in &lt;em&gt;to experience, be aware of, or be mindful of.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do we know in meditation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objects that we must know in meditation are ourselves. The self can be divided into two main parts: &lt;strong&gt;the mind and the body&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, it could further be separated it into five parts which are..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Body&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Consciousness&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Thoughts&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Feeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the objects of meditations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do we do once we are mindful of our body, consciousness, knowledge, thoughts, and feeling?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing. Simply by being mindful of ourselves is enough. This might sounds very strange in this age where one has to always do more or always take a more active stance in achieving something. But this is not the case for meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the correct way to know in meditation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Know objectively as is. Without any need to change or to desire how our body, consciousness, knowledge, thoughts, and feeling should or should not be. If you are upset, know that you are upset. If we have a stomach ache, know that we have the stomach ache. This is how we develop our mindfulness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why should I develop my mindfulness? What is the purpose of meditation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of meditation is to allow the mind to see its own reality. Our life is full of ups and downs, positive emotions and negative emotions, good thoughts and bad thoughts, birth and death, and of knowledge of what is “good” and “evil”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we live and navigate in the world which is full of these dualities of life is the real question that one must know the answer to live a  happy life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When life is not going the way we want we can always say to ourselves that, “life is uncertain” or that “it will soon pass.” But do our hearts really accept this fact? Even with the knowledge that life is uncertain, we still suffer. For this reason, knowing by knowledge is not enough. What we need is to know life by heart. This is why meditation is needed as the tool for our hearts to come to know truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By allowing our hearts to see the dualities of life, we can see that life with its ups and downs has three characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything is impermanent.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Nothing lasted.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Reality has nothing to do with what we want, but it has everything to do with the natural law of cause and effect. &lt;a href=&quot;/2016/01/07/no-room-for-desire-in-life/&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;(For a more detailed explanation, click here.)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meditation is how one comes to understand reality. It is how our hearts learn about how everything comes and goes, how all must inevitably progress from birth to death, and how the world is not about what we want but about the absolute law of cause and effect. These are the truth that our hearts will come to see for itself just by being mindful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the hearts could come to understand the truth of life. Life becomes easier to live and harder for it to suffer. Like learning how to ride a horse, if you do not know how, riding becomes a nightmare. And often times than not, the horse rides you more than you ride the horse. Life is very much the same. This is why one must learn life to live it. And meditation is how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Types of Meditation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong id=&quot;meditation_in_daily_life&quot;&gt;1. Meditation in Daily Life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important type of meditation is not one in which most people believe. Many have the idea of meditation as sitting down, closing our eyes, and watch our breathing. But for meditation to be effective it must be practical in our daily life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there are two ways one could develop mindfulness in our daily life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Being mindful of our mind&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Our mind consists of our consciousness, knowledge, thoughts, and feelings. Consciousness&#39;s only task is to know. Knowledge is what we know. Thoughts are our cognitive thinking. And feeling is... feeling! (However, it could be further generalized into three types of feelings: positive, negative, and neutral.)&lt;/p&gt;

		&lt;p&gt;We develop our mindfulness by noticing our thoughts and feelings. When a thought takes our mind from places to places we know our mind is wandering. When we are happy, we know that we are happy. When we are sad we know that we are sad. This is all it takes to develop mindfulness. (Really?) Really!&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Being mindful of our body&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;In our daily life, we can develop our mindfulness by knowing our bodies in the present moment like when we are breathing, walking, eating, sitting, and etc. Simple right? Just know our bodily movement through out the day and we are all set!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, meditation in daily life is to know our body, consciousness, knowledge, thoughts, and feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;How much daily meditation is enough?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;All day is enough. True practictioners of mindfulness begin their practice starting from the moment they wake up until the moment they go to bed. They are mindful of when they get out of bed, brush their teeth, eat, walk, go to work, come home, and go to bed. They are mindful of all their positive or negative thoughts and emotions through out the day. The practice of mindfulness is easy; but to practice it consistently through out the day is not. Slowly build your mindfulness in daily life until it becomes a second-nature.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Sitting and Walking Meditation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong id=&quot;sitting_meditation&quot;&gt;Sitting Meditation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Sitting meditation is ultimately to be mindful of our in breath and out breath. Let&#39;s first begin with the steps:&lt;/p&gt;

		&lt;ol&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Find a suitable spot for sitting meditation. Preferably any place that is quiet and give you a sense of peace and tranquility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sit in a comfortable position. It is not required for you to sit on the floor. Sitting on a chair would do. But I would recommend that the chair should not be too comfortable because it would make you fall asleep!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can begin noticing your out breath and in breath with your eyes open or closed. If you easily get sleepy while doing your sitting meditation then it would be good to start with your eyes open and just notice the in and out breath before closing your eyes once you feel more concentrated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuosly be mindful of the breath. If you mind wanders, simply bring it back to the breath and continue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ol&gt;

		&lt;p&gt;These are the steps to sitting meditation which can seem pretty simple but once you are into the practice and actuality of doing it, it is not. So here are some tips.&lt;/p&gt;

		&lt;u&gt;Quick Tips on Sitting Meditation&lt;/u&gt;
		
		&lt;p&gt;Meditation is not about control nor is it about letting the mind runs loose. The trick is to find the perfect balance between controlling and not. To know the breath by being not too tight and not too loose. Sitting meditation is like holding a chick. If you hold it too loosely it runs away. If you hold it too tightly, the chick suffocates. If you find yourself feeling tight, stiff, having a headache, or finding it difficult to just breathe during or after meditation then it is a clear sign that you are exerting too much control. If you are sleepy, find your mind wandering from places to places without being able to come back to the breath, then it might be possible that you are too loose. Learning sitting meditaiton is like learning how to ride a bike. It will take time and experience to adjust and know your own balance. And practice is key to finding it.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walking Meditation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Since my practice in walking meditation has been trained from the Theravada Buddhist tradition. I want to offer what I know from my own experience. So follow the links below to learn about how as well as why we do walking meditation. (Make sure you turn on the subtitle.) This knowledge will also aid you in your sitting meditation since it pretty much has the same concept.
&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LPqhDiHmQWw&quot;&gt;Video on &quot;How to practice walking meditation?&quot; #1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zJRBu5uYrjI&quot;&gt;Video on &quot;How to practice walking meditation?&quot; #2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;How much sitting/walking meditation is enough?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Twice a day. I would suggest to make this into a habit by chaining it with some daily routine you have been doing. For example, right after you shower or before you go to bed. It does not need to be a hour long session. In fact one minute would do. But the important thing is to not lose the routine. Once you keep the routine for around 3 weeks, the habit of meditating will stick with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;I can only show you the door. But you are the only who has to walk through it.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, I could talk all day about how you should meditate; but in the end you have to do it. Only through meditation will you find out for yourself what meditation actually is. You can’t learn how to ride a horse or swim from just reading a textbook. You must do it to learn it. Life is where we can learn about life’s truth. This is why &lt;strong&gt;meditation is defined as the process of knowing oneself&lt;/strong&gt;. Enough talking and start doing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;short&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recommended readings about “Meditation”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Why Meditation?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2016/03/22/why-meditate/&quot;&gt;Learn goals behind the art of meditation, click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Why Meditation Matters to The World?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/08/24/why_true_happiness/&quot;&gt;If you are curious about why meditation is important to this world, click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;What I Have Received from Meditation as a Long-Time Practitioner?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2016/04/02/my-experience-with-meditation/&quot;&gt;Click here to learn more about my experience with meditation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/05/21/how-to-know-oneself/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/05/21/how-to-know-oneself/</guid>
        
        <category>practice-of-true-happiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When You Love, You Become Love</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;And in the end, the love you take is equal to the love you make.&quot; ― The Beatles&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything is and can be the object of our love. When we exercise our capacity to love on anything at all–ourselves, love ones, stranger, work, pets or even an insect–we become love itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site is about finding True Happiness. And love is definitely one of the ways in which one could come to understand and experience True Happiness. But unlike the convention kind of romantic love, the kind of love we are talking about is an act of compassion and selflessness, to look beyond ourselves for the well-being of others without expecting anything in return. It is an act done entirely for the benefits of others. There is no exchange in this kind of love. It is not a give and take. We get nothing for it. It is a &lt;strong&gt;gift&lt;/strong&gt; in its truest sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many believe it is never worth it to do anything if it does not pay. Just like this website, many have told me it is a waste of time to write these articles on True Happiness. Their logic is that if it does not generate income then it is, in their exact words, “useless”, “a waste of time”, “never going to work.” But this website is not intented to be an exchange for me to gain something. &lt;em&gt;It’s a gift.&lt;/em&gt; It is to love others even though there is nothing in return. It is an investment in a relationship that may or may not work at all. I am pouring my heart and soul into this blind shot in the dark all in the hope that it will help someone in their life to find love, peace, truth, purpose, and happiness. I am betting everything to get nothing and it is fine by me because I am happy to love first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Love is Happiness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love is probably one of the strongest emotion. It dominates and dissipates all doubts, hates, politics, and the dramas of human’s life. You will be surprised how quickly can love turn your day around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We always think that we would be happy if others love us. But what we do not realise is that we would be just as happy if we were to love others. So stop wanting to be loved, and start looking for ways to love. Look no further to find True Happiness because &lt;strong&gt;True Happiness is in the very act of love.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dalai Lama once said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;If you want others to be happy, practice compassion. If you want to be happy, practice compassion.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all have the capacity for love. So exercise it. And exercise it often epecially on those who you dislike. Exercise it on yourself and everything that come into your life until it becomes your nature to love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you look at someone, always ask the question of “How can I love?” or “How can I love this person?” Just in that very thought, you are already setting up yourself to be happy. Regardless of who he is she is or what he or she has done to you, this is our &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; duty. It’s perhaps the only attitude we all should have toward life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Let no one ever come to you without leaving better and happier. Be the living expression of God&#39;s kindness: kindness in your face, kindness in your eyes, kindness in your smile.&quot; - Mother Teresa&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This task is not limited to others but it can be applied to anything at anytime. So you can also ask question like “How can I love myself?” or “What is the best thing to do for myself right now?” Even ill thoughts and negative feelings that enter our mind, they are also the objects of our love. I have been waking up with the question of “How can I love today?” It’s a great question to start the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- We always want to be loved by others, but rarely do we want to love others. So let&#39;s change that.
 --&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to leave you with these beautiful and memorable quotes below which I believe better summarise my point about love and True Happiness. (I think it would also be a good ideas to put these quotes up on our desks and in our bedrooms.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;“Seize the moments of happiness, love and be loved! That is the only reality in the world, all else is folly. It is the one thing we are interested in here.” 
― Leo Tolstoy&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;short&quot; /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;“For every minute you are angry you lose sixty seconds of happiness.” 
― Ralph Waldo Emerson&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;short&quot; /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;“The Paradoxical Commandments&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

People are illogical, unreasonable, and self-centered.
Love them anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

If you do good, people will accuse you of selfish ulterior motives.
Do good anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

If you are successful, you will win false friends and true enemies.
Succeed anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

The good you do today will be forgotten tomorrow.
Do good anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Honesty and frankness make you vulnerable.
Be honest and frank anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

The biggest men and women with the biggest ideas can be shot down by the smallest men and women with the smallest minds.
Think big anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

People favor underdogs but follow only top dogs.
Fight for a few underdogs anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

What you spend years building may be destroyed overnight.
Build anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

People really need help but may attack you if you do help them.
Help people anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Give the world the best you have and you&#39;ll get kicked in the teeth.
Give the world the best you have anyway.” 
― Kent M. Keith, The Silent Revolution: Dynamic Leadership in the Student Council&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;short&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related resources about “love and compassion”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Ted Talk by Ex-Googler Chade-Meng Tan on &quot;Everyday Compassion at Google&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/chade_meng_tan_everyday_compassion_at_google.html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/04/10/becoming-love/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/04/10/becoming-love/</guid>
        
        <category>love</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Experience With Meditation</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It is not wrong to be curious about meditation and where it would take us. So as a long-time practitioner of mindfulness, here is a short list of what I have received in these last 10 years of meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Happiness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Make a man happy and he will be happy for a day. Teach a man how to be happy and he will be happy for a life time.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People today are finding life more difficult to be happy and easier to be discontent. The reason is because our happiness has become both fleeting and is always in front of us. We often think, “I’ll be happy if…”, “I’ll be happy when…” Thus, our happiness is always in the future. Never is our happiness with us in this very moment. We have become so busy running and jumping from one kind of happiness to the next hoping it would finally fulfil our lives. But the chase never ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;If you can&#39;t be happy now. You will never be happy.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meditation is a method which allows us to be in touch with our inner balance. It is not about chasing, but about coming home. When we are in touch with our inner balance, we become more conscious of our inner imbalances. And that is how mindfulness builds and becomes awareness. What I mean by “imbalance” is our unhappiness; namely anger, worry, jealousy, greed, frustration, despair, disappointment and etc. (For more information about what unhappiness is, click &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/06/01/what_is_happiness/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether or not we will be happy or unhappy all depends on how much we can be awared of our own imbalances. When we are unawared of the unhappiness in our lives, the unhappiness spreads in our mind like wildfire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are angry at someone and you do not forgive him or her, what you eventually find is yourself saying bad things about him or her in your head. You will start convincing yourself how he or she is a bad person and how you will never talk to them again. So by allowing our inner fire to go wild, we unknowingly fueled our fire of hatred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noticing these imbalances quickly and objectively is enough for the fire to stop. When you practice long enough, you will notice, in split second, even the slightest imbalance in our hearts. When we could quickly see what is causing our unhappiness, we couldn’t help but ask ourselves, “Why hold on to the hot iron?” This is precisely the reason why meditation or mindfulness is imperative to our happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mindfulness protects our happiness.&lt;/strong&gt; It allows us to see the true cause of our unhappiness. It helps us to not be consumed by our own feelings and instead see it for what it is. Through mindfulness, we become the observer of our unhappiness and not the unhappiness itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;blockquote&gt;Hatred can&#39;t be stop by hatred. It only stops by compassion. &lt;br&gt;-Buddha&lt;/blockquote&gt;
 --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t tell you how many times a day these imbalances pop up in my daily life. And every single day for the last 10 years, mindfulness has countlessly saved my happiness. This is why I started True Happiness. This is why I know for sure that it will save your happiness too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Self-Transformation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to think I am already “good”. Even when others gave me honest constructive criticisms or useful feedbacks, I would see them as “attacks” or attempts to delegitimize my identity of being “good”. I prefered to hold on to my image of being “good” rather than be good. And for that, I can’t grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This attitude of being too good for improvement is perhaps the worst attitude anyone could have toward self-growth. According to the Buddha, he considered these people to already be “dead.” For they no longer have anything more to offer because their attempts to hold on to their “goodness” has hinder them of bettering themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meditation has turn this attitude of mine 360 degrees. What meditation allows me to see is myself for who I really am. Before I was biased toward myself. I thought I was already “good”. And there is nothing more I need to improve. But once I started seeing myself more and more, I start to see that I was not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have found many contradictions within myself which I only apply to others but never to myself. I realised my prejudices and double-standards which many times have causes me many troubles without me seeing itse negative effects. I have come to see my many flaws and shortcomings which I had always overlook and sometimes even blamed others for. I have overcame many unwholesome desires which I thought was my “happiness” but turns out just to be the attempts to fill the unfillable void in my heart. The list goes on and on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mind is like a garden. If you do not tend it, only weed grows. It is impossible to improve what we do not know because you don’t even know what the thing to be improved is in the first place. Seeing ourselves is precisely what meditation allows us to do. And if meditation could completely change who I am for the better then it will change yours too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Love&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not the romantic kind of “love” we know. But this is the love that is found and given out of self-understanding and selflessness. It is the love which comes as the fruits of meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one is perfect; and I am of no exception. Many times in my life I wanted to yell and insult others who have angered me. Many times in my life I feel jealous of others who are doing better than me. Many times in my life I wanted to hurt others who have hurt me. Many times in my life I wanted to lie and cheat to quickly get whatever I want in life. But I never did any of those things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? Because I kept my practice and was mindful of these unwholesome desires. I can’t command what kind of thought would pop up in my mind. I can’t tell my feelings to never feel bad. I can’t tell my stomach ache to stop being painful. These are my realities. However, what I can do is how I response to it. And I simply choose to be mindful of it instead of giving in to it. This is meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I become mindful of my own reality. I start seeing myself as something which comes and goes. I learn to not take my negative thought and feeling seriously. I start seeing myself as something which has death as its final destination, I learn to let go of my unhappiness knowing life is too short to be unhappy. I start seeing myself as part of the absolute law of cause and effect, I know that everything happens because there are conditions for it to happen. Thus, I can easily come to terms with reality whether it is good or bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The practice of mindfulness is an upward spiral which helps one to be better than oneself. Each time I come to understand and let go of one unwholesome desire, I became better and better at handling the next. This is self-mastery. If you truly love yourself this is what you do. If you seek happiness and truth, meditation is what you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I can overcome my unwholesome desire, I am in the process stop myself from harming others. This for me is love–one which is good for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Purpose in Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every individual lives to seek happiness in one form or another. However, the pursue of one’s happiness does not necessarily mean that it is always beneficial for all. Often time than not, our pursues of happiness only benefit ourselves. And worse, in some cases, they come at the cost of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the best way of living life–one that is beneficial for both oneself and the world? What is the best way to solve world problem and social problem of today? What is the best step to take toward creating the condition for world peace? &lt;strong&gt;What is the best thing life can offer?&lt;/strong&gt; These are the questions I have since 18.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my journey to answer these questions, I began studying Philosophy. I traveled, backpacked, and lived in India, France, Japan and many others countries around the world. I even ordained as a Theravada Buddhist monk for one year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After years of ceaselessly searching for the answer, the answer I have found is happiness. Happiness is what create our world, for good or for evil. It dictates people’s lives and decides how our world will be. Wealth will not save this world from itself. Even if it rains in gold today, people’s greed will not end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;World peace can not be achieved by changing what is outside of us, it is achieved by developing how each and everyone of us seek and define happiness inside of ourselves.&lt;/strong&gt; And meditation is the tool for developing our happiness. Through the practice of mindfulness, not only will we find both Truth and True Happiness, but in the process benefits the world as well. It is the best thing that one can do for oneself as well as the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Truth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Knowing yourself is the beginning of all wisdom.&quot; - Aristotle&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What originally led me to meditation is not my desire to be happy, but my desire to know Truth. It is rather odd how the two coincide. But from my experience, they do and they must. There is no True Happiness without Truth. One would not be wrong to say that finding Truth is also finding True Happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my time in college, I studied Philosophy. My journey in Philosophy has led me to know Truth. I know that Truth is outside of language. I know that it is the Unspeakable. I know that it transcends all dualities of life. But what I am saying to you right now is like describing to you how a dish would taste. I could tell you all about it but in the end it is you who have to taste it to know what it actually taste like. Similarly, Truth can be learned. But it must be experienced through meditation in order to truly know what it actually is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, learning the truth of life is enjoyable in and of itself. Think of it as learning how to ride a horse. When you don’t know how, it is difficult and stressful to try to steer it. But once you come to learn about the nature of the horse and how to ride it, it is much easier and much more enjoyable. Life is very much the same. The more I became aware of the Truth of life the easier and happier life becomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You either live life or the life will live you, one way or the other.&lt;/strong&gt; And the only difference is how much can  we come to know life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What meditation has given me is unrequitable and invaluable. There is too much that meditation has given me to all be written in words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have spoken to you about what I have received through meditation. But just as a final note, &lt;strong&gt;meditation is not something anyone should expect to gain anything out of.&lt;/strong&gt; The expectation and desire of meditation will make it impossible to succeed in any attempt to meditate. Even though meditation leads you to True Happiness, but you can’t even expect or demand it to make you happy. Meditation is just to be mindful of ourselves. Just that is enough to get us to True Happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I am not here to prove to you why you should meditate. &lt;strong&gt;Meditation does not need convincing as much as it needs to be proven.&lt;/strong&gt; Thus, the only way to find out if what I have told you is true or if meditation can really give you True Happiness is to give it a try. Let meditation speaks its own truth to you so that you can see for yourself what meditation is and what it is for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;I can only point you toward the door. But you have to walk through it yourself.&quot; - Buddha&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;short&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For other suggested/related readings...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/08/24/why_true_happiness/&quot;&gt;How Meditation Will Save The World?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2016/03/22/why-meditate/&quot;&gt;Why Meditate?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/04/02/my-experience-with-meditation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/04/02/my-experience-with-meditation/</guid>
        
        <category>practice-oftrue-happiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Know Oneself?</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are 3 goals in knowing oneself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		To see the true nature of ourselves and the world
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		To experience peace and happiness
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		To become skillful at handling our own desires
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This practice is known since ancient times as &quot;&lt;strong&gt;meditation&lt;/strong&gt;&quot;. Meditation allows us to experience a state of stillness. When the mind is not looking for something it wants and is not concern about its dislike, our mind comes together to produce an experience of True Happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be careful though that the practice of mindfulness is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; about not thinking or ignoring or denying the reality of our undesirable thoughts and feelings. Mindfulness is simply to be mindful. All thoughts, feeling and everything that comes to our senses are &lt;em&gt;allowed.&lt;/em&gt; The practice of mindfulness is not a judgment on ourselves. It is not a self-management exercise in which we must assert control over ourselves. It is a practice of knowing and being mindful of life as it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more we come to know the nature of ourselves the more we will realize the three noble Truths of our lives which are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything-ourselves, our feelings, our attitude, our body, or the world-is impermanent.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Nothing lasted.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Reality has nothing to do with what we want. (&lt;a href=&quot;/2016/01/07/no-room-for-desire-in-life/&quot;&gt;For a more detailed explanation, click here.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How could the heart be unhappy if it knows everything is impermanent? How could the heart be unhappy if it knows everything will not last forever? How could our heart be unhappy if it knows that reality is not about what we want but about the absolute law of cause and effect that determined reality? It can&#39;t be unhappy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the Truth that our hearts will come to know through meditation. It is not about knowing it intellectually. We can know that everything is impermanent in our thought but does our hearts truly accept and understand that Truth? When someone we love passes away, regardless of how many books we read about impermanent, it is only the heart that decides our happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this reason, &lt;strong&gt;we need to meditate in order to let our heart see the Truth for itself.&lt;/strong&gt; It&#39;s not an intellectual discovery to be found in books or in logic. It&#39;s a spiritual discovery which comes from and by the heart that see the Truth of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;short&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recommended readings about “Why we know oneself?”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Why Knowing Oneself Matters to The World?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/08/24/why_true_happiness/&quot;&gt;If you are curious about why meditation is important to this world, click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong class=&quot;capitalized&quot;&gt;What I Have Received from my self-study as a Long-Time Practitioner?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2016/04/02/my-experience-with-meditation/&quot;&gt;Click here to learn more about my experience with meditation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/03/22/why-know-oneself/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/03/22/why-know-oneself/</guid>
        
        <category>practice-of-true-happiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cause of Unhappiness Part Four: Mistake in Life</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;You can&#39;t change or erase what happened in the past, all you can change is your attitude toward it.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mistake in life is not to be taken lightly. For some, one small mistake could define who they are and enslave our lives in an unending quest to redeem or fix the mistake that he or she has done in the past. So let’s first begin by understanding what mistake is and how it affects our happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Understanding the Nature of Life Mistake&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Mistake is like a ghost.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we do not reconcile or do not know how to reconcile with our mistake, the mistake becomes an open loop which endlessly haunts our lives. The more we wish to not think about our mistake, the more our minds irresistibly wander back to the mistake to relive it. Even though that particular mistake might have happened many years ago, or you might be at work or in the middle of a party, our mistake will not rest or give us a break. It will continue to enter into our conscious mind to remind us of its presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The mistake itself is not what makes us unhappy. It’s our attitude towards it that makes us unhappy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mistake is fueled by our biases toward it. The more we resist, avoid, hide, deny, blame, bend, or twist the reality of our mistake the more powerful it becomes in our lives. It draws power from our desire to not accept or come to term with it. The feeling of guilt, depression, anger, frustration, self-hating, and embarrassment. All of which originate from our desire that the past should or should not have been otherwise. It’s the void in our want from reality which we desperately want to change but can’t. The only way for a mistake to lose its power is for us to allow our mistake to be, without disliking it or denying its reality. Accept the mistake as it is without any filters. This is how a mistake loses its power and slowly fade away from our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Mistake is by default inevitable.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody wants to make mistake. Yet, why do we make mistake? Nobody would make a mistake if they know ahead of time what would be the consequence of that action. &lt;em&gt;But the point here is we don’t.&lt;/em&gt; That is why we must make mistake. There is no avoiding it. So when we look back at our mistake in life especially ones that our minds often replay in our heads, it is important to understand that there was nothing we can do to change the past. It is something that must happen the way it did and not any other way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Changing Our Attitude with Our Mistakes in Life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how does one deal with one’s mistake? Here are 4 definitive steps to overcoming your mistake in life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Take Full Responsibility For Your Mistake And All Its Ramification&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;If we are unwilling to accept its consequences, then we are not ready to fully come to terms with our mistake. Have the courage to face your mistake. Be responsible for it. Don&#39;t run away from it. Mistake is by definition undesirable. But when we made a mistake, we must be strong and mature enough to take full responsibility for it whether or not it was intentionally or unintentionally, whether it effects just you or many other people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Think About What Is Best At This Very Moment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Is there a benefit in going over our mistake? If there is then please do. But if brooding over our mistake only rubs the salt in the wound, then perhaps there is no point in letting our mistake take over our lives. The best question to ask in this situation is, &quot;What can we control at this moment?&quot; Can we change the past? No. Can we change what is in the now? Yes. So let&#39;s focus on what we can change instead of what we can&#39;t. Let&#39;s ask relevant questions like, &quot;How can I do my best now so that I can avoid more mistake in the future?&quot; or &quot;What is the best thing to do right now?&quot; So without the burden of the past, &lt;strong&gt;move on by letting go of the past which you no longer have control and focus on what you can control in the present moment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Learn to Forgive Ourselves&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;It&#39;s impossible to move on if we do not forgive ourselves from our mistake. The characteristic of mistake in life is that they inevitable. Thus, it must happen the way it did. Looking back, you would never have done it. But because you did not know. That&#39;s why you made that mistake. So don&#39;t take it personally. Anyone who was in your shoes would have made the same mistake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Accepting Our Mistake as It Is. Do not Avoid, Hide, Deny, Blame Others, Bend, or Twist the Reality of Our Mistake.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;If you can&#39;t openly tell others your mistake, then this is perhaps a good indicator that there is something you still cannot accept about it. Of course, I am &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; suggesting for us to go out and tell everybody of our mistake either. My point is simply to come to understand ourselves to see if we still have our biases toward our mistake. If we still do then it is time to reconcile ourselves with these mistakes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Learning to Be with Your Mistake&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to reconcile with any mistakes in life is to accept it. Accepting is different from justifying our wrong doing. Accepting our mistake is to understand that there is no way of going back to fix the past of what we have done. Accepting our mistake is to be courageous and mature enough to accept whatever outcome and ramification that resulted as the direct or indirect outcome of our mistake. Accepting is to see no value in brooding or regretting our mistake, but instead see the value in what is in front of us. It is to be in the now by taking in the mistake as is, not as what you hope or do not hope it would be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a basic practice, when the mind wanders back to your mistake in life, &lt;strong&gt;do not fight it.&lt;/strong&gt; Do not find excuses for yourself about why you were not wrong. Do not look for a scapegoat. Observe the feelings associated with our mistakes, but let it be as it is without hoping the mistake would happen otherwise. Simply, know it and be mindful of it. Take it as it is. And understand that it must happen the way it did. Remind yourself of what is the best thing to do right now by knowing what you can and what you can’t control. And let go of our feelings by seeing how the bad feelings that comes with your mistake does not help you or anyone to be better. Eventually, your mistake will begin to lose its power as you slowly come to understand its nature. &lt;strong&gt;Don’t let your mistake of the past clouds what is in front you today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Worse, we even welcome it in our lives by letting the mistake take over us. This is similar to when you are sad and want to listen to a sad song just to make life sadder. We feel it is not enough for us to feel the pain of the mistake, so we begin rubbing the salt in the wound just so the pain can seep a little deeper.
 --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/03/09/why-am-i-unhappy-4/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/03/09/why-am-i-unhappy-4/</guid>
        
        <category>dealing-with-unhappiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cause of Unhappiness Part Three: Fear of Being Meaningless</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the worst fear of our lives is that we become meaningless. Whether this would be meaningless to oneself, meaningless to others, or meaningless to the world. Meaninglessness comes in various forms. The feeling of being useless, most evident in today society where everything is about productivity, to a feeling of inadequacy. At True Happiness, this is an important concept to understand as often times, we, humans, equate our self-worth with our meaning. So let’s dig a little deeper on this subject of meaninglessness to see where we could find True Happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; src=&quot;http://true-happiness.github.io/img/stick.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most renowned Theravada Buddhist Monk in Thailand, “Ajahn Chah,” once asked his disciples if a wooden stick–just like the one in the picture above–is long or short. Some answered, “It is long.” Some answered, “It is short.” But Ajahn Chah’s answer was not what one would unexpected. His answer is that the stick is neither long nor short. It is only long if we want it to be short. And it is short only if you want it to be long. Thus, the wooden stick is neither short or long. It is what it is. Only our want make it short or long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, our life is the same as that wooden stick. &lt;strong&gt;We are as meaningless as how much meaningful we want to be.&lt;/strong&gt; A rich person who want to be richer always feels he or she is not meaningful enough. So in a sense, he is “poor.” A poor person who feels that he or she has all that he or she could ever want is in way “rich.” It all depends on your want. If you want to be richer then immediately you are “poor.” If you feel you already have more than you want then at that very moment you are “rich.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We are as meaningless as how much meaningful we want to be.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moment you want to be more meaningful is the moment that you have become meaningless. Those who feels they are already meaningful has no need to search for more meaning in their life. They are already happy and satisfied with life. They have finished looking for more meaning to fill the void of their meaninglessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, &lt;strong&gt;to find true happiness is not to look for more meaning, but to stop looking for one&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;What To Take Away&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are as meaningless as how much meaningful we want to be. Thus, to find true happiness is not to look for meaning, but to stop looking for one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- 
&lt;p&gt;
	Meaning emernate from the function of difference. What I mean by that is meaning is only possible by comparing two things. The meaning of something is emernate from what it is not. How
&lt;/p&gt; --&gt;

&lt;!-- 
&lt;p&gt;Life, in essense, is incomparable to one another. Life is just is. You can compare all you want but at the end of the day how could you ever compare something so different to one another? So live and let live.&lt;/p&gt;

We are as meaningless as we want to be. 


&lt;p&gt;meaning = self-worth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have studied Philosophy espeically on the topic of epistemology or the study of how we know what we know then you will know that meaning emernate from a function of difference. What I mean by that is &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what I am going to tell you. First, it&#39;s ok to be meaningless.(decontructivist) Second, you are not meaningless.(constructivist)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are looking for a meaningful life, but to truly live is not to look for one.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If you want to be meaningful, then you need to have what it takes to be meaningless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;http://seattleinsight.org/Talks/BrowseTalks/DharmaTalk/tabid/90/TalkID/375/Default.aspx&quot;&gt;recommended talks&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;p&gt; 
	Let&#39;s face it. I believe we are all born with the fear of being meaningless. We are so fearful that we will not have any meaning that we live our lives trying to add meaning to ourselves. We buy things we do not need to help boost our ego. We want to get that degrees so that we look better than our friends. We want to get that job so that we feel better about ourselves. Why? because we feel we still do not have enough.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;It takes so little, so infinitely little, for someone to find himself on the other side of the border, where everything - love, convictions, faith, history - no longer has meaning. The whole mystery of human life resides on the fact that it is spent in the immediate proximity of, and even in direct contact with, that border, that it is separated from it not by kilometers but by barely a millimeter.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- Milan Kundera, The Book of Laughter and Forgetting&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This fear of being meaningless has been with us since we were born and it is at the core of our existence.

	We can&#39;t even rest anymore since it is tied to a sense of meaninglessness. We can&#39;t even not have a salary. How much salary we make become how meaningful we are.

	But is being meaningful or useful in life
&lt;/p&gt;


So why do we not want to be meaningless? What&#39;s wrong with being meaningless? I believe that the answer to this question is the fact that we were born with nothing to begin with.

So why do we fear meaninglessness?
How does meaningless cause us unhappiness?


&lt;p&gt;
	But we are born with nothing, and we will die with nothing. So actually whatever a little we have right now is already a plus. It is a gift just to be alive. It is a gift to be born healthy. Thus, it is not correct to assume that we are meaningless.

	It&#39;s ok to be meaningless. We were all born from being zero. 

	There are probably millions of infant motality  We have nothing to begin with. Why are we crying over something which is even already even better than when we are born. Many infants today die even before they get a chance to live. Why are we crying over our the bad luck despite being so lucky to live up until now?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Meaning is, therefore, relative. Let&#39;s say you feel you are not rich enough. And you are unhappy about it. 

	Meaning is created by comparing one thing with another. It simply the difference between one thing and another. Meaning does not emernate from the thing itself. 
&lt;/p&gt;
 --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/02/20/why-am-i-unhappy-3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/02/20/why-am-i-unhappy-3/</guid>
        
        <category>dealing-with-unhappiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Science of Happiness: The Law of Cause and Effect.</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If I know water would boil at a 100 degrees Celsius. Do I need to hope it would boil at 100 degree Celsius? Or even if I do not want the water to be boiled, could I desire the water not to be boiled even if I heat it up to 100 degrees Celsius? I can hope, dance, or pray—or do all three at once—for it to rain tomorrow. However, if the causes are not right, it will not rain. Or maybe I do not want it to rain tomorrow. But again, if the conditions are right for it to rain, it will rain regardless of what I want or do not want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simple yet elegant wisdom that I am attempting to reiterate here is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reality has nothing to do with what one wants. Instead, reality has everything to do with the law of cause and effect.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the causes are right for an effect to occur, it will occur regardless of what one wants or do not want. Scientifically speaking, there is no room for desires in reality. There is only cause and effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The common way, we, humans, achieve happiness in life is to put what we desire in front of the causes we must perform to achieve the result. We start a project by wanting it to be finished. We run a business by hoping to gain and never to lose. We often live by being afraid of dying even though we are perfectly fine. Even when we are deeply in love with someone, we can’t help ourselves feeling a little insecure about how long the good time will last. Humans always put our desire in front of what the reality is. For this reason, our pursue of happiness has led us to constantly become fearful, worried, impatient, and frustrated by what we demand from reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But is this really necessary? or is there a better way of pursuing happiness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Two Approaches Toward True Happiness: One Is Scientific And Other Is Not.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ways of achieving anything in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Desire-Oriented Approach to Happiness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This human’s most typical approach toward happiness. By putting our desire in front of what the reality is, our happiness is externalized and is dependent what we hope from the reality than what the reality is. And thus, he or she can never be happy until his desire is fulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Reality-Oriented Approach to Happiness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second way is to work toward your goal without the need to get ahead of ourselves. In other words, to work with and according to what the reality is, not work from the stance of what we expect reality to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man whose desire is with reality is always satisfied with what is. Since his desire is in tune with reality, he is not anxious or worry. This, in turn, allows him to become more composed, relaxed, and ultimately more productive while working toward his goal with a peace of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I am explaining here is also captured by Epictetus as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Do not seek to have events happen as you want them to, but instead want them to happen as they do happen, and your life will go well.
-Epictetus&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Our Duty To Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone—like me—is applying for graduate school I might, right away, desires to be accepted. But who am I to want or not want things from reality without ever creating the right causes for it to happen? In reality, whether or not anyone would or would not be accepted has many different factors—many beyond one’s control. So just by applying or having a great supporting resume doesn’t mean I have the right to demand or hope from reality my admission. So why hope? Why put my desire ahead of the reality? Why worry? And why not channel this energy, instead, at creating the right causes which are writing the best application?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can attain anything in life &lt;em&gt;with or without&lt;/em&gt; the need to desire for it. But since reality runs by the absolute law of cause and effect, it does not obey one’s desire no matter how large or small the desire. The only that matters is whether or not there is enough causes for the effect to occur. Thus, there is no need to desire because…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;One simply can&#39;t. &lt;strong&gt;There is no room for desire in reality.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;It is unscientific. How can I hope the tree to grow instantly if I just put the seed into the soil? Every effect must has it rightful causes.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Putting our demands of the reality before the reality is the root of all unhappiness of life. Why suffer?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One does not need to desire to achieve whatever he or she set out to accomplish. Our duty to life is not to desire, but to create the right causes to produce the right effect. And depending on how well one could live in accordance with this natural law and not according to what he or she demands of reality, the happier he or she becomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.7;&quot;&gt;All in all, the message here is simple: life is happier, better, and more satisfactory if one lives in accordance with reality and its law rather than living in accordance with what one wants from reality. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.7;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reality does not revolves around what one wants from it; it revolves around the absolute law of cause and effect.&lt;/strong&gt; Thus, life is never like what one wants it to be. The only way for anyone to feel the unsatisfactoriness of life is to be unmindful of the law of conditionality and desire life or reality to be the way one wants. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&#39;What&#39;s worse, the falling rain, or your resistance to getting wet?&#39;
- Jeff Foster&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;line-height: 1.7;&quot;&gt;So let’s keep our feet on the ground; and stay with reality and its law. Forget about all your fantasies about how reality should be. Instead, focus on, be satisfied, and accept what is. Begin living in the now! Keep on working with reality by making the right causes to achieve the right effect. And always remember that the way to live happily, correctly, and more efficiently, is not to put our desires in front of our reality, but the other way around.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/01/07/no-room-for-desire-in-life/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/01/07/no-room-for-desire-in-life/</guid>
        
        <category>understanding-of-true-happiness</category>
        
        <category>true-happiness-essential</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cause of Unhappiness Part Two: Comparing Yourself to Others</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Human’s innate ability to compare ourselves to others is perhaps the root of all sins in this world. Knowing that I am better create a sense of pride or even arrogant, while knowing that I am less create a sense of envy and jealousy toward the other. There can be no ends to our comparison unless we stop to put any value into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The fuels behind our comparisons are our likes and dislikes.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say for example that we would like to be promoted. However, someone was promoted instead. We can’t help but feel disappointed or even a sense of hate or jealousy. Why? Because we believe a promotion has value and is desirable. But if we did not want to be promoted in the first place then we simply would not care who got promoted or didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to be someone who enjoyed being better than others. My identity was dependent upon others being less than who I am. Every conversation I start every word I speak leak a sense of pride and the desperate need to show off myself. When I met someone who is worse of than I am then I became overjoyed because I felt I was “better”. But when I met someone who was better suddenly I felt scared and inferior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My happiness was contextual. I thought my happiness was to look better than others, but what I couldn’t see is how tiresome it was for me as well as those around me to put up with my own inferiority complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness is not to be taken likely. If one does not take care of it and see it objectively. It is most likely that this kind of pursue of “happiness” will never stop. And for me or for anyone, they would forever carry around this “happiness” complex without noticing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mindfulness saves my life.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was lucky. I somehow found my way to the practice of mindfulness. Through the practice mindfulness, I began to reflect upon this inferiority complex I called “happiness”. And the more I reflect the more I see its negative effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it is rather obnoxious for others who have to put up with my own insecurity. No one likes someone who fill up the conversation only to boast about himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, it was tiresome to try to talk about how great you are in every context. I simply can’t be happy by myself. I needed someone to be better than at all time else I couldn’t be happy. When I felt like I am better than a person, I became happy. When that person or someone else become better than me then I became unsatisfied. My happiness was fleeting. It’s the kind of happiness which is dependent upon whether or not the context allow me to feel as if I am “better” than others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I eventually realise is that it was too hard for me to find happiness. My happiness to look better didn’t do anyone, including myself, any good except fulfilling the unfulfillable desire to look “better”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comparing myself to others did not bring me any joy, only pain and bitterness. Thus, I quit.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to Stop Comparing Yourself to Others&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Reflect. As long as you are biased toward yourself and your ways of attaining happiness, you will never find True Happiness. You will say, &quot;This is my happiness. Why would I change?&quot; Thus, it is necessary to have the desire to improve one&#39;s happiness by reflecting often. Question yourself. Why I am still unhappy even though I am trying to be happy? And if possible, learn to be mindful of your actions to see whether they are driven by your unwholesome desire or the desire to prove yourself. Know thyself and change yourself before it&#39;s too late!&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Knowing that there is no ends to comparing yourself to others. You will never be satisfied because your satisfaction is relative to how others are.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Better could mean worse and less is sometimes more. It all depends on which standard or perspective are you putting yourself against. No one is better or worse. Everyone has different background and up-bring and naturally each is incomparably different from one another.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Seeing the negative effects it has on oneself and everyone around you.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Compare yourself today with yourself yesterday&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Learn the art of mindfulness! &lt;a href=&quot;http://true-happiness.github.io/tags/practice-of-true-happiness/&quot;&gt;Click here to learn!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;p&gt;
Knowing this, I am reminded of story of Adam and Even in the Holy Bible where God warned Adam and Eve not eat the forbidden fruit of knowledge of good and evil. But they did and now it has began our original sin.

With our knowledge of what is good and bad, we are driven for that which is good and 
&lt;/p&gt;
 --&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;p&gt;There is no good or evil in reality. Atoms or molecules are neither good or bad. They are just the way they are. Only human made them &quot;good&quot; or &quot;bad&quot;. Thus, there is no static good or bad.&lt;/p&gt; --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/12/19/why-am-I-unhappy-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/12/19/why-am-I-unhappy-2/</guid>
        
        <category>dealing-with-unhappiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cause of Unhappiness Part One: Externalizing Our Happiness</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading capitalized&quot;&gt;Happiness is like a string which ties us to that which we believe is our happiness.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We, humans, have many things which our happiness is dependent upon whether it would be our wealth, health, or our love ones. Let’s say for example that if you tie your happiness with being rich and accepted, then as long as you are not rich and accepted you can not be happy. Similarly, if you rest your happiness on your promotion then the promotion becomes the happiness which you have put outside of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;The person who seeks all their applause from outside has their happiness in another&#39;s keeping .&quot; - Dale Carnegie&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, the society &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; encourages us to put our happiness outside of ourselves. The media is telling us that for one to be happy one needs to have a new iPhone, a big house, a good job, and a beautiful spouse, a degree from Harvard and on and on. Imagine ourselves being tied to millions of these strings which we come to know as “happiness”. What we soon realise is that “happiness” starts to become a spider webs in which we are the preys. Each “happiness” is pulling us left and right to the point that it becomes impossible to obtain any happiness or freedom in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading capitalized&quot;&gt;So What Do We Do?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do we keep our happiness with us? Here are some interesting concepts to contemplate and chew on which will help you find True Happiness in this chaotic world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;1. Don&#39;t Let Anything Defines Your Self-Worth.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The worst thing you can do for yourself is to let money defines your self-worth. And the worst thing you can do to others is to define others&#39; self-worth through money.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing can define your self-worth unless you let it. However, one way we, humans, externalize our happiness is to let something else defines our self-worth. This is very common in our materialistic society where often times we let material–like cars, money, cloth, or house–tells us our self-worth. If we let material defines our self-worth then material becomes our happiness. The more material or wealth we have the happier we becomes and inversely the less material or wealth we have the more unhappy we become. So by letting money defines ourselves our happiness becomes dependent to money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The happiest man on earth does not rest his “happiness” on anything. And for that reason, he cannot not be happy. He does not need to be “rich” to be happy. He does not need to be “smart” to be happy. He does not need other’s compliment or affection to be happy. He is already happiness as is. There is no happiness which he has externalized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, material or outer wealth has nothing to do with ourselves self-worth from the very start. When we were young materialism does not affect our world much. We wear whatever we want. We be whoever we want to be without feeling superior or inferior to anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whatever we come to value we also judge.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we let money defines our self-worth, we, in the same way, judge others through money. When how much money one has can define a person, there is naturally someone who is worse, or the same as the others. When such valuation of our humanity is as such. This valuation becomes the root of discrimination, prejudice, jealousy, pride and arrogant. Hence, one should be very careful about what one values and how far one takes it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading capitalized&quot;&gt;2. Good Or Bad Is A Matter Of Human&#39;s Perspective&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Good or bad, rich or poor, beautiful or ugly, these dualities are man-made. In God&#39;s eyes there is no such thing as good or bad. For Him, everything is just is.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether or not we have externalized our happiness, the value we perceive about ourselves–whether we believe we are rich or poor, beautiful or ugly, successful or unsuccessful, young or old, worthy or worthless–is only a matter of how and what we compare ourselves to. If you compare yourself to someone who are less fortunate than you might be “rich.” But if you compare yourself to a billionaire then we are, in a way, “poor”. So we are both “rich” and “poor” and at the same time we are neither. Positivity or negativity is a matter of perspective. In the realm of the ultimate reality, there is no one who is better or worse. We are just who we are–incomparably different from one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;3. Question Your Happiness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;A happy life must always be simple no matter how complicate our lives have become.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people rarely question their own happiness. But in order to maintain a happy life, it is necessary to regularly check up on what we called “happiness.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a practice, I suggest you to regularly review your life. I personally have a habit of writing a journal every night before going to bed to see what is bothering my mind. List them all out, question this list of what you called “happiness” then sort only ones that matter most to you while eliminating others which are not. You will easily find many things which you desire yet they are unnecessary towards life and are, in some ways, even weighting you down from achieving what really matters. Is it all that important to be “successful” in eyes of the others? Is being rich the answer to life? Is it worth it to trade your inner happiness for an outer one? Is my family comes first before my work? Slowly find out what matters to you most. Cut out any unnecessary wants. Eventually your life will feel lighter as you let go of those extraneous ties of “happiness.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing where your happiness truly belongs is a skill one which can be improved by learning to quickly identify where you have misplaced your happiness. This is what mindfulness is for. (Click &lt;a href=&quot;http://true-happiness.github.io/tags/true-happiness-essential/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about the practice of True Happiness.) And once you can see that these ties of “happiness” have been causing you more pain than happiness then perhaps it is time to let go. As a rule of thumb, the less ties of “happiness” we have the easier for us to find happiness in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;What To Take Away&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happiness is a delicate science. It is intriguing how sometimes even the things in which we believe will bring us “happiness” can end up causing us more unhappiness than happiness. Who would have thought that the way to be happy is less about pursuing it than questioning it? Happiness should never be ahead of us. It should be with us even though we are pursuing something ahead of us. Happiness is like a fire. And it is advisable that one be very careful with what you believe to be “happiness”. Question it. Simplify it. Deconstruction it. And what you will find is that there is nothing you need more to make you happy since our heart is by nature already happy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/12/12/why-am-I-unhappy-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/12/12/why-am-I-unhappy-1/</guid>
        
        <category>dealing-with-unhappiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why True Happiness Matters</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;!-- &lt;h2 class=&#39;text-center&#39;&gt;Saving the World Through Mindfulness One Breath At a Time&lt;/h2&gt;
 --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would making everyone in the world richer give us world peace? If wealth can save the world, why are we nowhere near world peace despite the fact that our GDP has increased by the thousand folds compare to what it was hundreds years ago? Even if it rains in gold today, what we will have is not world peace. But more likely wars in which people would fight one another to be richer even though they might already be rich.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would giving humans more power give us world peace? Since the beginning of our civilization, humanity has poured unimaginable amount of resources into bettering our education system. But does giving humans more power and skills without teaching how to excercise that power lead us toward world peace? Theodore Roosevelt once stated:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;A man who has never gone to school may steal from a freight car; but if he has a university education, he may steal the whole railroad.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Power is a double-edged sword. One which must not be taken lightly. Imagine a simple scenario in which you are a swordmaster. And you are now deciding which of your pupils to teach. Would you give someone the ability to take life to someone who finds happiness in taking from others or would you give it to someone who finds happiness in giving to others? The obvious answer is the latter. Thus..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;capitalized&quot;&gt;Happiness can and must be developed.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness matters. It is what create our world, for good or for evil. It dictates people lives and decides how our world will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By developing our happiness, not only will humanity finds both Truth and True Happiness, but it will also along the way create the right condition for world peace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;capitalized&quot;&gt;World Peace is not possible without True Happiness.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More wealth will not stop people from their greed. And more power will not stop people from abusing it. World peace cannot be achieved by changing what is outside of us, it is achieved by developing how each and every one of us seeks and defines happiness inside of ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than sharing the way to True Happiness, this is also another the noble goal which this website aims to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;float-center text-center&quot;&gt;World Peace Begins Here In Our Journey Toward True Happiness.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/08/24/why_true_happiness/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/08/24/why_true_happiness/</guid>
        
        <category>true-happiness-essential</category>
        
        <category>why-true-happiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Attain Happiness?</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#39;What&#39;s worse, the falling rain, or your resistance to getting wet?&#39;&lt;br /&gt;- Jeff Foster&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quote above is what I believe best summarizes how happiness is a matter of what&#39;s going on inside of us more than a matter of what&#39;s going on outside. We can&#39;t be mad at reality. Reality is just is. But our attitude toward reality, that&#39;s up to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness is not about getting what we want. It is about knowing how to want what we get. And for that very reason, one must learn how to want which requires us to change ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actual process of changing oneself is not hard. What is hard is the fact that &lt;strong&gt;we do not, cannot, and do not want to alter ourselves.&lt;/strong&gt; This is why &lt;strong&gt;the problem here is not so much that we cannot change as much as we do not want to change ourselves.&lt;/strong&gt;  I never hear anyone defines happiness as  “how to want what we get.” It’s always the other way around. Worse we say, &quot;It’s what I want, why would I question my own want?”, &quot;It’s what I hate, why I would alter myself to not hate?” The only time we ever decide to change our want is when our wants have become unbearable. It is the only after the damage that our wants have caused that we are willing to change. This is the common attitude which makes it so difficult to change ourselves which, in turn, makes it so difficult for us to be happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you are ready to be happy, below are the steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Four Core Habits to True Happiness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know Thyself&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;I am not going to lie to you: Happiness requires work and expertise. You can&#39;t master what you do not know well. And you definitely can&#39;t know anything well if you do not even know it in the first place! Thus, to master ourselves, the first step toward True Happiness is to know ourselves. Knowing ourselves is by far the most important steps in changing ourselves. It will be where we work. It is our laboratory where we do our experiment in happiness. The goal is to learn the truth and nature of both ourselves and reality in order to achieve harmony between the two. (For more information, &lt;a href=&quot;/2016/03/22/why-meditate/&quot;&gt;Click Here&lt;/a&gt;)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- 	&lt;p&gt;I won&#39;t go into details about the how here. These are the links to some articles at True Happiness that will guide you in detail about the how.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
			
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;
			
		&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt; --&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be an Expert: Truly Understand the Nature of Happiness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Once you have your practice of knowing yourself or mindfulness rock solid, you are now ready to walk toward True Happiness. Being able to walk is different from knowing where to walk to. Thus, the next step is to learn as much as you can from those who have walked before us so that we will have a road map of where we are taking ourselves toward. Happiness is delicate science which could even take more than a life-time to learn. But it is definitely the most meaningful, fulfilling, and beautiful journey you will ever take.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong class=&quot;capitalized&quot;&gt;Learn to see life for what it is and not for what you want or don&#39;t want it to be.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Once you understand what you are doing and learn some basic about how to practice, it is time to applied it into your own life. And the result of understanding life is the ability to see it objectively.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find a Role Model and a Learning Communities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;There will be times when it is difficult for us to continue on our journey. There will be struggles. There will be confusions about how to go about one&#39;s inner path. Thus, what you need is others to go with you especially those who have already walked the path. Don&#39;t expect this to be a solo journey. It&#39;s nearly impossible alone. Thus, finding your supportive community of practitioners and people who have mastered this art of happiness is a must.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True Happiness is impossible if we are unwilling to change ourselves. And the only steps toward True Happiness is just to know ourselves. It is as simple as that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next article will we will look at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/08/24/why_true_happiness/&quot;&gt;why happiness matters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to the world and how developing our happiness is the key for making the world a better place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/07/23/how_of_happiness/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/07/23/how_of_happiness/</guid>
        
        <category>practice-of-true-happiness</category>
        
        <category>true-happiness-essential</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Causes and Conditions of Happiness</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;By looking at the &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/06/01/what_is_happiness/&quot;&gt;definition of happiness&lt;/a&gt; alone, one could come to the conclusion that there are two ways of approaching happiness in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To learn how to change reality to fits our want.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To learn how to change our wants to fit the reality.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mix and match between the two approach is also possible. Either way both are ways of achieving happiness by synchronizing our wants and reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why Our Common Approach of Happiness Makes Us Unhappy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first approach is the common approach that we, humans, use to find happiness which is to do our best to change reality to fits our want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;strong&gt;two major fallacies&lt;/strong&gt; in this approach to happiness:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Our want, if untrained, is ever-expanding in its demand of the reality.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we are rich we want to be richer. When we see someone who is happy, we too want to be like them. When we see our friends succeed sometimes we can’t help but feel a sense of jealousy or inferiority. There is no end to our want. Imagine if there is a million of things that we want but have not achieved, then we have a million things that are unsatisfactory in our lives. That does not sounds like a good, happy, and fulfilling life. When we infinitely want things from the reality then we infinitely must suffer from our unending chase of happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could we demand the dead to come back to life? The obvious answer is no. Could we expect everyone to like us without being disliked? The answer is very unlikely. Even though we all know these facts but still our mind will not easily accept it. When someone talked behind our back, we become agitated and wish that person to stop. When someone we love passed away, we wish that person would still be alive with us. An untrained mind does not play by the rules or law of the universe. It does not live with reality. It takes in, hold on and grab whatever that it likes and push away or destroy all that it does not like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. By trying to satisfy our want only by changing what is outside of us we overlook the other half of happiness which is inside of us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we only work to change what is the outside of ourselves. We left our wants static, unchanging and unquestioned across time and space. But the fact of life is that &lt;strong&gt;we can’t always get what we want.&lt;/strong&gt; Life does not always goes according to what we want. Often times than not, there are too many things in which we can not change the reality to be like how we want. These could be something as obvious as death, sickness, and old-age. It could be our inability to control others’ thought, speech, and action. It even could be something as trivial as a stomach-ache in which we can’t command it to stop being painful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reality is never satisfactory with our expanding minds wanting the impossible. With our untrained minds, we are stuck in the situation where we have unchanging want in an ever-changing reality, unrealistic want in a realistic reality, and an infinite want in a finite reality. And naturally, we end up being the ones who suffer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, the cause of our happiness depends on how much we can harmonize our wants with our reality. We all know how to change what is outside of us but not many people know how to change what is inside. The less you know about yourself and its nature, the less control you have over it. And inversely, the more unhappiness you will have in your life. I believe this is why Horace, a famous greek philosopher, said this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;“Rule your mind or it will rule you.”&lt;br /&gt;- Horace&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next article, “&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/07/23/how_of_happiness/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Attain Happiness?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;”, will introduce to you to the other missing half of achieving True Happiness. It will introduce you to the basics of changing and improving oneself and how it is imperative to our happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/06/29/cause_of_happiness/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/06/29/cause_of_happiness/</guid>
        
        <category>true-happiness-essential</category>
        
        <category>understanding-of-true-happiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is Happiness?</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Happiness, in its most typical definition, is to get what we want. We would be happy if we always get what we want. We would be happy if everything goes exactly like how we want life to be. Once we get all that we want, we become content and satisfied with life. This sense of contentment, fulfilment, and satisfaction is ultimately what happiness is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three basic components of happiness:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;One’s desire&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The reality or the world&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;And their interaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness is when what you want from reality is in harmony with what reality is; or to put it in an even simpler term, happiness is when life is exactly like how you want it to be. There is nothing that you want more or less. Life is just perfect as it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;It&#39;s impossible to know what happiness is unless you also know what unhappiness is.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unhappiness, on the other hand, is when the reality is not like what you want it to be. Anything which you want but couldn’t have, anything that you do not want yet it enters into your life, anything that you used to have but now it’s gone. These are the unhappinesses of life which we come to know as worry, frustration, disappointment, depression, confusion, and etc. As an example, disappointment is when the reality is not what you hope it would be. And worry is when you want the reality to be a certain way, yet you are afraid it might not be like what you hope. In essence, all of these array of negative emotions, or unhappinesses, stem from the disharmony between what we want from reality and what the reality is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, understanding happiness is the easy part. The hard part is how to attain one. Why are we &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; always happy despite our knowledge of happiness? If happiness is simply to match reality and our want then where did we go wrong in this simple process to produce happiness? Why does our pursuit of happiness still lead us toward discontent and sometimes even a sense of meaninglessness in life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer these questions, the next article, “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2015/06/29/cause_of_happiness/&quot;&gt;The Cause and Condition of Happiness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;”, will introduce you into the nature of happiness, so that we will understand how to attain one. Click on the button below!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/06/01/what_is_happiness/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/06/01/what_is_happiness/</guid>
        
        <category>true-happiness-essential</category>
        
        <category>understanding-of-true-happiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
