<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" 
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
    >
  <channel>
    <title>True Happiness</title>
    <description>This is a blog written by Supakorn Laohasongkram for all to learn more about the science and practice of how to become happier in life.</description>
    <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://true-happiness.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 14:28:17 +0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 14:28:17 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>When You Love, You Become Love</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;And in the end, the love you take is equal to the love you make.&quot; ― The Beatles&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything is and can be the object of our love. When we exercise our capacity to love on anything at all–ourselves, love ones, work, pets or even an insect–we become love itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site is about finding True Happiness. And love is definitely one of the ways in which one could come to understand and experience True Happiness. But unlike the convention kind of romantic love, the kind of love we are talking about is an act of compassion and selflessness, to look beyond ourselves for the well-being of others without expecting anything in return. It is entirely for the benefits of others. There is no exchange in this kind of love. It is not a give and take. We get nothing for it. It is a &lt;strong&gt;gift&lt;/strong&gt; in its truest sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Many believe it never worth to do anything if it does not pay. Just like this website, I do not gain anything. Th
it&#39;s a waste of time for me to write these articles on True Happiness. Their logic is that if it does not generate income then it is a waste of time. But this website is not intented to be an exchange for me to gain something. It&#39;s simply an expression of love. It is to love others even though there is no guarantee or nothing in return. It is an investment in a relationship that may or may not work at all. It is a total blind shot in the dark which I hope will help someone in their life become happier. 
 --&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Love is Happiness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love is probably one of the stronger emotion which dominates and dissipates all doubts, hates, politics, and the dramas of human’s life. So look no further to find True Happiness because &lt;strong&gt;True Happiness is in the very act of love.&lt;/strong&gt; You will be surprised how quickly can love turn your day around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mother Teresa once said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Let no one ever come to you without leaving better and happier. Be the living expression of God&#39;s kindness: kindness in your face, kindness in your eyes, kindness in your smile.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all have the capacity for love. So exercise it. And exercise it epecially on those who you dislike. Exercise it on yourself and everything that come into your life until it becomes your nature to love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I would like to leave you with these beautiful and memorable quotes below which I believe fully summarise my point about love and True Happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;“Seize the moments of happiness, love and be loved! That is the only reality in the world, all else is folly. It is the one thing we are interested in here.” 
― Leo Tolstoy&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;short&quot; /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;“For every minute you are angry you lose sixty seconds of happiness.” 
― Ralph Waldo Emerson&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;short&quot; /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;“The Paradoxical Commandments&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

People are illogical, unreasonable, and self-centered.
Love them anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

If you do good, people will accuse you of selfish ulterior motives.
Do good anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

If you are successful, you will win false friends and true enemies.
Succeed anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

The good you do today will be forgotten tomorrow.
Do good anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Honesty and frankness make you vulnerable.
Be honest and frank anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

The biggest men and women with the biggest ideas can be shot down by the smallest men and women with the smallest minds.
Think big anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

People favor underdogs but follow only top dogs.
Fight for a few underdogs anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

What you spend years building may be destroyed overnight.
Build anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

People really need help but may attack you if you do help them.
Help people anyway.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Give the world the best you have and you&#39;ll get kicked in the teeth.
Give the world the best you have anyway.” 
― Kent M. Keith, The Silent Revolution: Dynamic Leadership in the Student Council&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/04/01/becoming-love/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/04/01/becoming-love/</guid>
        
        <category>love</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Meditate?</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are 3 goals in meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		To see the true nature of ourselves and the world
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		To experience peace and happiness
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		To become skillful at handling our own desires
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meditation allows us to experience a state of stillness. When the mind is not looking for something it wants and is not concern about its dislike, our mind comes together to produce an experience of True Happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be careful though that the practice of mindfulness is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; about not thinking or ignoring or denying the reality of our undesirable thoughts and feelings. Mindfulness is simply to be mindful. All thoughts, feeling and everything that comes to our senses are &lt;em&gt;allowed.&lt;/em&gt; The practice of mindfulness is not a judgment on ourselves. It is not a self-management exercise in which we must assert control over ourselves. It is a practice of knowing and being mindful of life as it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more we come to know the nature of ourselves the more we will realize the three noble Truths of our lives which are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything-ourselves, our feelings, our attitude, our body, or the world-is impermanent.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Nothing lasted.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Reality has nothing to do with what we want. (&lt;a href=&quot;/2016/01/07/no-room-for-desire-in-life/&quot;&gt;Click to Learn More&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How could the heart be unhappy if it knows everything is impermanent? How could the heart be unhappy if it knows everything will not last forever? How could our heart be unhappy if it knows that reality is not about what we want but about the absolute law of cause and effect that determined reality? It can&#39;t be unhappy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the Truth that our hearts will come to know through meditation. It is not about knowing it intellectually. We can know that everything is impermanent in our thought but does our hearts truly accept and understand that Truth? When someone we love passes away, regardless of how many books we read about impermanent, it is only the heart that decides our happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this reason, &lt;strong&gt;we need to meditate in order to let our heart see the Truth for itself.&lt;/strong&gt; It&#39;s not an intellectual discovery to be found in books or in logic. It&#39;s a spiritual discovery which comes from and by the heart that see the Truth of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;short&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recommended readings about “Why we meditate?”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Why Meditation Matters to The World?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are curious about why meditation is important to this world, click &lt;a href=&quot;/principles_of_happiness/why_true_happiness/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;strong&gt;What I Have Received from Meditation as a Long-Time Practitioner?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click &lt;a href=&quot;/principles_of_happiness/why_true_happiness/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about what I have received from my 10 years experience with meditation.&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/03/22/why-meditate/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/03/22/why-meditate/</guid>
        
        <category>practice-of-true-happiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Experience With Meditation</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It is not wrong to be curious about meditation and where it would take us. So as a long-time practitioner of mindfulness, here is a short list of what I have received/gained in these last 10 years of meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Happiness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Make a man happy and he will be happy for a day. Teach a man how to be happy and he will be happy for a life time.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People today are finding life more difficult to be happy and easier to be discontent. The reason is because our happiness is both fleeting and is always in front of us. We often think, “I’ll be happy if…”, “I’ll be happy when…” But never is our happiness with us in this very moment. We have become so out of touch with our happiness that we barely know what happiness actually is. This is why we have become so busy running and jumping from one kind of happiness to the next hoping it would finally fulfil our lives. But the chase never ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meditation is a method which allow us to be in touch with our inner balance. It is not about chasing, but about coming home. Whenever our hearts are off-balanced by whatever life throws at us, we know because when if we’ve regularly been practice mindfulness we have become in touch with our inner balanced. And for that reason, we can quickly discern our imbalances within our hearts. That is awareness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I mean by “imbalance” is our unhappiness; namely anger, worry, jealousy, greed, frustration, despair, disappointment and etcs. (For more information about what unhappiness is, click &lt;a href=&quot;/principles_of_happiness/what_is_happiness/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we are unawared of the unhappiness in our lives, the unhappiness spreads in our mind like wildfire. When you are angry at someone and you do not forgive him or her, what you eventually find is yourself saying bad things about him or her in your head. You will start convincing yourself how he or she is a bad person and how you will never talk to them again. So by allowing of inner fire to go wild, we unknowingly fueled our fire of hatred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noticing these imbalances quickly and objectively is enough for the fire to stop. When you practice long enough, you will notice, in split second, even the slightest imbalance in our hearts. When we could quickly see what is causing our unhappiness, we couldn’t help but ask ourselves, “Why hold on to the hot iron?” This is precisely the reason why meditation or mindfulness is imperative to our happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mindfulness protects our happiness. It allows us to see the true cause of our unhappiness. It helps us to not be comsumed by our own feelings and instead see it for what it is. Through mindfullness, we become the observer of our unhappiness and not the unhappiness itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;blockquote&gt;Hatred can&#39;t be stop by hatred. It only stops by compassion. &lt;br&gt;-Buddha&lt;/blockquote&gt;
 --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t tell you how many times a day these imbalances pop up in my daily life. And every single day for the last 10 years, mindfulness has countlessly saved my happiness. This is why I started True Happiness. This is why I know for sure that it will save your happiness too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Self-Transformation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to think I am already “good”. Even when others would give me honest constructive criticisms or useful feedbacks, I would see them as attacks or attempts to delegitimize my identity of being “good”. I prefered to hold on to my image of “good” rather be good. And for that, I can’t grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This attitude of being too good for improvement is perhaps the worst attitude anyone could have toward self-growth. According to the Buddha, he considered these people to already be “dead.” For they no longer have anything more to offer because their attempt to hold on to their “goodness” has hinder them of bettering themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meditation has turn this attitude of mine 360 degrees. What meditation allows one to see is myself for who I really am. Before I was biased toward myself. I thought I was already “good” enough. But once I started seeing myself more and more, I start to see that I was not. I have found many contradictories within myself which I only applies to others but never to myself. I realised my prejudices, and double-standards which many times have causes me troubles. I have come to see my many flaws and shortcomings which I had always overlook and even sometimes blame others for. I have overcome many unwholesome desires which I thought was my “happiness” but turns out just to be an attempt to fill the unfillable void in my heart. The list goes on and on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mind is like a garden. If you do not tend it, only weed grows. It is impossible to improve what we do not know because you don’t even know what the thing to be improved is in the first place. This is precisely what meditation allows us to do: seeing ourselves. And if meditation could completely change who I am for the better then it will change yours too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Love&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not the romantic kind of “love” we know. But this is the love given through Truth. It is the love born out of self-understanding and selflessness. It is the love which comes as the fruits of meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one is perfect; and I am of no exception. Many times in my life I wanted to yell and insult others who have anger me. Many times in my life I feel jealous of others who are doing better than me. Many times in my life I wanted to hurt others who have hurt me. Many times in my life what wanted to lie and cheat. Without mindfulness, I would have done all those thing without a second-thought because I felt it was right for me to feel such a way. And it was right for me to retaliate. However, nothing good ever comes out of doing, speaking, and thinking when you are emotional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? Because each time I faced with such situations, mindfulness was there to help me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the situation where I could cheat, did not because I am aware of my unwholesome desire.
In the situation where I could take advantage of others for my own goods, I did not.
In the situation where I know I am better than others but choose never to enjoy that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mindfulness allows me to see that these thoughts comes and goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But every time I was mindful of these thoughts. I couldn’t help but feel compassion for myself for having these thoughts. Instead of letting it comsume my life and who I am, I simply feel compassion for myself. And for that reason, I did not do anything of those things which I know I would regret hundred times over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this is not love, then what is? This is the love which benefits all for all eternity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I let it be without personalising it or denying it. And soon enough it passes away. For me this is love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to do all these things which I did not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one is perfect. I must admit that sometimes I even have the worst thought in my mind. When I see my friend is doing something better than me. I want to destroy him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has protected myself from harming others. I have better self-control though mindfulness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has protect myself from myself. I have better self-control though mindfulness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has given my life purpose.I have found my purpose in life through meditation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Purpose in Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the best way of living life both for oneself and for the world?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every individual lives to seek happiness in one form or another. However, the pursue of one’s happiness does not necessarily mean that it is always beneficial for all. Often time than not, our pursue of happiness only benefit ourselves. And worse, in some cases, it comes at the cost of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness must be developed. If it is not developed, then it always&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone seeks happiness. However, the pursue of one’s happiness does not necessarily mean that it is always beneficial for all. Often time than not, our pursue of happiness only benefit ourselves. And worse, in some cases, it comes at the cost of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone seeks happiness. But why is it so hard to become happy in compare to being discontent with life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the question is this, &lt;strong&gt;“What is the best way of living life both for oneself and for the world?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meditation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness must be learned and developed or else our happiness will be given by others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer to most of us is simply happiness. But the pursue of one’s happiness does not necessarily mean that it is always beneficial for all. Often time than not, our pursue of happiness only benefit ourselves. And worse, in some cases, at the cost of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone seeks happiness. However, the pursue of one’s happiness does not necessarily mean that it is always beneficial for all. Often time than not, our pursue of happiness only benefit ourselves. And worse, in some cases, at the cost of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I truly understood what meditation is and what it is for, I realise that &lt;strong&gt;meditation or the practice of mindfulness is not only the answer for one’s life, but also for world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the best thing to do for oneself and the world. If you seek not just happiness but True Happiness then meditation or the practice of mindfulness is what lies between the two. If you are looking to solve world problem or working for world peace then do not look else where. Because as long as humans do not know how to find the peace inside there can never be peace outside. (For more infomation about why learning True Happiness will save the world, &lt;a href=&quot;/principles_of_happiness/why_true_happiness/&quot;&gt;Click Here.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this website is to introduce everyone to a way of living life that will both be beneficial for oneself and the world. All of which are based upon the goals of improving our ways of seeking happiness, fiding True Happiness, differentiating happiness from True Happiness, learning to be mindful of oneself, finding happiness not taking but in giving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will might take a while for anyone to realise what meditation actually is. But for me,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Truth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Knowing yourself is the beginning of all wisdom.&quot; - Aristotle
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What originally led me to meditation is not my desire to be happy, but rather my desire to know Truth. It is rather odd how the two coincide. But from my experience, they do and they must. There is no True Happiness without Truth. One would not be wrong to say that finding Truth is also finding True Happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my time in college, I studied Philosophy. My journey in Philosophy has led to me know Truth. I know that Truth is outside of language. I know that it is the unspeakable. I know that it transcends all dualities of life. But what I am saying to you right now is like describing to you how a dish would taste. I could tell you all about it but in the end it is you who have to taste it to know what it actually taste like. Similarly, Truth can be learned. But it must be experienced through meditation in order to know what it actually is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning the Truth of Life is enjoyable in and of itself. Think of it as learning how to ride a horse. When you don’t know how, it is difficult and stressful to try to steer it. But once you come to learn about the nature of the horse and how to ride it, it is much easier and much more enjoyable. Life is very much the same. The more I became aware of the Truth of life the easier and happier it becomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking from what I know, you either live life or the life will live you, one way or the other. And the only difference is whether or not we know life. Knowing life is precisely what meditation is for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr class=&quot;short&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the more you understand yourself the more you understand others, and thus it made it that much easier for me to understand and get along with other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What meditation has given me is unrequitable and invaluable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I have spoken to you about what I have gain/received through meditation, but just as a final note, &lt;strong&gt;meditation is not something anyone should expect to gain anything out of.&lt;/strong&gt; The expectation and desire of meditation will make it impossible to succeed in any attempt to meditate. Even though meditation leads you to True Happiness, but you can’t even expect or demand it to make you be happy. Meditation is just about being with ourselves and being mindful of ourselves. So just be careful and meditate for meditation’s sake. That’s how you will find True Happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beside from the my main list above, calmness, productivity, focus, are the byproduct of meditation. Meditation is the exercise for the mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I am not here to prove to you why you should meditate. Meditation does not need convincing as much as it needs be proven. Thus, give it a try and let meditation speaks its truth to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why do we meditate?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Now that we understand why we meditate, the next article we will discuss about &quot;How to Meditate?&quot; so that you will know exactly what to do and what not to do. How can you practice.
 --&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How does meditation leads one to True Happiness?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How could we be unhappy if we know everything is impermanent? How could we be unhappy if we know everything will not last forever? How could we be unhappy if we know reality is not about what we want but about the absolute law of cause and effect that determined it? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meditation allows us to experience a state of stillness. Our mind is not looking for something it wants more. It is not concern about what is troubled what it is does not like. When the mind comes to know this state more and more it comes to experience what true happiness is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But be careful that the practice of mindfulness is not about not thinking or ignoring or denying the reality of our undesirable thoughts. Mindfulness is simply to be mindful of everything. All thoughts, feelings and everything that come to our senses are &lt;em&gt;allowed.&lt;/em&gt; The practice of mindfulness is not a judgement on ourselves or the world. It is not a self-management in which you have to assert control over ourselves. It is simply to be mindful of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more we come to know ourselves for what it is the more we will realise the three noble truth which is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything is impermanent--ourselves, our feelings, our attitude, our body.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Nothing lasted.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Reality has nothing to do with what we want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True Happiness is not a path of control. It is a path of acceptance. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How could we be unhappy if we know everything is impermanent? How could we be unhappy if we know everything will not last forever? How could we be unhappy if reality is not about what we want but about the absolute law of cause and effect that determined reality? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can&#39;t. But this is not a know that we can convince our heart and mind to accept. Through our mindfulness, we will let our heart and mind to see these truth for itself. We can say that we know everything is impermanent. But does our heart truly understand that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a huge different between knowing intellectually andk nowing from the heart. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How is it related to mindfulness?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What do people who practice meditation regular gains? How would it improve my daily life?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Life Changing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meditation is the tool to make us happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meditation is mindfulness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meditation is a way to let us probe into our true nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meditation is our school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meditatin is where you learn about the truth of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of meditation is to make us happy. It is the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meditation is the path for you to learn the truth about life. Once your mind comes to understand its own true nature, the result is our ability to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is probably one of the most unanswered question in meditation. Most people will be satified with the answer that meditation helps you calm your mind or it will increase your productivity. But is that really the reason why? I believe the reasons why there aren’t many good explanation is because people do not know why.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/03/22/my-experience-with-meditation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/03/22/my-experience-with-meditation/</guid>
        
        <category>practice-of-true-happiness</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cause of Unhappiness Part Four: Mistake in Life</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;You can&#39;t change or erase what happened in the past, all you can change is your attitude toward it.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mistake in life is not to be taken lightly. For some, one mistake could define who they are and enslave our lives in an unending quest to redeem or fix the mistake that we have done in the past. So let’s first begin by understanding what mistake is and how it effects our happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Understanding the Nature of Life Mistake&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Mistake is like a ghost.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we do not reconcile or do not know how to reconcile with our mistake, the mistake becomes an open loop which endlessly haunts our lives. The more we wish to not think about our mistake, the more our minds irresistibly wander back to the mistake to relive it over and over again. Even though it might have happened years ago, or you might be at work or in the middle of a party, our mistake will not rest or give us a break. It will continue to enter into our conscious mind to remind us of its presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Worse, we even welcome it in our lives by letting the mistake take over us. This is similar to when you are sad and want to listen to a sad song just to make life sadder. We feel it is not enough for us to feel the pain of the mistake, so we begin rubbing the salt in the wound just so the pain can seep a little deeper.
 --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The mistake itself is not what makes us unhappy. It’s our attitude towards it that makes us unhappy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mistake is fueled by our biases toward it. The more we resist, avoid, hide, deny, blame others, bend, or twist the reality of our mistake the more powerful it becomes in our lives. It draws power from our hate toward it. It draws power from our inability accept or come to term with it. It draws power from our feeling of guilt, depression, anger, frustration, self-hating, and embarrassment. All of which originate from our desire that the past should or should not have been otherwise. It’s the void in our want from reality which could never be changed. The only way for a mistake to lose its power is for us to allow our mistake to be, without disliking it or denying its reality. This is how a mistake loses its power and slowly fade away from our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Mistake is by default inevitable.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody wants to make mistake. Yet, why do we make mistake? Nobody would make a mistake if they know ahead of time what would be the consequence of that action. &lt;em&gt;But the point here is we don’t.&lt;/em&gt; That is why we must make mistake. There is no avoiding it. So when we look back at our mistake in life especially ones that our minds often replay in our heads, it is important to understand that there was nothing we can do to change the past. It is something that must happen the way it did and not any other way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Changing Our Attitude with Our Mistakes in Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how does one deal with one’s mistake? Here are 4 definitive steps to overcoming your mistake in life:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Take Full Responsibility for Your Mistake and All Its Ramification&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		If we are unwilling to accept its consequences, then we are not ready to fully come to terms with our mistake. Have the courage to face your mistake. Be responsible for it. Don&#39;t run away from it. Mistake is by definition undesirable. But when we made a mistake, we must be strong and mature enough to take full responsibility for it whether or not it was intentionally or unintentionaly, whether it effects just you or many other people.
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Think About What Is Best at This Very Moment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		Is there a benefit in going over our mistake? If there is then please do. But if brooding over our mistake only rubs the salt in the wound, then perhaps there is no point in letting our mistake take over our lives. The best question to ask in this situation is, &quot;What can we control at this moment?&quot; Can we change the past? No. Can we change what is in the now? Yes. So why not focus on what we can change instead of what we can&#39;t? Why not ask important questions like, &quot;How can I do my best now so that I can avoid more mistake in the future?&quot; or &quot;What is the best thing to do right now?&quot; So without the burden of the past, &lt;strong&gt;move on by letting go of the past which you no longer have control and focus on what you can control in the present moment.&lt;/strong&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Learn to Forgive Ourselves&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		It&#39;s impossible to move on if we do not forgive ourselves from our mistake. The characteristic of mistake in life is that they inevitable. Thus, it must happen the way it did. Looking back, you would never have done it. But because you did not know. That&#39;s why you made that mistake. So don&#39;t take it personally. Anyone who was in your shoes would have made the same mistake. 
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Accepting Our Mistake as It Is. Do not Avoid, Hide, Deny, Blame Others, Bend, or Twist the Reality of Our Mistake.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
		If you can&#39;t openly tell others your mistake, then this is a good indicator that there is something you still cannot accept about it. Of course, I am &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; suggesting for us to go out and tell everybody of our mistake either. My point is simply to come to understand ourselves if we still have our biases toward our mistake. If we still do then it is a good time to reconcile ourselves with these mistakes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Learning to Be with Your Mistake&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to reconcile with any mistakes in life is to accept it. Accepting is different from justifying our wrong doing. Accepting our mistake is to understand that there is no way of going back to fix the past of what we have done. Accepting our mistake is to be courageous and mature enough to accept whatever outcome and ramification that come as the direct or indirect results of our mistake. Accepting is to see no value in brooding or regreting our mistake, but instead see the value in what is in front of us. It is to be in the now by taking in the mistake as is, not as what you hope or do not hope it would be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a basic practice, when the mind wanders back to your mistake in life. Do not fight it. Do not find excuses for yourself about why you were not wrong. Observe the feelings associated with our mistakes, but do not let it overwhelm or take control of our lives. Do not hope the mistake would happen otherwise. Simply, know it and be mindful of it. Take it as it is. And understand that it must happen the way it did. Remind yourself of what is the best thing to do right now by knowing what you can and what you can’t control at this very moment. And let go of our feelings by seeing how the bad feelings that comes with your mistake does not help you or anyone to be better. Eventually, your mistake will begin to lose its power as you slowly come to see it for what it is. &lt;strong&gt;Don’t let your mistake of the past clouds what is in front you today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/03/09/why-am-i-unhappy-4/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/03/09/why-am-i-unhappy-4/</guid>
        
        <category>why-am-i-unhappy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cause of Unhappiness Part Three: Fear of Being Meaningless</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
	One of the worst fear of our lives is that we become meaningless. Whether this would be meaningless to oneself, meaningless to others, or meaningless to the world. Meaninglessness comes in various forms. The feeling of being useless, most evident in today society where everything is about productivity, to a feeling of inadequency. At True Happiness, this is an important concept to understand as often times, we, humans, equate our self-worth with our meaning. So let&#39;s dig a little deeper on this subject of meaninglessness to see where we could find True Happiness in this.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 
&lt;p&gt;
	Meaning emernate from the function of difference. What I mean by that is meaning is only possible by comparing two things. The meaning of something is emernate from what it is not. How
&lt;/p&gt; --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://true-happiness.github.io/img/stick.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most reowned Theravada Buddhist Monk in Thailand, &quot;Ajahn Chah,&quot; once asked his disciples if a wooden stick--just like the one in the picture above--is long or short. Some answered, &quot;It is long.&quot; Some answered, &quot;It is short.&quot; But Ajahn Chah&#39;s answer was not what one would unexpected. His answer is that the stick is neither long nor short. It is only long if we want it to be short. And it is short only if you want it to be long. Thus, the wooden stick is neither short or long. It is what it is. Only our want make it so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, our life is the same as that wooden stick. &lt;strong&gt;We are as meaningless as how much meaningful we want to be.&lt;/strong&gt; A rich person who want to be richer always feels he or she is not meaningful enough. So in a sense, he is &quot;poor.&quot; A poor person who feels that he or she has all that he or she ever wants is in way &quot;rich.&quot; It all depends on your want. If you want to be richer then immediately you are &quot;poor.&quot; If you feel you already have more than you want then at that very moment you are &quot;rich.&quot;

&lt;blockquote&gt;We are as meaningless as how much meaningful we want to be.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moment you want to be more meaningful is the moment that you have become meaningless. Those who feels they are already meaningful has no need to search for more meaning in their life. They are already happy and satisfied with life. They have finished looking for more meaning to fill the void of their meaninglessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, to find true happiness is not to look for more meaning, but to stop looking for one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;What to take away&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
	We are as meaningless as how much meaningful we want to be. Thus, to find true happiness is not to look for meaning, but to stop looking for one.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- 
&lt;p&gt;Life, in essense, is incomparable to one another. Life is just is. You can compare all you want but at the end of the day how could you ever compare something so different to one another? So live and let live.&lt;/p&gt;

We are as meaningless as we want to be. 


&lt;p&gt;meaning = self-worth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have studied Philosophy espeically on the topic of epistemology or the study of how we know what we know then you will know that meaning emernate from a function of difference. What I mean by that is &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what I am going to tell you. First, it&#39;s ok to be meaningless.(decontructivist) Second, you are not meaningless.(constructivist)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are looking for a meaningful life, but to truly live is not to look for one.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If you want to be meaningful, then you need to have what it takes to be meaningless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;http://seattleinsight.org/Talks/BrowseTalks/DharmaTalk/tabid/90/TalkID/375/Default.aspx&quot;&gt;recommended talks&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;p&gt; 
	Let&#39;s face it. I believe we are all born with the fear of being meaningless. We are so fearful that we will not have any meaning that we live our lives trying to add meaning to ourselves. We buy things we do not need to help boost our ego. We want to get that degrees so that we look better than our friends. We want to get that job so that we feel better about ourselves. Why? because we feel we still do not have enough.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;It takes so little, so infinitely little, for someone to find himself on the other side of the border, where everything - love, convictions, faith, history - no longer has meaning. The whole mystery of human life resides on the fact that it is spent in the immediate proximity of, and even in direct contact with, that border, that it is separated from it not by kilometers but by barely a millimeter.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;- Milan Kundera, The Book of Laughter and Forgetting&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This fear of being meaningless has been with us since we were born and it is at the core of our existence.

	We can&#39;t even rest anymore since it is tied to a sense of meaninglessness. We can&#39;t even not have a salary. How much salary we make become how meaningful we are.

	But is being meaningful or useful in life
&lt;/p&gt;


So why do we not want to be meaningless? What&#39;s wrong with being meaningless? I believe that the answer to this question is the fact that we were born with nothing to begin with.

So why do we fear meaninglessness?
How does meaningless cause us unhappiness?


&lt;p&gt;
	But we are born with nothing, and we will die with nothing. So actually whatever a little we have right now is already a plus. It is a gift just to be alive. It is a gift to be born healthy. Thus, it is not correct to assume that we are meaningless.

	It&#39;s ok to be meaningless. We were all born from being zero. 

	There are probably millions of infant motality  We have nothing to begin with. Why are we crying over something which is even already even better than when we are born. Many infants today die even before they get a chance to live. Why are we crying over our the bad luck despite being so lucky to live up until now?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Meaning is, therefore, relative. Let&#39;s say you feel you are not rich enough. And you are unhappy about it. 

	Meaning is created by comparing one thing with another. It simply the difference between one thing and another. Meaning does not emernate from the thing itself. 
&lt;/p&gt;
 --&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/02/20/why-am-i-unhappy-3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/02/20/why-am-i-unhappy-3/</guid>
        
        <category>why-am-i-unhappy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cause of Unhappiness Part Five: When Life Is At a Loss</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are times when life&#39;s enormity will be too overwhelming for us. There will be times in our lives where we have no idea how go on with our lives. There will be times with doubt, fear, and uncertainty will cloud our mind so much that we just could not rest or fall as sleep. In this age of information where we are always bombarded by others who try to tell us what we should want in life, it is difficult to live a simple life. &quot;You have to get a degree in order to be happy.&quot; &quot;You need a new phone in order to look good in front of your friends.&quot; &quot;You need that big house in order to the so called &#39;successful people&#39;.&quot; &quot;You need to get married by this age or else it will be impossible afterward.&quot; On and on and on. Life is becoming harder to keep up with the things that we should want in life. 


The universality of what a good life is. 

 The best way to get your life back on track is to... &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what should one do when life is at a loss? Here are four simple steps getting some control back on your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;4 Steps to Get Your Life Back When It Is At a Loss.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Stop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Thich Nhat Han, a famous Zen Master, wrote in his book &quot;Present Moment Wonderful Moment&quot; as follows:

&lt;blockquote&gt;One evening I return to my hermitage from a walk in the hills, and I found that all the doors and windows of the hermitage had been blown open. When I left the house, I hand&#39;t secured them, and a could wind blew through the house, opened the windows, and scattered the papers from the desk all over the room. Immediately I closed the dooers and the windows, lit a lamp, picked up the papers, and arranged them neatly on my desk. Then I started a fire in the fireplace, and soon the crackiling logs brought warmth back to the room.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Somtimes in a crowd we feel tired, cold, and lonely. We may wish to withdraw to be by ourselves and become warm again, as I did at the hermitage sitting by the fire, protected from the cold, damp wind. Our senses are our windows to the outside world, and sometimes the wind blows and disturbs everything withing us.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

 once depicted in a imagery of life as a small hut in a tonado. What do you do when the storm is here? You shut the windows and doors of your hut. This is exactly the same. We stop whatever 

The point of shutting is not to run away. It is not to hide. The point is to prepare and strength oneself. the point is to give oneself a place to start anew. If the storm is hitting your hut there is no way you will be able to manage anything in life.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;2. Ask yourself what do you really want in life.&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason why we are sometimes confused with life is because we have too many wants which some are even conflicting with one another.
&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;strong&gt;3. Simplify&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having too much wants makes our live become too much to manage. As a rule of thumb, a simple life always lead to happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/02/20/why-am-i-unhappy-5/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/02/20/why-am-i-unhappy-5/</guid>
        
        <category>why-am-i-unhappy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Philosophy of Meaning</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;!-- 
&lt;p&gt;
	One of the worst fear of our lives is that we become meaningless. Whether this would be meaningless to oneself, meaningless to others, or meaningless to the world. Meaningless comes in various forms. The feeling of being useless, which is most evident in today society where everything is about productivity, to a feeling of inadequency. At True Happiness, this is an important concept to understand as often times meaning, we, humans, equate our self-worth with our meaning. So let&#39;s dig a little deeper on this subject of meaninglessness to see where we could find True Happiness in this.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/img/stick.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most reowned Theravada Buddhist Monk in Thailand, &quot;Ajahn Chah,&quot; once asked his disciples if a wooden stick--just like the one in the picture above--is long or short. Some answered, &quot;It is long.&quot; Some answered, &quot;It is short.&quot; But Ajahn Chah&#39;s answer was not what one would unexpected. His answer is that the stick is neither long nor short. It is only long if we want it to be short. And it is short only if you want it to be long. The wooden stick is neither short or long. It is what it is. Only our want make it so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, our life is the same as that wooden stick. &lt;strong&gt;We are as meaningless as how much meaningful we want to be.&lt;/strong&gt; A rich person who want to be richer always feels he or she is not meaningful enough. So in a sense, he is &quot;poor.&quot; A poor person who feels that he or she have all that he or she ever wants is in way &quot;rich.&quot; It all depends on your want. If you want to be richer then immediately you are &quot;poor.&quot; If you feel you already have more than you want then at that very moment you are &quot;rich.&quot;

&lt;blockquote&gt;We are as meaningless as how much meaningful we want to be.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The moment you want to be more meaningful is the moment that you have become meaningless.&lt;/strong&gt; Because those who feels they are already meaningful has no need to search for more meaning in their life. They are already happy and satisfied with life. They have finished looking for more meaning to fill the void of their meaninglessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, to find true happiness is not to look for more meaning, but to stop looking for one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;What to take away&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
	We are as meaningless as how much meaningful we want to be. Thus, to find true happiness is not to look for meaning, but to stop looking for one.
&lt;/blockquote&gt; --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life, in essense, is incomparable to one another. Life is just is. You can compare all you want but at the end of the day how could you ever compare something so different to one another? So live and let live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are as meaningless as we want to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;meaning = self-worth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have studied Philosophy espeically on the topic of epistemology or the study of how we know what we know then you will know that meaning emernate from a function of difference. What I mean by that is &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what I am going to tell you. First, it&#39;s ok to be meaningless.(decontructivist) Second, you are not meaningless.(constructivist)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are looking for a meaningful life, but to truly live is not to look for one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to be meaningful, then you need to have what it takes to be meaningless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://seattleinsight.org/Talks/BrowseTalks/DharmaTalk/tabid/90/TalkID/375/Default.aspx&quot;&gt;recommended talks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; 
	Let&#39;s face it. I believe we are all born with the fear of being meaningless. We are so fearful that we will not have any meaning that we live our lives trying to add meaning to ourselves. We buy things we do not need to help boost our ego. We want to get that degrees so that we look better than our friends. We want to get that job so that we feel better about ourselves. Why? because we feel we still do not have enough.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;It takes so little, so infinitely little, for someone to find himself on the other side of the border, where everything - love, convictions, faith, history - no longer has meaning. The whole mystery of human life resides on the fact that it is spent in the immediate proximity of, and even in direct contact with, that border, that it is separated from it not by kilometers but by barely a millimeter.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;- Milan Kundera, The Book of Laughter and Forgetting&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
This fear of being meaningless has been with us since we were born and it is at the core of our existence.

	We can&#39;t even rest anymore since it is tied to a sense of meaninglessness. We can&#39;t even not have a salary. How much salary we make become how meaningful we are.

	But is being meaningful or useful in life
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why do we not want to be meaningless? What’s wrong with being meaningless? I believe that the answer to this question is the fact that we were born with nothing to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why do we fear meaninglessness?
How does meaningless cause us unhappiness?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	But we are born with nothing, and we will die with nothing. So actually whatever a little we have right now is already a plus. It is a gift just to be alive. It is a gift to be born healthy. Thus, it is not correct to assume that we are meaningless.

	It&#39;s ok to be meaningless. We were all born from being zero. 

	There are probably millions of infant motality  We have nothing to begin with. Why are we crying over something which is even already even better than when we are born. Many infants today die even before they get a chance to live. Why are we crying over our the bad luck despite being so lucky to live up until now?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	Meaning is, therefore, relative. Let&#39;s say you feel you are not rich enough. And you are unhappy about it. 

	Meaning is created by comparing one thing with another. It simply the difference between one thing and another. Meaning does not emernate from the thing itself. 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/02/20/why-am-i-unhappy-3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/02/20/why-am-i-unhappy-3/</guid>
        
        <category></category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Science of Happiness</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If I know water would boil at a 100 degrees Celsius. Do I need to hope it would boil at 100 degree Celsius? Or even if I do not want the water to be boiled, could I desire the water not to be boiled even if I heat it up to 100 degrees Celsius?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, I can hope, dance, or pray—or do all three at once—for it to rain tomorrow. However, if the causes are not right, it will not rain. Or maybe I do not want it to rain tomorrow. But again, if the conditions are right for it rain, it will rain regardless of what I want or do not want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simple yet elegant wisdom that I am attempting to reiterate here is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Reality has nothing to do with what one wants. Instead, reality has everything to do with the law of cause and effect.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the causes are right for an effect to occur, it will occur regardless of what one wants or do not want. Scientifically speaking, there is no room for desires in reality. There is only cause and effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The common way, we, humans, achieve happiness in life is to put what we desire in front of the causes we must perform to achieve the result. We start a project by wanting it to be finished. We run a business by only wanting to gain and never to lose. We begin living by being afraid of dying. Even when we are deeply in love with someone, we can&#39;t help ourselves feeling a little insecure about how long the good time will last. Humans always put our desire in front of what the reality is. For this reason, we have become constantly fearful, worried, impatient, and frustrated by what we demand from reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One does not need desire in life to achieve whatever he or she wants. Because it doesn&#39;t matter how much you want something, what matters is whether or not there is enough causes for the the effect to occur. Our duty is to the law of cause and effect, not to what you want from reality. By creating the right causes, you can attain anything in life &lt;em&gt;with or without&lt;/em&gt; the need to desire for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only difference between these two wanting and not wanting is the difference between being the happiest man alive or being miserable. There are two ways of achieving anything in life. One is to put your desire in front of what the reality is. In this case, happiness is therefore fleeting by away where but now. He can never be happy until his goal and desire is fulfilled. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second way is to work toward your goal without the need to get ahead of ourselves. In other words, to work with and according to what the reality is, not work for what you want from reality. The man whose desire is with reality is always satisfied with what is. Since his desire is in tune with reality, he is not anxious or worry. This, in turn, allows him to become more composed, relaxed, and ultimately more productive while working toward his goal with a peace of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I am explaining here is best summarized by Epictetus as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Do not seek to have events happen as you want them to, but instead want them to happen as they do happen, and your life will go well.&lt;br /&gt;-Epictetus&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When someone—like me—is applying for graduate school I might, right away, desires to be accepted. But who am I to want or not want things from reality without ever creating the right causes for it to happen? In reality, whether or not anyone would or would not be accepted has many different factors—many beyond one’s control. So just by applying or having a great supporting resume doesn’t mean I have the right or the claim or demand from reality my admission. So why desire? Why worry? Why put my desire ahead of the reality? And why not channel this energy, instead, at creating the right causes, which are writing the best application?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, the message here is simple: life is happier, better, and more satisfactory if one lives in accordance with reality and its law rather than living in accordance with what one wants from reality. Reality does not revolves around what one wants from it; it revolves around the absolute law of cause and effect. Thus, life is never like what one wants it to be. The only way for anyone to feel the unsatisfactoriness of life is to be unmindful of the law of conditionality and desire life or reality to be the way one wants. So let’s keep our feet on the ground; and stay with reality and its law. Never forget that the way to live happily, correctly, and more efficiently, is not to put our desires in front of our action, but the other way around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;What to take away&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
	Life doesn&#39;t revolve around what we desire from reality because reality revolves around the absolute law of cause and effect. So forget about all your fantasies about how reality should be. Instead, focus on, be satisfied, and accept what is. Begin living in the now! And keep on working with reality by making the right causes to achieve the right effect. 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/01/07/no-room-for-desire-in-life/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/01/07/no-room-for-desire-in-life/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Six Greatest Gifts You Can Give Your Loved Ones</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;So if we love someone, we should train in being able to listen. By listening with calm and understanding, we can ease the suffering of another person.&amp;#8221; &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8211; Thich Nhat Hanh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s Christmastime and it&amp;#8217;s the season of giving &amp;#8230; what are you giving your loved ones this year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The holidays often mean giving a lot of gifts, sometimes expensive, but often we lose sight of what&amp;#8217;s most important.&lt;span id=&quot;more-2072&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What gifts do your loved ones really want, whether they&amp;#8217;re your children, your significant other, your parents, your friends, or other family members? Is it an expensive electronic item, or some other material or tangible item? Perhaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the gifts I list below are more important. Sure, they might not be as fun to open on Christmas morning (or whatever other holiday you might celebrate), but in the long run, they&amp;#8217;ll value these gifts more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Your Presence&lt;/strong&gt;. This means making it a priority to spend time with them &amp;#8212; if they are truly important, you can make the time. You might have to change things in your life to make the time, but it&amp;#8217;s worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond just making the time, though, you have to actually be present when you spend time with loved ones. That means learning to stay in the moment, rather than having your mind on other things, checking your iPhone or Blackberry every two minutes, or trying to take care of other tasks and chores while spending time with them. Instead, drop everything else and focus on being there with your loved ones &amp;#8212; really listen, really have fun, really be present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Your Love&lt;/strong&gt;. This is perhaps an obvious one on the list, but it&amp;#8217;s too important to gloss over. It&amp;#8217;s imperative that you tell your loved ones that &amp;#8230; well, that you love them. Regularly. But just as important is that you actually show them you love them, in your actions every day, throughout the day. Hugs, intimacy, smiles, doing kind things for them, considering their needs and feelings &amp;#8230; just little things that mean a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Your Compassion&lt;/strong&gt;. How is this different than giving the gift of your love? Well, it&amp;#8217;s possible to love someone and not show compassion. For example, we parents often discipline our children and love them at the same time &amp;#8230; but often compassion is even more important than discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compassion is finding empathy with your loved one &amp;#8230; trying to see things from their eyes, trying to understand what they&amp;#8217;re going through &amp;#8230; and then doing your best to be kind and to end their suffering and to make them happier. &lt;a href=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/2007/06/a-guide-to-cultivating-compassion-in-your-life-with-7-practices/&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. A Voice&lt;/strong&gt;. We can give so much just by paying attention to a loved one, and really listening, and showing that we&amp;#8217;re interested in what they have to say, and showing that what they say is important and respected. Too often our children or spouse might talk to us but are only met with a disinterested nod or other small acknowledgment, or we&amp;#8217;ll make light or fun of what they say, as if it&amp;#8217;s not important. But giving a person a voice, and showing that their words matter, will have a long-lasting different in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. A Healthy Lifestyle&lt;/strong&gt;. When you spend time with your loved one, try to do so while enjoying a healthy and fun activity, such as going on a hike, playing a sport, tossing around a Frisbee, going for a walk or jog, doing some yardwork, and so on. When you get together to eat, try to eat healthy foods. Make the habits of good health a part of your lifestyle, and encourage your loved ones to do the same &amp;#8212; it could save their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Your Belief in Them&lt;/strong&gt;. Simply believing in another person, and showing that in your words and in your deeds, can make a huge difference. Studies of people who grew up in dysfunctional homes but who grew up to be happy and successful show that the one thing they had in common was a significant adult who believed in them. Do this for your child, and for the adult loved ones in your life as well. Support their dreams and passions and hobbies. Participate with them. Be nothing but encouraging. Be their greatest cheerleader. Whether they actually accomplish these dreams or not, your belief is of unlimited importance to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Love and compassion are necessities, not luxuries. Without them, humanity cannot survive.&amp;#8221; &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8211; the Dalai Lama&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/12/24/six-greatest-gifts-you-can-give-your-loved-ones/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/12/24/six-greatest-gifts-you-can-give-your-loved-ones/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cause of Unhappiness Part Two: Comparing Yourself to Others</title>
        <dc:creator>Supakorn Laohasongkram</dc:creator>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
Human&#39;s innate ability to compare ourselves to others is perhap the root of all sins in this world. Knowing that I am better create a sense of pride or even arrogant, while knowing that I am less create a sense of envy and jealousy toward the other. There can be no ends to our comparison unless we stop to put any value into it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;p&gt;
Knowing this, I am reminded of story of Adam and Even in the Holy Bible where God warned Adam and Eve not eat the forbidden fruit of knowledge of good and evil. But they did and now it has began our original sin.

With our knowledge of what is good and bad, we are driven for that which is good and 
&lt;/p&gt;
 --&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The fuels behind our comparisons are our likes and dislikes.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Let&#39;s say for example that we would like to be promoted. However, someone was promoted instead of us. We can&#39;t help but feel disappointed or even an sense of hate or jealousy. Why? Because we believe a promotion has value and is desirable. But if we did not want to be promoted then we would not care who got promoted or didn&#39;t.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I used to be someone who enjoyed being better than others. My identity was dependent upon others being less than who I am. Every conservation I start every word I speak leak a sense of pride and the desperate need to show off myself. When I met someone who is worse of than I am then I became overjoy because I felt I am &quot;better&quot;. But when I met someone who is better than me I felt scared and inferior. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
My happiness was fleeting and contextual. I thought my happiness was to look better than others, but what I couldn&#39;t see is how tiresome it was for me as well as those around me to put up with my own inferiority complex.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happiness is not to be taken likely. If one does not take care of it and see it objectively. It is most likely that this kind of pursue of “happiness” will never stop. And for me or for anyone, they would forever carry around this inferiority complex without noticing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Mindfulness saves my life.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, I was lucky. I somehow found my way to the practice of mindfulness. Through the practice mindfulness, I began to reflect upon this inferiority complex I called “happiness”. And the more I reflect the more I see its negative effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it is rather obnoxious for others who have to put up with my own insecurity. No one likes someone who fill up the conversation only to boast about himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, it was tiresome to try to talk about how great you are in every context. I simply can’t be happy since my happiness is fleeting. I needed someone to be better than at all time else I wouldn’t be happy. When I feel like I am better than a person, I become happy. When that person or someone else become better than me then I become unsatisfied. It’s the kind of happiness which is dependent upon whether or not the context allow me to feel as if I am “better” than others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I eventually realise is that it was too hard for me to find happiness in such a way. My happiness to look better didn’t do anyone, including myself, any good except fulfilling the unfulfillable desire to look “better”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comparing myself to others did not bring me any joy, only pain and bitterness.&lt;/strong&gt; Thus, I quit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;p&gt;There is no good or evil in reality. Atoms or molecules are neither good or bad. They are just the way they are. Only human made them &quot;good&quot; or &quot;bad&quot;. Thus, there is no static good or bad.&lt;/p&gt; --&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How to Stop Comparing Yourself to Others&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Reflect. Reflect. Reflect. As long as you are biased toward yourself and your ways of attaining happiness, you will never find True Happiness. You will say, &quot;This is my happiness. Why would I change?&quot; Thus, it is necessary to reflect often. Question yourself. Why I am still unhappy? And if possible, learn to be mindfulness of your actions to see whether they are driven by this unwholesome desire or the desire to prove yourself. Know thyself and change yourself before it&#39;s too late!&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Knowing that that there is no ends to comparing yourself to others. You will never be satisfied. Because your satisfaction is relative to how others are.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Better could mean worse and less is sometimes more. It all depends on which standard or perspective are you putting yourself against&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Seeing the negative effect it has on oneself and everyone around you.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Compare yourself today with yourself yesterday&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Learn the art of mindfulness! &lt;a href=&quot;/tags/practice-of-true-happiness/&quot;&gt;Click here to learn now!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/12/19/why-am-I-unhappy-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/12/19/why-am-I-unhappy-2/</guid>
        
        <category>why-am-i-unhappy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
