<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>True Happiness</title>
    <description>This is a blog written by Supakorn Laohasongkram for others to learn more about how to become happier in life.</description>
    <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://true-happiness.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 21:16:20 +0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 21:16:20 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Science of Happiness</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If I know water would boil at a 100 degrees Celsius. Do I need to hope it would boil at 100 degree Celsius? Or even if I do not want the water to be boiled, could I desire the water not to be boiled even if I heat it up to 100 degrees Celsius?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, I can hope, dance, or pray—or do all three at once—for it to rain tomorrow. However, if the causes are not right, it will not rain. Or maybe I do not want it to rain tomorrow. But again, if the conditions are right for it rain, it will rain regardless of what I want or do not want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simple yet elegant wisdom that I am attempting to reiterate here is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Reality has nothing to do with what one wants. Instead, reality has everything to do with the law of cause and effect.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the causes are right for an effect to occur, it will occur regardless of what one wants or do not want. Scientifically speaking, there is no room for desires in reality. There is only cause and effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The common way, we, humans, achieve happiness in life is to put what we desire in front of the causes we must perform to achieve the result. We start a project by wanting it to be finished. We live by wishing that we would never die. Even when we are deeply in love with someone, we can&#39;t help ourselves feeling a little insecure about how long the good time will last. Humans always put what we want in front of what the reality is. For this reason, we have become constantly fearful, worried, impatient, and frustrated by what we demand from reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One does not need desire in life to achieve whatever he or she wants. Because it doesn&#39;t matter how much you want something, what matters is whether or there is enough causes for the the effect to occur. Thus, our duty is to the law of cause and effect, not to what you want from reality. By creating the right causes, you can attain anything in life &lt;em&gt;with or without&lt;/em&gt; the need to desire for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only difference between these two wanting and not wanting is the difference between being the happiest man alive or being miserable. There are two ways of achieving anything in life. One is to put your desire in front of what the reality is. In this case, happiness is therefore fleeting by away where but now. He can never be happy until his goal and desire is fulfilled. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second way is to work toward your goal without the need to get ahead of ourselves. In other words, to work with and according to what the reality is, not work for what you want from reality. The man whose desire is with reality is always satisfied with what is. Since his desire is in tune with reality, he is not anxious or worry. This, in turn, allows him to become more composed, relaxed, and ultimately more productive while working toward his goal with a peace of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I am explaining here is best summerised by Epictetus as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Do not seek to have events happen as you want them to, but instead want them to happen as they do happen, and your life will go well.&lt;br /&gt;-Epictetus&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When someone—like me—is applying for graduate school I might, right away, desires to be accepted. But who am I to want or not want things from reality without ever creating the right causes for it to happen? In reality, whether or not anyone would or would not be accepted has many different factors—many beyond one’s control. So just by applying or having a great supporting resume doesn’t mean I have the right or the claim or demand from reality my admission. So why desire? Why worry? Why put my desire ahead of the reality? And why not channel this energy, instead, at creating the right causes, which are writing the best application?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, the message here is simple: life is happier, better, and more satisfactory if one lives in accordance with reality and its law rather than living in accordance with what one wants from reality. Reality does not revolves around what one wants from it; it revolves around the absolute law of cause and effect. Thus, life is never like what one wants it to be. The only way for anyone to feel the unsatisfactoriness of life is to be unmindful of the law of conditionality and desire life or reality to be the way one wants. So let’s keep our feet on the ground; and stay with reality and its law. Never forget that the way to live happily, correctly, and more efficiently, is not to put our desires in front of our action, but the other way around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;What to take away&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
	Life doesn&#39;t revolve around what we desire from reality because reality revolves around the absolute law of cause and effect. So forgot about all your fantasies about how reality should be. Instead, focus on, be satisfied, and accept what is. And keep on working with reality by making the right causes to achieve the right effect. 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/01/07/no-room-for-desire-in-life/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2016/01/07/no-room-for-desire-in-life/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Six Greatest Gifts You Can Give Your Loved Ones</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;So if we love someone, we should train in being able to listen. By listening with calm and understanding, we can ease the suffering of another person.&amp;#8221; &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8211; Thich Nhat Hanh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s Christmastime and it&amp;#8217;s the season of giving &amp;#8230; what are you giving your loved ones this year?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The holidays often mean giving a lot of gifts, sometimes expensive, but often we lose sight of what&amp;#8217;s most important.&lt;span id=&quot;more-2072&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What gifts do your loved ones really want, whether they&amp;#8217;re your children, your significant other, your parents, your friends, or other family members? Is it an expensive electronic item, or some other material or tangible item? Perhaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the gifts I list below are more important. Sure, they might not be as fun to open on Christmas morning (or whatever other holiday you might celebrate), but in the long run, they&amp;#8217;ll value these gifts more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Your Presence&lt;/strong&gt;. This means making it a priority to spend time with them &amp;#8212; if they are truly important, you can make the time. You might have to change things in your life to make the time, but it&amp;#8217;s worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond just making the time, though, you have to actually be present when you spend time with loved ones. That means learning to stay in the moment, rather than having your mind on other things, checking your iPhone or Blackberry every two minutes, or trying to take care of other tasks and chores while spending time with them. Instead, drop everything else and focus on being there with your loved ones &amp;#8212; really listen, really have fun, really be present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Your Love&lt;/strong&gt;. This is perhaps an obvious one on the list, but it&amp;#8217;s too important to gloss over. It&amp;#8217;s imperative that you tell your loved ones that &amp;#8230; well, that you love them. Regularly. But just as important is that you actually show them you love them, in your actions every day, throughout the day. Hugs, intimacy, smiles, doing kind things for them, considering their needs and feelings &amp;#8230; just little things that mean a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Your Compassion&lt;/strong&gt;. How is this different than giving the gift of your love? Well, it&amp;#8217;s possible to love someone and not show compassion. For example, we parents often discipline our children and love them at the same time &amp;#8230; but often compassion is even more important than discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compassion is finding empathy with your loved one &amp;#8230; trying to see things from their eyes, trying to understand what they&amp;#8217;re going through &amp;#8230; and then doing your best to be kind and to end their suffering and to make them happier. &lt;a href=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/2007/06/a-guide-to-cultivating-compassion-in-your-life-with-7-practices/&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. A Voice&lt;/strong&gt;. We can give so much just by paying attention to a loved one, and really listening, and showing that we&amp;#8217;re interested in what they have to say, and showing that what they say is important and respected. Too often our children or spouse might talk to us but are only met with a disinterested nod or other small acknowledgment, or we&amp;#8217;ll make light or fun of what they say, as if it&amp;#8217;s not important. But giving a person a voice, and showing that their words matter, will have a long-lasting different in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. A Healthy Lifestyle&lt;/strong&gt;. When you spend time with your loved one, try to do so while enjoying a healthy and fun activity, such as going on a hike, playing a sport, tossing around a Frisbee, going for a walk or jog, doing some yardwork, and so on. When you get together to eat, try to eat healthy foods. Make the habits of good health a part of your lifestyle, and encourage your loved ones to do the same &amp;#8212; it could save their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Your Belief in Them&lt;/strong&gt;. Simply believing in another person, and showing that in your words and in your deeds, can make a huge difference. Studies of people who grew up in dysfunctional homes but who grew up to be happy and successful show that the one thing they had in common was a significant adult who believed in them. Do this for your child, and for the adult loved ones in your life as well. Support their dreams and passions and hobbies. Participate with them. Be nothing but encouraging. Be their greatest cheerleader. Whether they actually accomplish these dreams or not, your belief is of unlimited importance to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Love and compassion are necessities, not luxuries. Without them, humanity cannot survive.&amp;#8221; &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8211; the Dalai Lama&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/12/24/six-greatest-gifts-you-can-give-your-loved-ones/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/12/24/six-greatest-gifts-you-can-give-your-loved-ones/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cause of Unhappiness Part two: Comparing Yourself to Others</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Human&#39;s innate ability to compare ourselves to others is perhaps the root of all sins in life. Knowing that I am better create a sense of pride, while knowing that I am less create a sense of jealousy. There is no ends to our comparison unless we stop to put any value into it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I mean by &quot;no ends&quot; is this. Let&#39;s say that I want to be better than others. Once you meet someone who is worse of than you are then you are happy. But in reality, that is rarely the case because there is always someone better than you. Always. Thus, when there is no happiness to be found in such desire of trying to look better than other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to be that kind of person where I enjoy being better than others. Every conservation I start, every word I speak reak a sense of pride and the desperate need to show off myself. If one does not see oneself objectively. It is most likely that this habit will never change. And that person would forever carry around this inferiority complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since my happiness was to look better than others, I couldn&#39;t see how tiresome it is for me as well as those around me to put up with my own lack of confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the more I reflect upon this &quot;happines&quot; I gain from being seen as better than others, the more I see its negative effects. First of all, it is tiresome to try to talk about how great you are in every context. And second, it is rather obnoxious for others who have to put up with my own insecurity. No one likes someone how only boast about himself. And worse, who always are they are better than you are. I simply can&#39;t be happy since my happiness is fleeting. It&#39;s the kind of happiness which is dependent upon whether or not the context allow me to feel as if I am &quot;better&quot; than others or not. What I eventually realise is that it is too hard to find happiness in that way. My happiness to look better didn&#39;t do anyone including myself any good except fulfilling the unfulfillable desire to look &quot;better&quot;. Thus, I quit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;How to Stop Comparing Yourself to Others&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Compare yourself today with yourself yesterday&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Knowing that that there is no ends to comparing yourself to others. You will never be satisfied. Because you satisfaction is relative to how others are.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Better could mean worse and less doesn&#39;t always mean more. It all depends on which standard or perspective are you putting yourself against&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Seeing the negative effect it has on oneself and everyone around you.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Reflect. Reflect. Reflect. As long as you are biased toward yourself and your ways of attaining happiness, you will not find true happiness. Thus, it is necessary to reflect often. Question yourself. And if possible, learn to be mindfulness of your actions to see whether they are driven by this unwholesome desire or the desire to prove yourself something. Know thyself and change yourself before it&#39;s too late!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/12/19/Why-am-I-unhappy-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/12/19/Why-am-I-unhappy-2/</guid>
        
        <category>why-am-i-unhappy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cause of Unhappiness Part one: Misplacing your happiness</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Happiness is like a string which ties us to that which we believe is our happiness.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s say for example that if you tie your happiness with being rich and accepted, then as long as you are not rich or accepted you can not be happy. Similarly if you rest your happiness on your promotion then the promotion itself becomes the happiness which you have put outside of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We humans have many things which our happiness is dependent upon whether it would be our wealth, health, or love ones. So imagine yourself being ties to millions of these strings of &amp;ldquo;happiness&amp;rdquo; and what you soon realise is that &amp;ldquo;happiness&amp;rdquo; becomes a spider web which we are the preys. Each &quot;happiness&quot; is pulling us left and right to the point that it become impossible to attain any happiness or freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So be careful where you place your happiness because that which you believe to be &amp;ldquo;happiness&amp;rdquo; will be your master and you will be its slave. The happiest man on earth does not rest his &amp;ldquo;happiness&amp;rdquo; on anything. He is already happiness as is. He is even happy with the unhappy things in life because he could accept and move on. For for us how are new this journey, so begin small by simply trying to make our the wish list &lt;em&gt;small&lt;/em&gt; so that it will be easier for you to manage and attain happy. Simplify your life and cut those unnessarily ties of &amp;ldquo;happiness&amp;rdquo;. Is it all that important to be &amp;ldquo;succesful&amp;rdquo; in eyes of the others? Is being rich the answer to life? Is it worth to trade your inner happiness for an outer one? Is my family comes first before my work? Slowly find out what matters to you most. Cut out any unnecessary wants. Eventually your life will feel lighter as  you let go of those extraneous ties.&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Question Your Happiness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a practice, I suggest you to regularly review your life. I personally do it every night before going to bed to see what is bothering my mind. List them all out, question this list of what you called &amp;ldquo;happiness&amp;rdquo; then sort only ones that matters most to you. You will easily find many things which you desire; yet they are unnecessary towards life and are, in some ways, even weighting you down from achieving what really matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So invest some time to learn more about what you really want. Tell me what you find out in the comments below so that we can all help one another. We are learning to be happy so enjoy your road toward it. Have fun learning it. I promise you it&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;What to take away&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing where your happiness truly belongs is a skill one which can be improve by learning to quickly identify where you have misplaced your happiness, and letting go of unnecessary desire. The less ties of &quot;happiness&quot; you have the better you easier and happier your life will be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/12/12/Why-am-I-unhappy-misplacing-your-happiness/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/12/12/Why-am-I-unhappy-misplacing-your-happiness/</guid>
        
        <category>why-am-i-unhappy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Empty Handed Full Hearted</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We often load ourselves up when we travel, because we want to be prepared for various situations. This burden of being prepared leaves us with our arms full, unable to receive whatever is there when we arrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It leaves us tired from carrying, so that we are not happy when we meet someone new on our travels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if we traveled with empty hands, ready to embrace new experiences, receive new foods, touch new people?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We might feel less prepared when we leave, but the preparedness is an illusion. Stuff doesn&amp;#8217;t make us prepared. Having empty hands but a heart that is full of love leaves us prepared for anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn&amp;#8217;t just apply to taking a trip, but to living each day. Each day is a journey, and we load ourselves up with material possessions, with tasks and projects, with things to read and write, with meetings and calls and texts. Our hands are full, not ready for anything new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drop everything, be &lt;a href=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/embrace-chaos/&quot;&gt;open to everything&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter each day empty-handed, and full-hearted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/11/21/empty-handed-full-hearted/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/11/21/empty-handed-full-hearted/</guid>
        
        <category>why-am-i-unhappy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Simplify</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8216;In proportion as he simplifies his life, the laws of the universe will appear less complex, and solitude will not be solitude, nor poverty poverty, nor weakness weakness.&amp;#8217; &lt;strong&gt;~Henry David Thoreau&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tendency of life in our society is to become more complicated: Internet, television, shopping, work, family commitments, possessions, eating, debt &amp;#8230; these things pile on top of each other endlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a rather bad formula, as our days have a limited capacity, and so do we as humans. We can only do so much, only handle so many tasks and possessions and social commitments, and filling ourselves to those limits means we stress our breaking points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It takes a bit of conscious effort to simplify, but it&amp;#8217;s one of the greatest things I&amp;#8217;ve ever learned to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simplify everything. That might sound hard, but with practice it&amp;#8217;s actually fairly easy, and leads to a quiet, content, lovely life full of space, with only the things in it that matter to me: my family, my writing, with some reading and workouts thrown in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do you simplify? As simply as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Block off some disconnected time&lt;/strong&gt;. The Internet is amazing, but always being connected means you&amp;#8217;re always pulled in a thousand directions at once. It&amp;#8217;s hard to focus, hard to connect with others, hard to get out into nature and be active. So schedule some time every day for disconnection: maybe a block in the morning where you get your best work done, and a block in the afternoon when you get out and active, or connect with friends or family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start eliminating commitments&lt;/strong&gt;. List your commitments, and pick one to eliminate today. It&amp;#8217;s a simple matter of making a call or sending an email explaining that you can&amp;#8217;t do the commitment. Trust me, they&amp;#8217;ll find a way to live without you. You&amp;#8217;ll start to free up time for what&amp;#8217;s more important to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start purging possessions&lt;/strong&gt;. Every day, find 5 things to donate or give to friends. Or clear an entire shelf or countertop, leaving only the things you actually use, getting rid of the rest. Slowly your possessions will be simplified to just the essentials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ban shopping for 30 days&lt;/strong&gt;. You can do this. Don&amp;#8217;t buy anything except the essentials (food, toiletries, basic supplies). If you think you really need it, put it on a list to be evaluated after the 30 days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wash your bowl&lt;/strong&gt;. When you&amp;#8217;re done eating, mindfully wash your bowl. When you&amp;#8217;re done with anything, get in the habit of pausing before moving onto the next thing, and cleaning up after yourself. Put your food away. Put your clothes where they belong. Put your keys in one spot. Clean the sink before you leave it. This simple habit will keep you mindful while saving you lots of cleanup later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schedule time for what&amp;#8217;s important&lt;/strong&gt;. What&amp;#8217;s most important to you? Your spouse or kids? Creating? Reading novels? Cooking, gardening, crafts, carpentry? Make the time for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get outdoors once a day&lt;/strong&gt;. Too often we are stuck at a desk or on the couch. Get outside, take a walk, enjoy the fresh air and sunshine. Go for a hike or a run with a friend. Play some sports. Run around and play tag with your kids. These simple activities will change your life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eat some plants&lt;/strong&gt;. Learn some simple recipes that incorporate super healthy foods you might not be eating: kale, spinach, broccoli, quinoa, berries, flaxseeds, lentils, avocados, black beans, squash, raw almonds and walnuts, garlic, turmeric, cayenne, cinnamon. These simple plants will make you strong like oxen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drink tea&lt;/strong&gt;. Green tea brewed from relatively fresh whole tea leaves is calming, healthy, and wonderful. A daily tea ritual keeps you grounded and mindful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/yoyo/2015/08/24/simplify/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/yoyo/2015/08/24/simplify/</guid>
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
        
        <category>yoyo</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Secret Habit to Success</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In Og Mandino&amp;#8217;s self-help classic, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/055327757X?ie=UTF8&amp;#038;tag=zenhab-20&amp;#038;linkCode=as2&amp;#038;camp=1789&amp;#038;creative=9325&amp;#038;creativeASIN=055327757X&quot;&gt;The Greatest Salesman in the World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=zenhab-20&amp;#038;l=as2&amp;#038;o=1&amp;#038;a=055327757X&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&quot; /&gt;, one of his more powerful concepts is how to form good habits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will form good habits and become their slave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will read each scroll for thirty days in this prescribed manner, before I proceed to the next scroll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I will read the words in silence when I arise. Then, I will read the words in silence after I have partaken of my midday meal. Last, I will read the words again just before I retire at day&amp;#8217;s end, and most important, on this occasion I will read the words aloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the next day I will repeat this procedure, and I will continue in like manner for thirty days. Then, I will turn to the next scroll and repeat this procedure for another thirty days. I will continue in this manner until I have lived with each scroll for thirty days and my reading has become habit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So basically, the habit is to read from the 10 Scrolls for 30 days each, morning, noon and night &amp;#8212; but the challenging part is holding back so you only do one scroll per month. &lt;strong&gt;And the first month, you focus on the process of forming those good habits.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you draw from that powerful concept, and start by first teaching yourself how to form a habit, and then focus on one habit for each of the following months, you will be more successful with each habit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So here&amp;#8217;s the secret: for the first month&amp;#8217;s habit, you need to develop the discipline of reading a mantra morning, noon and night &amp;#8211; the First Habit.&lt;/strong&gt; It can be a mantra you write yourself, or one that I suggest below. If you can stick to that habit for a month, you can build on that success and start with a second habit &amp;#8212; staying with another small one is best. Each month, you can work on a new habit, focusing on only one per month. But the key is to have the patience to work on only that First Habit for the first month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of us have a bunch of habits we&amp;#8217;d like to instill in our daily routine &amp;#8212; from eating healthy, to exercise, reading, writing, waking early, organization, frugality and more &amp;#8212; and it&amp;#8217;s hard not to try to conquer them all at once. But if you can do this, and hold off on those habits until you&amp;#8217;ve accomplished this one, &lt;strong&gt;you&amp;#8217;ll have a much, much greater chance of success at all of them&lt;/strong&gt;. Having the patience to do this won&amp;#8217;t be easy, but remember: you have your entire life ahead of you. If you follow this program, and you&amp;#8217;re successful, you&amp;#8217;ll have eight more habits developed by the end of this year (starting with your next habit in May), and 12 more the next year, and so on. It&amp;#8217;s worth the wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do you implement this First Habit? Here&amp;#8217;s the plan:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commit Thyself.&lt;/strong&gt; Commit to doing this First Habit for the rest of this month (or if you&amp;#8217;re starting late, do it for 30 days).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morning Habit.&lt;/strong&gt; Every morning, when you wake up, silently read this mantra (borrowed in part from reader &lt;a href=&quot;http://gitmo2007.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Ann M.&lt;/a&gt;, and in part from Og Mandino): &amp;#8220;Today, I start a new life. Today, I create a new, positive habit. The only difference between those who have failed and those who have succeeded lies in the difference of their habits. Good habits are the key to all success. Thus, the first law I will obey is: I will form good habits and become their slave. Today, I take control of my actions and behaviors. With these, I create my life and destiny.&amp;#8221;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Midday Habit.&lt;/strong&gt; Every day after you eat lunch, silently read the above mantra.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evening Habit.&lt;/strong&gt; Every evening, just before you go to bed, read the above mantra out loud.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tracking Habit.&lt;/strong&gt; Create a chart or log, and each day give yourself a checkmark, gold star, or other such mark so that you can see that you&amp;#8217;ve done the habit every single day. Don&amp;#8217;t miss a day, no matter what &amp;#8212; if you can do it every day, without fail, you will have create a 3x-a-day habit that you can use to build upon for your next habit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Future Habits.&lt;/strong&gt; Make a list of what habits you&amp;#8217;d like to work on each month, once you&amp;#8217;ve successfully completed the First Habit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivation Hacks.&lt;/strong&gt; If possible, use as many of the Top 20 Motivation hacks to help you stick to your habit for the rest of the month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Celebration Time!&lt;/strong&gt; Celebrate your successes along the way, and celebrate when you&amp;#8217;re done!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resolve yourself to this First Habit, and you&amp;#8217;ll be inspired by your own success. From Og Mandino:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
And I make a solemn oath to myself that nothing will retard my new life&amp;#8217;s growth. I will lose not a day from these readings for that day cannot be retrieved nor can I substitute another for it. I must not , I will not, break this habit of daily reading from these scrolls and, in truth, the few moments spent each day on this new habit are but a small price to pay for the happiness and success that will be mine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So here&amp;#8217;s your challenge: Commit to doing this First Habit, morning noon and night, for a month.&lt;/strong&gt; That simple. Then you can move on to other habits, once this one is established.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/05/30/the-secret-habit-to-success-an-april-challenge/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/05/30/the-secret-habit-to-success-an-april-challenge/</guid>
        
        <category>self-improvement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Half Step That Will Change Your Life</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;d be surprised to know how many emails I get where people are stuck in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&amp;#8217;re broke, or unmotivated, or in a job they hate, or they can&amp;#8217;t find their passion, or they can&amp;#8217;t get motivated to get healthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they don&amp;#8217;t know where to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It hurts to read these emails. It brings back to life the pain I lived through not too many years ago, when I too was stuck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know the feeling of despair when you are unhappy with your life and don&amp;#8217;t know how to change. When you&amp;#8217;ve tried lots of changes, but couldn&amp;#8217;t find the discipline to make them stick. When you feel crappy about yourself because you know you should get off your butt and start improving your life, but you&amp;#8217;d rather put it off for another day.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;more-8744&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Problems go away when you ignore them, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also know that there is really only one way out of this mire of despair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s to take an action, no matter how tiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#8217;t need to fix everything in your life right now. You don&amp;#8217;t even need to fix one thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You just need to do one little, miniscule, almost nothing thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make a list. Go outside and take a walk. Get rid of some of your junk food. Clear off your kitchen table. Cancel something tomorrow so you can make time to create something, no matter how small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t do all of these. Do one. Or half of one, or one thousandth. It doesn&amp;#8217;t matter how small &amp;#8212; the smaller, the better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take that first step. Celebrate that first step. Love the step, not the destination. That step, even the motion of taking the first foot off the ground and moving it forward &amp;#8212; that&amp;#8217;s everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s the truth, and you&amp;#8217;ll not read it in many self-help books: put every microparticle of your existence into that half step, and be nothing but that half step, and love it with all you have &amp;#8230; and your life has changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this half step, everything is different. You haven&amp;#8217;t achieved any goals &amp;#8230; but you&amp;#8217;ve moved. You haven&amp;#8217;t created something amazing &amp;#8230; and yet, more than ever before, you have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ve created beauty and joy and movement where none existed before, where previously only constriction and paralysis and confusion lived. You have changed the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The First Habit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choose one little habit to add joy to your life. Just one, and tiny is miraculous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be writing or painting or making music for 2 minutes a day. It can be a ridiculously easy walk or jog or enjoying a bowl of fruit. It can be 2 minutes of meditation or reflecting in a journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy the hell out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create this one habit, and you have a success. This is a foundation, a first step, to build on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you can do a second, and a third, but you can&amp;#8217;t do those without a first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t change your entire life. Just change this one little thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;d be amazed how much that matters. I was.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/02/12/half/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/02/12/half/</guid>
        
        <category>self-improvement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The No. 1 Habit of Highly Creative People</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;In order to be open to creativity, one must have the capacity for contructive use of solitude. One must overcome the fear of being alone.&amp;#8221;&lt;strong&gt; ~&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rollo_May&quot;&gt;Rollo May&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creativity is a nebulous, murky topic that fascinates me endlessly &amp;#8212; how does it work? What habits to creative people do that makes them so successful at creativity?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve reflected on my own creative habits, but decided I&amp;#8217;d look at the habits that others consider important to their creativity. I picked a handful of creatives, almost at random &amp;#8212; there are so many that picking the best would be impossible, so I just picked some that I admire, who came to mind when I thought of the word &amp;#8220;creative&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was going to be a list of their creative habits &amp;#8230; but in reviewing their lists, and my own habits, I found one that stood out. And it stands out if you review the habits and quotes from great creative people in history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s the Most Important Habit when it comes to creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you read the No. 1 habit, please scroll down and read the No. 2 habit &amp;#8212; they might seem contradictory but in my experience, you can&amp;#8217;t really hit your creative stride until you find a way to balance both habits.&lt;span id=&quot;more-4649&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The No. 1 Creativity Habit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a word: solitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creativity flourishes in solitude. With quiet, you can hear your thoughts, you can reach deep within yourself, you can focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are lots of ways to find this solitude. Let&amp;#8217;s listen to a few of the creative people I talked to or researched:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/feliciaday.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feliciaday.com/blog&quot;&gt;Felicia Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8211; wonderful actress perhaps best known for her awesome awesome work on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.drhorrible.com/&quot;&gt;Dr. Horrible&amp;#8217;s Sing-along Blog&lt;/a&gt;, Buffy the Vampire Slayer, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.watchtheguild.com/&quot;&gt;The Guild&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was thrilled when she replied to my email asking about her creative habits. One of the things she said: she makes &amp;#8220;sure to be creative first thing in the morning, before doing anything for the outside world, really sets the day up for me. It makes it feel that CREATING is my job, not answering emails.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/aliedwards.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aliedwards.com/&quot;&gt;Ali Edwards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8211; an author, designer, and leading authority on scrapbooking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was honored with a response from Ali as well. One of her top habits wasn&amp;#8217;t exactly solitude, but is related: &amp;#8220;&lt;strong&gt;Do nothing&lt;/strong&gt;. I have a habit of welcoming time away from my creative work. For me this is serious life-recharging time where my only responsibility is to just be Mom &amp;amp; Wife &amp;amp; Me. Doing nothing has a way of synthesizing what is really important in my life and in my work and inspires me beyond measure. When I come back to work I am better equipped to weed out the non-essential stuff and focus on the things I most want to express creatively.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/chasejarvis.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.chasejarvis.com/blog/&quot;&gt;Chase Jarvis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8211; an award-winning photographer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chase also kindly responded with several of his key creativity habits &amp;#8212; see more great ones at the bottom of this post. But here&amp;#8217;s one that I loved: &amp;#8220;Find Quiet.  Creativity sometimes washes over me during times of intense focus and craziness of work, but more often I get whacked by the creative stick when I&amp;#8217;ve got time in my schedule.  And since my schedule is a crazy one and almost always fills up if I&amp;#8217;m just &amp;#8220;living&amp;#8221;, I tend to carve out little retreats for myself.  I get some good thinking and re-charge time during vacations, or on airplanes, but the retreats are more focused on thinking about creative problems that I&amp;#8217;m wanting to solve.  That&amp;#8217;s why I intentionally carve time out.  I make room for creativity.  Intentionally.  The best example of what I mean by a retreat is a weekend at my family&amp;#8217;s cabin.  It&amp;#8217;s a 90 minute drive from my house on the coast.  There are few distractions.  Just a rocky beach and a cabin from the 60&amp;#8217;s with wood paneling and shag carpet.  I go for walks, hikes, naps. I read.  I did get an internet signal put in there to stay connected if I need it.  But the gist is QUIET.  Let there be space for creativity to fill your brain.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/maciej.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.idlewords.com/&quot;&gt;Maciej Cegłowski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8211; painter, programmer, excellent writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maciej is one of my favorite bloggers, and responded to my email with a classically short answer that to me, embodies a beautiful way to find solitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What habit helps his creativity?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maciej replied: &amp;#8220;Running up hills!&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leo Babauta&lt;/strong&gt;: OK, I wasn&amp;#8217;t going to talk about myself in this post, but I thought I should share some of my previous thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best art is created in solitude, for good reason: it&amp;#8217;s only when we are alone that we can reach into ourselves and find truth, beauty, soul. Some of the most famous philosophers took daily walks, and it was on these walks that they found their deepest thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My best writing, and in fact the best of anything I&amp;#8217;ve done, was created in solitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a few of the benefits I&amp;#8217;ve found from solitude:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time for thought&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in being alone, we get to know ourselves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we face our demons, and deal with them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;space to create&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;space to unwind, and find peace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time to reflect on what we&amp;#8217;ve done, and learn from it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;isolation from the influences of other helps us to find our own voice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;quiet helps us to appreciate the smaller things that get lost in the roar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/solitude/&quot;&gt;the lost art of solitude&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Greats on Solitude&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, many other creative people have believed in the habit of solitude. I&amp;#8217;ve collected a small but influential sample here. There are many more examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/mozart.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wolfgang_Amadeus_Mozart&quot;&gt;Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; prolific and influential composer of the Classical era. He composed over 600 works, many acknowledged as pinnacles of symphonic, concertante, chamber, piano, operatic, and choral music. He is among the most enduringly popular of classical composers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mozart: &amp;#8220;When I am, as it were, completely myself, entirely alone, and of good cheer&amp;#8211;say, traveling in a carriage or walking after a good meal or during the night when I cannot sleep&amp;#8211;it is on such occasions that my ideas flow best and most abundantly.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/einstein.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Albert_Einstein&quot;&gt;Albert Einstein&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211;  theoretical physicist, philosopher and author who is widely regarded as one of the most influential and best known scientists and intellectuals of all time. He is often regarded as the father of modern physics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Einstein: &amp;#8220;On the other hand, although I have a regular work schedule, I take time to go for long walks on the beach so that I can listen to what is going on inside my head. If my work isn&amp;#8217;t going well, I lie down in the middle of a workday and gaze at the ceiling while I listen and visualize what goes on in my imagination.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/kafka.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Franz_Kafka&quot;&gt;Franz Kafka&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; one of the most influential writers of the 20th century. Novelist and writer of short stories whose works came to be regarded as one of the major achievements of 20th century literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kafka: &amp;#8220;You need not leave your room. Remain sitting at your table and listen. You need not even listen, simply wait, just learn to become quiet, and still, and solitary. The world will freely offer itself to you to be unmasked. It has no choice; it will roll in ecstasy at your feet.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/tesla.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nikola_Tesla&quot;&gt;Nikola Tesla&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; inventor, one of the most important contributors to the birth of commercial electricity, best known for his many revolutionary developments in the field of electromagnetism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesla: &amp;#8220;The mind is sharper and keener in seclusion and uninterrupted solitude. Originality thrives in seclusion free of outside influences beating upon us to cripple the creative mind. Be alone—that is the secret of invention: be alone, that is when ideas are born.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/haydn.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joseph_Haydn&quot;&gt;Joseph Haydn&lt;/a&gt;: A life-long resident of Austria, Haydn spent much of his career as a court musician for the wealthy Hungarian aristocratic Esterházy family on their remote estate. Isolated from other composers and trends in music until the later part of his long life, he was, as he put it, &amp;#8220;forced to become original&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/goethe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Johann_Wolfgang_von_Goethe&quot;&gt;Johann Wolfgang von Goethe&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; German writer and polymath. Goethe&amp;#8217;s works span the fields of poetry, drama, literature, theology, philosophy, and science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His magnum opus, lauded as one of the peaks of world literature, is the two-part drama Faust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goethe: &amp;#8220;One can be instructed in society, one is inspired only in solitude.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/picasso.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pablo_Picasso&quot;&gt;Pablo Picasso&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; Spanish painter best known for co-founding the Cubist movement and for the wide variety of styles embodied in his work. His revolutionary artistic accomplishments brought him universal renown and immense fortunes throughout his life, making him one of the best-known figures in twentieth century art.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picasso: &amp;#8220;Without great solitude no serious work is possible.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/sandburg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_Sandburg&quot;&gt;Carl Sandburg&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211;  American writer and editor, best known for his poetry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He won three Pulitzer Prizes, two for his poetry and another for a biography of Abraham Lincoln. H. L. Mencken called Carl Sandburg &amp;#8220;indubitably an American in every pulse-beat.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sandburg: &amp;#8220;One of the greatest necessities in America is to discover creative solitude.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;padding: 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/fotos/mann.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thomas_Mann&quot;&gt;Thomas Mann&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; German novelist, short story writer, social critic, philanthropist, essayist, and 1929 Nobel Prize laureate, known for his series of highly symbolic and ironic epic novels and novellas, noted for their insight into the psychology of the artist and the intellectual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mann: &amp;#8220;Solitude gives birth to the original in us, to beauty unfamiliar and perilous — to poetry.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The No. 2 Creative Habit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it might seem contradictory, the No. 2 habit when it comes to nurturing creativity: participation. This can come in many forms, but it requires connecting with others, being inspired by others, reading others, collaborating with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how can you have both solitude and participation? They obviously have to come at different times. Finding the balance is key, of course, but it takes a conscious effort: this time is for solitude, and this time is for participation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are they both important? We need inspiration from without, but we need creation from within.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A couple of the people I interviewed had habits that relate to this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.chasejarvis.com/blog/&quot;&gt;Chase Jarvis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;#8220;&lt;strong&gt;Devour Popular Culture&lt;/strong&gt;. Consuming the works of others inspires me.  And it&amp;#8217;s not just museums and the &amp;#8220;establishment&amp;#8221;. I devour magazines, books, street art, performances, music, etc. All things that make me think critically (and whimsically) about the world. You get the picture. Inspiration can come from anywhere.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://awww.aliedwards.com/&quot;&gt;Ali Edwards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;#8220;&lt;strong&gt;Participate&lt;/strong&gt;. My creative spirit is interested in documenting the wonderful everyday details of our lives. To really get to the heart of the matter I need to be fully participating in my life, in the interactions with my kids and husband and family and friends. If I am just going through the motions or wishing away the present moment for &amp;#8220;the next thing&amp;#8221; I am missing the blessing of right now. My creativity requires the habit of active participation and daily attention to detail.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other Creative Habits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other habits than those top two, of course, that can nourish creativity. Some other good ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://feliciaday.com/blog&quot;&gt;Felicia Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;#8220;When I am most productive I am the most ruthless with my schedule. I will literally make a daily checklist with, &amp;#8220;one hour gym&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;30 minutes of internet research,&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;drink 3 glasses of water&amp;#8221; on it. For some reason being that disciplined creates a sense of control that I wouldn&amp;#8217;t have otherwise, as a self-employed person, and I get the most out of the scheduled hours that I have for writing.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aliedwards.com/&quot;&gt;Ali Edwards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: &amp;#8220;Take notes. I am a really good note-taker. It&amp;#8217;s essential for me to write down my ideas when they come to mind&amp;#8230;otherwise, poof, they disappear way too quickly as I move on to the next task (diaper changes, wiping noses, tending to the stuff of life). I use my phone, my computer, and a moleskine notebook to jot down thoughts and ideas and then I move them into Things every week or so.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.chasejarvis.com/blog/&quot;&gt;Chase Jarvis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; had a few more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Live a creative life everyday&lt;/strong&gt;.  I very much believe in doing creative stuff everyday. For one, I take photos and videos almost everyday.  Doesn&amp;#8217;t matter the camera.  I use my iPhone everyday. Just taking photos keeps me in a creative headspace.  Hell, I play with my food and draw and doodle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moderate Expectations&lt;/strong&gt;. Make it a habit not to judge yourself on your creative output.  Sometimes your creativity is on fire.  Great news.  Other times, it&amp;#8217;s not.  It&amp;#8217;s hard sometimes when you make art in a professional commercial capacity because you&amp;#8217;re paid to be &amp;#8216;ON&amp;#8217;, but you&amp;#8217;ll save yourself a lot of greif if you make it a habit to be cool to your psyche when your creative mojo isn&amp;#8217;t firing on all pistons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shake Your Tree&lt;/strong&gt;.  When I&amp;#8217;m starting to feel stale, I make a habit of getting into adventures.  Break molds. Drive home from work a different way. Stir up my routine.  I get active and &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.chasejarvis.com/blog/2009/05/shake-your-tree-today.html&quot;&gt;shake my tree&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find fun&lt;/strong&gt;.  Doing what you love inspires you to be more creative.  Make time and space for having fun.  All work and no play makes Jane a dull girl.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lastly, being creative means &lt;strong&gt;living a creative life&lt;/strong&gt;.  Expect yourself to have one.  Believe you are creative. Know that you are. Make that the most important habit of all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more on creativity, read my &lt;a href=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/the-little-but-really-useful-guide-to-creativity/&quot;&gt;Little But Useful Guide to Creativity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Creativity is essentially a lonely art. An even lonelier struggle. To some a blessing. To others a curse. It is in reality the ability to reach inside yourself and drag forth from your very soul an idea.&amp;#8221; &lt;strong&gt;~Lou Dorfsman &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/01/20/number-one-habit/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2015/01/20/number-one-habit/</guid>
        
        <category>self-improvement</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Short but Powerful Guide to Finding Your Passion</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;The supreme accomplishment is to blur the line between work and play.&amp;#8221; &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8211; Arnold Toynbee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following your passion can be a tough thing. But figuring out what that passion is can be even more elusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m lucky &amp;#8212; I&amp;#8217;ve found my passion, and I&amp;#8217;m living it. I can testify that it&amp;#8217;s the most wonderful thing, to be able to make a living doing what you love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, in this little guide, I&amp;#8217;d like to help you get started figuring out what you&amp;#8217;d love doing. This turns out to be one of the most common problems of many True Happiness readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be the thing that will get you motivated to get out of bed in the morning, to cry out, &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m alive! I&amp;#8217;m feeling this, baby!&amp;#8221;. And to scare your family members or anyone who happens to be in yelling distance as you do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide won&amp;#8217;t be comprehensive, and it won&amp;#8217;t find your passion for you. But it will help you in your journey to find it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. What are you good at?&lt;/strong&gt; Unless you&amp;#8217;re just starting out in life, you have some skills or talent, shown some kind of aptitude. Even if you are just starting out, you might have shown some talent when you were young, even as young as elementary school. Have you always been a good writer, speaker, drawer, organizer, builder, teacher, friend? Have you been good at ideas, connecting people, gardening, selling? Give this some thought. Take at least 30 minutes, going over this question &amp;#8212; often we forget about things we&amp;#8217;ve done well. Think back, as far as you can, to jobs, projects, hobbies. This could be your passion. Or you may have several things. Start a list of potential candidates.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span id=&quot;more-4993&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2. What excites you?&lt;/strong&gt; It may be something at work &amp;#8212; a little part of your job that gets you excited. It could be something you do outside of work &amp;#8212; a hobby, a side job, something you do as a volunteer or a parent or a spouse or a friend. It could be something you haven&amp;#8217;t done in awhile. Again, think about this for 30 minutes, or 15 at the least. If you don&amp;#8217;t, you&amp;#8217;re probably shortchanging yourself. Add any answers to your list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. What do you read about?&lt;/strong&gt; What have you spent hours reading about online? What magazines do you look forward to reading? What blogs do you follow? What section of the bookstore do you usually peruse? There may be many topics here &amp;#8212; add them to the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. What have you secretly dreamed of?&lt;/strong&gt; You might have some ridiculous dream job you&amp;#8217;ve always wanted to do &amp;#8212; to be a novelist, an artist, a designer, an architect, a doctor, an entrepreneur, a programmer. But some fear, some self-doubt, has held you back, has led you to dismiss this idea. Maybe there are several. Add them to the list &amp;#8212; no matter how unrealistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Learn, ask, take notes&lt;/strong&gt;. OK, you have a list. Pick one thing from the list that excites you most. This is your first candidate. Now read up on it, talk to people who&amp;#8217;ve been successful in the field (through their blogs, if they have them, or email). Make a list of notes of things you need to learn, need to improve on, skills you want to master, people to talk to. Study up on it, but don&amp;#8217;t make yourself wait too long before diving into the next step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Experiment, try&lt;/strong&gt;. Here&amp;#8217;s where the learning really takes place. If you haven&amp;#8217;t been already, start to do the thing you&amp;#8217;ve chosen. Maybe you already are, in which case you might be able to skip to the next step or choose a second candidate to try out. But if you haven&amp;#8217;t been, start now &amp;#8212; just do it. It can be in the privacy of your own home, but as quickly as possible, make it public however you can. This motivates you to improve, it gets you feedback, and your reputation will improve as you do. Pay attention to how you feel doing it &amp;#8212; is it something you look forward to, that gets you excited, that you love to share?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Narrow things down&lt;/strong&gt;. I recommend that you pick 3-5 things from your list, if it&amp;#8217;s longer than that, and do steps 5 &amp;amp; 6 with them. This could take month, or perhaps you&amp;#8217;ve already learned about and tried them all out. So now here&amp;#8217;s what you need to ask yourself: which gets you the most excited? Which of these can produce something that people will pay for or get excited about? Which can you see yourself doing for years (even if it&amp;#8217;s not a traditional career path)? Pick one, or two at the most, and focus on that. You&amp;#8217;re going to do the next three steps with it: banish your fears, find the time, and make it into a career if possible. If it doesn&amp;#8217;t work out, you can try the next thing on your list &amp;#8212; there&amp;#8217;s no shame in giving something a shot and failing, because it&amp;#8217;ll teach you valuable lessons that will help you to be successful in the next attempt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Banish your fears&lt;/strong&gt;. This is the biggest obstacle for most people &amp;#8211; self-doubt and fear of failure. You&amp;#8217;re going to face it and banish it. First, acknowledge it rather than ignoring or denying it. Second, write it down, to externalize it. Third, feel it, and be OK with having it. Fourth, ask yourself, &amp;#8220;What&amp;#8217;s the worst that can happen?&amp;#8221; Usually it&amp;#8217;s not catastrophic. Fifth, prepare yourself for doing it anyway, and then do it. Take small steps, as tiny as possible, and forget about what might happen &amp;#8212; focus on what actually is happening, right now. And then celebrate your success, no matter how small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Find the time&lt;/strong&gt;. Don&amp;#8217;t have the time to pursue this passion? Make the time, dammit! If this is a priority, you&amp;#8217;ll make the time &amp;#8212; rearrange your life until you have the time. This might mean waking earlier, or doing it after work or during lunch, or on weekends. It will probably mean canceling some commitments, simplifying your work routing or doing a lot of work in advance (like you&amp;#8217;re going on a vacation). Do what it takes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. How to make a living doing it&lt;/strong&gt;. This doesn&amp;#8217;t happen overnight. You need to do something, get good at it, be passionate about it. This could take months or years, but if you&amp;#8217;re having fun, that&amp;#8217;s what&amp;#8217;s most important. When you get to the point where someone would pay you for it, then you&amp;#8217;re golden &amp;#8212; there are many ways to make a living at that point, including doing freelance or consulting work, making information products such as ebooks, writing a blog and selling advertising. In fact, I recommend you do a blog if you&amp;#8217;re not already &amp;#8212; it&amp;#8217;ll help solidify your thinking, build a reputation, find people who are interested in what you do, demonstrate your knowledge and passion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I told you this wouldn&amp;#8217;t be easy. It&amp;#8217;ll require a lot of reflection and soul-searching, at first, then a lot of courage and learning and experimentation, and finally a lot of commitment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;#8217;s all worth it &amp;#8212; every second, every ounce of courage and effort. Because in the end, you&amp;#8217;ll have something that will transform your life in so many ways, will give you that reason to jump out of bed, will make you happy no matter how much you make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you follow this guide and find success, because I wish on you nothing less than finding your true passion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Choose a job you love, and you will never have to work a day in your life.&amp;#8221; &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8211; Confucius&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 19:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://true-happiness.github.io/2014/12/15/the-short-but-powerful-guide-to-finding-your-passion/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://true-happiness.github.io/2014/12/15/the-short-but-powerful-guide-to-finding-your-passion/</guid>
        
        <category>passion</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
